<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Lyceum Scholar Background</name>
		<update version="0.0.3">
		   <file name="lyceum-scholar.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/critcal-role-taldorei-campaign-setting-reborn/backgrounds/lyceum-scholar.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Lyceum Scholar" type="Background" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_BACKGROUND_LYCEUM_SCHOLAR">
		<description>
			<p>You most likely came up through money or hailed from a family with social prestige if you were able to afford tuition at the Alabaster Lyceum in Emon. But whatever your origin, your interests and pursuits brought you to the hallowed halls of Tal’Dorei’s highest place of learning, where you soaked in every lesson you could, hoping to better make your mark on the world. (Or at least you pretended to. Even at the Lyceum, every class has its slackers.) Eventually, though, the call to adventure pulled you from your studies, and you now face the challenge of keeping up with your education even as the tides of destiny threaten to sweep you away.</p>
			<p class="indent">You might have come to the Lyceum to better research and understand the history and lore of Exandria and the lands you call home. Perhaps you sought a future here as a professor—or you might hope to do so still. You could also have been drawn by the promise of prosperity in politics, learning the inner workings of government and alliances to better position yourself as a future writer of history. Or perhaps your knack for the arcane inspired you to attend the Lyceum to refine your spellcraft, following in the footsteps of some of the finest wizards to ever practice the arts of magic.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you choose this background, you could be either an active student seeking adventures for your own research, or a graduated alumnus. With a little modification, you could easily be a professor as well.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Your choice of two of the following: Arcana, History, or Persuasion</li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong> Two of your choice</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of fine clothes, a student uniform, a writing kit (small pouch with a quill, ink, folded parchment, and a penknife), and a belt pouch containing 10 gp </li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_ACADEMIC_REQUISITION" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>The Alabaster Lyceum accepts students of all major trades, the fine arts, and the magical arts. Pupils talented and privileged enough to be accepted travel to Emon from all over Tal’Dorei, seeking to study among some of the greatest minds and most talented arcanists in the land. If you came from a smaller city, a rural area, or Tal’Dorei’s relatively uncharted wilderness, studying at the Lyceum might have left you with a sense of culture shock, for good or for ill.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your bond is likely associated with your goals as a student or graduate. Your ideal probably involves your hopes in using the knowledge you’ve gained at the Lyceum, and your travels as an adventurer, to tailor the world to your liking.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">2 Arcana/History/Persuasion, 2 Languages of your choice</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Lyceum Scholar" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" number="2" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language, Lyceum Scholar" supports="Standard||Exotic" number="2" />


			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_ACADEMIC_REQUISITION" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
				<item id="1">I can’t believe I’m here! At the Alabaster Lyceum. Oh, gods, I’ve dreamed of this my whole life, and now I’m here!</item>
				<item id="2">I can’t believe I squandered all the opportunities I had at school. I was supposed to be learning good stuff, but I wasted it all daydreaming about fighting monsters.</item>
				<item id="3">Every night at school, I’d knock back a couple of meads and read with my pals! Just a bunch of nerds having fun, and I loved it.</item>
				<item id="4">Everyone at school was such a stick in the mud. Dressing the same, listening to the same bards…ugh, it’s sad. Just be yourself.</item>
				<item id="5">I’m happiest when I’ve got my little party with me. At school, it was like we were a squad of heroes, slaying projects like monsters.</item>
				<item id="6">I’d really rather you didn’t bother me. Can’t you see I’m studying here?</item>
				<item id="7">I don’t care. I just don’t care about it all. The dates I had to memorize, the formulae I learned…I just want to run away and live!</item>
				<item id="8">I’m just…tired. All the time. Oh, adventuring, sure, that’s fine, as long as I can find time to… nap…goodnight.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Ideal">
				<item id="1">Preparedness. I can’t go out into the world unless I know what I’m up against. Study first, act later. (Neutral)</item>
				<item id="2">Stardom. Having a team is good and all, but you can’t win a game of ball without the star charger, and you know that’s me. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="3">Individuality. The world keeps us down by trying to put us all into little boxes. I’m tired of living in my box, and I don’t care what you think about it. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="4">Purpose. I study because there are things I need to know. I’ll find my place in the world, and I’ll make the world better. (Good)</item>
				<item id="5">Code of Conduct. The student code is there to benefit all students, you know. It’s the same for laws! (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="6">Recreation. All this studying crap wasn’t worth anything if you weren’t partying when you were done. Meet me down at the tavern, okay? (Chaotic)</item>
			</select>
		   <select type="List" name="Bond">
				<item id="1">I came to the Lyceum with no one, but I fell in love with the city of Emon. I’ve finally found a place that feels like home!</item>
				<item id="2">Most of my professors drove me to frustration, but there’s one who was kind and wise. I know they’ll always have my back.</item>
				<item id="3">My family saved every copper piece to give me the opportunities I have now. I can’t let them down.</item>
				<item id="4">I came to the Lyceum with a childhood friend, but we’ve long been drifting apart.</item>
				<item id="5">Discovery is the only thing that matters to me. The topic doesn’t matter. Books keep me company on my loneliest days.</item>
				<item id="6">The Lyceum is my life. I’d give up anything— everything—to protect it from harm.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Flaw">
				<item id="1">The Lyceum taught me to never want to leave my room. The campus was so huge, and the crowds were so horrible.</item>
				<item id="2">You think you’re so great just because you’ve got muscles, and endurance, and…shut up! Read a book sometime!</item>
				<item id="3">Huh? What? Sorry, I was thinking about a test I need to retake when I get back to school….</item>
				<item id="4">I spent too much time studying. Now I don’t have any friends.</item>
				<item id="5">If you don’t match my aesthetic, I’m not interested in you. We can work together, but we won’t be friends. Got it?</item>
				<item id="6">I’m always striving for perfection. I got top of my class, sure, but only with a 98 average. And that’s. Not. Perfect.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Lyceum Scholar Background Feature-->

		<element name="Feature: Academic Requisition" type="Background Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_ACADEMIC_REQUISITION">
			<description>
				<p> You’ve cleared enough lessons—and have gained an ally or two among the staff—to enable access to certain private areas within the Lyceum and other allied universities. Whenever you’re on Lyceum grounds or at another major academic institution, you can requisition any set of tools found in the fifth edition rules. Each set of tools is magically marked to sound an alarm if they are removed from the university’s grounds.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you seek services such as spellcasting from an NPC at the Alabaster Lyceum or a related institution, you can use those services at a 25 percent discount, at the GM’s discretion.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>
				<p> You’ve cleared enough lessons—and have gained an ally or two among the staff—to enable access to certain private areas within the Lyceum and other allied universities. Whenever you’re on Lyceum grounds or at another major academic institution, you can requisition any set of tools found in the fifth edition rules. Each set of tools is magically marked to sound an alarm if they are removed from the university’s grounds.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you seek services such as spellcasting from an NPC at the Alabaster Lyceum or a related institution, you can use those services at a 25 percent discount, at the GM’s discretion.</p>
				</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>

</elements>
<!-- NEED TO REFORMAT-->
