<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Whitestone Rifle Corps Background</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="whitestone-rifle-corps.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/critcal-role-taldorei-campaign-setting-reborn/backgrounds/whitestone-rifle-corps.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    

    <element name="Whitestone Rifle Corps" type="Background" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_BACKGROUND_WHITESTONE_RIFLE_CORPS">
        <description>
            <p>You trained with the elite forces charged with the defense and protection of the isolated city-state of Whitestone, with much of that training focused on how to care for, protect, and safeguard the firearms that are the weapons of the Whitestone Rifle Corps. You are also entrusted with a solemn duty—to never let the secrets of your liege-lord’s deadly creations fall into the wrong hands.</p>
            <p class="indent">You might have come to Whitestone to prove yourself worthy of wielding the secretive and highly coveted firearms created there, and to seek instruction from warriors who have mastered those weapons. Or you might have grown up in Whitestone, perhaps even remembering the brutal days when Lord and Lady Briarwood ruled your homeland— a reign that began some thirty years ago and lasted for six harrowing years.</p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you or your parents might have come to Whitestone as refugees fleeing the destruction of the Chroma Conclave’s attack on Tal’Dorei. If so, your life in the city-state might have been a relatively peaceful one, dwelling among the engineers, artisans, and merchants seeking to capitalize upon Whitestone’s reputation as an up-and-coming center of trade, culture, and invention.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you choose this background, decide whether you were a member of the Rifle Corps, the Pale Guard, or the Whitestone Hunters. The “Whitestone” section in chapter 3 has more information about the Pale Guard, as well as the armaments and militia in the city-state. See below for more information on the Whitestone Hunters. </p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Your choice of two of the following: Athletics, Perception, or Survival</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Firearms</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of your choice</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> Your choice of a musket or a pistol, a set of common clothes, and a pouch containing 10 gp</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_LEGACY_OF_SECRECY" />
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>Those who join the Whitestone Rifle Corps become members of an elite and trusted band known as the city-state’s staunchest defenders. But this means working with your GM to determine why you’re not at home protecting Whitestone. Perhaps you took on a mission to guard someone on behalf of the de Rolo family, or you might have been separated from your company while on an assignment. Either way, you find yourself embroiled now in a series of new adventures as you try to make your way back home.</p>
            <p class="indent">You are—or were—a member of an elite and trusted band of Whitestone’s staunchest defenders. Work with your GM to determine your current relationship with the Rifle Corps. If your campaign starts in Whitestone, you might be an active member of that unit. Otherwise, you can use the Rifle Corps Relationships table for suggestions.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your bond is likely associated with your comradesin- arms or with Whitestone itself. Your ideal could be tied to justice or protection, but could also be a secretive, selfish perversion of those virtues.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">2 Athletics/Perception/Survival, Firearms, Language</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Whitestone Rifle Corps" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" number="2"/>
            

            <!-- firearms proficiency - needs both so the firearms options is checked -->
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_FIREARMS" /> <!-- not working??? -->
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_WOTC_DMG_OPTION_FIREARMS" /> 

            <select type="Language" name="Language, Whitestone Rifle Corps" supports="Standard||Exotic" />

            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_LEGACY_OF_SECRECY" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="Background Variant" name="Variant Whitestone Rifle Corps" supports="Background Variant, Whitestone Hunter" optional="true" />
            <select type="List" name="Rifle Corps Relationships">
                <item id="1">I retired honorably from the Rifle Corps— and now it’s time for me to pursue my own adventures.</item>
                <item id="2">I’m on an important mission to protect Whitestone or guard one of our allies.</item>
                <item id="3">Whitestone is in trouble, and I was sent away to seek help.</item>
                <item id="4">I don’t think firearms technology should be kept secret, so I escaped from the Rifle Corps with my weapon and am on the run.</item>
                <item id="5">I was on a mission with my company when I got separated from them. Now I need to find my way back home.</item>
                <item id="6">My weapon was stolen. I built a new one, but I can’t return home until I’ve tracked down the thief and recovered the original. (Whitestone Hunter variant only)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I want to make a good impression at all times. That means keeping my clothes and gear clean and in top condition.</item>
                <item id="2">I don’t like being the center of attention. I’d rather let someone else do the talking while I watch their back.</item>
                <item id="3">I feel safe only if I’m carrying my trusty rifle. And my dagger. And my concealed pistol. Oh, and of course my….</item>
                <item id="4">I don’t trust people with my secrets easily, so it feels like a big deal when someone else shares a secret with me.</item>
                <item id="5">I like coming up with solutions to problems using my esoteric knowledge of natural philosophy.</item>
                <item id="6">Everyone around me takes things so seriously. Sometimes I just want to let loose and have fun!</item>
                <item id="7">Knowing things that other people don’t know makes me feel special and important.</item>
                <item id="8">I’m most at home in woods and mountains, where everything feels at once familiar, always growing and changing.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">Responsibility. I have a duty to protect the people of Whitestone and to uphold the trust placed in me by the de Rolos. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="2">Militarization. Everyone should have access to the most powerful weapons available, so they can defend themselves effectively. (Evil)</item>
                <item id="3">Cooperation. Any problem can be solved as long as people are willing to work together. (Good)</item>
                <item id="4">Camaraderie. It’s important to have people you can trust to help out in a fight—and to uncork a bottle together afterward. (Any)</item>
                <item id="5">Context. There are no universal rights or wrongs. Every choice depends on the details of the situation. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="6">Secrecy. Information is valuable, but it can also be dangerous. I’ll keep my mouth shut and gather as much intel as I can. (Neutral)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I never knew what to do with myself until I joined the Rifle Corps. Now I have a purpose and comrades to give me direction.</item>
                <item id="2">One of my fellow Rifle Corps soldiers saved my life—and then I saved theirs. That kind of bond lasts forever.</item>
                <item id="3">Whitestone is the best city in all of Tal’Dorei. Nowhere else has been blessed by the Dawnfather and has a clock that tracks the movement of the stars!</item>
                <item id="4">My quick thinking saved a noble from assassination, and she showed me great kindness in return. I daren’t say it, but I’m more loyal to her than I am to the de Rolos.</item>
                <item id="5">My weapon is my life. I clean it, repair it, and care for it—and it serves me loyally in return.</item>
                <item id="6">The people of Whitestone cared for my family when we had nothing. I promise to repay their compassion with my service.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">Who cares about keeping this gun safe? “Don’t let it fall into the wrong hands!” Ha! It’s only a matter of time before someone slips up and these weapons are everywhere.</item>
                <item id="2">I think being part of the Rifle Corps is so cool. I love telling people about my position so I can impress them.</item>
                <item id="3">My weapon was stolen. I built a new one, but I can’t return home until I’ve tracked down the thief and recovered the original.</item>
                <item id="4">I’m tired of protecting spoiled people who don’t know how to protect themselves.</item>
                <item id="5">I shoot first and ask questions later.</item>
                <item id="6">The first and only time I killed someone, it changed my life. I still dream about it, and I’ll never be the carefree person I was before.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>


        <!-- Feature: Legacy of Secrecy -->
            <element name="Feature: Legacy of Secrecy" type="Background Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_LEGACY_OF_SECRECY">
                <description>
                    <p>You have been entrusted with the use and care of a weapon both powerful and terrifying. The rifle you wield might transform the face of warfare and life in Tal’Dorei. It is a weapon that haunts the mind of its creator, Percival de Rolo, manifesting as a pain that lives always behind his kind eyes.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You were granted a musket or a pistol (as described in the fifth edition core rules) by your commander in the Whitestone Rifle Corps. This weapon is a symbol of your status, and when you display it, other folk around you—particularly adventurers, mercenaries, guards, engineers, and weapons enthusiasts—treat you differently. You might be seen as a noble defender of the people, a selfish hoarder of power, or anything in between, at the GM’s discretion.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Legacy of Secrecy">
                    <description>You were granted a musket or a pistol (as described in the fifth edition core rules) by your commander in the Whitestone Rifle Corps. This weapon is a symbol of your status, and when you display it, other folk around you—particularly adventurers, mercenaries, guards, engineers, and weapons enthusiasts—treat you differently. You might be seen as a noble defender of the people, a selfish hoarder of power, or anything in between, at the GM’s discretion.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

            <element name="Variant: Whitestone Hunter" type="Background Variant" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_BACKGROUND_WHITESTONE_RIFLE_CORPS_VARIANT_WHITESTONE_HUNTER">
		        <supports>Background Variant, Whitestone Hunter</supports>
		        <description>
		        	<p>As elite as they are, the members of the Whitestone Rifle Corps do not represent the apex of firearms skill in Whitestone. A clandestine group of elite soldiers and survivalists is drawn secretly from the Rifle Corps ranks. Called the Whitestone Hunters, these soldiers are special operatives of the de Rolo family, and loyally serve as spies, bodyguards, and even assassins when the job requires it. Though few officially know of them, rumors of the Whitestone Hunters’ existence swirl constantly throughout the city-state, often in response to their activities after having been loaned out to protect Whitestone’s allies. You are one of these Whitestone Hunters, even if just a trainee (if you’re starting your campaign at low levels). You have the ear of the lord and lady of Whitestone, though you must exercise this privilege graciously lest you lose it.</p>
		        </description>
	        </element>

</elements>
