<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Deep Magic - Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Kobold%20Press/Deep%20Magic/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
<!-- ABHORRENCE -->
	<element name="Abhorrence" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ABHORRENCE">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You temporarily make a creature within range less appealing to others. The target makes a Wisdom saving throw against your spell. On a successful save, the spell is ineffective. On a failed save, the next time the creature makes a Charisma check before the spell ends, roll a d6 and subtract the result from the roll. The spell then ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Charisma</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
 
<!-- ABHORRENT APPARITION --> 
	<element name="Abhorrent Apparition" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ABHORRENT_APPARITION ">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You imbue a terrifying visage onto a gourd and toss it ahead of you to a spot of your choosing within range. Each creature within 15 feet of that spot takes 6d8 psychic damage and becomes frightened of you for 1 minute; a successful Wisdom saving throw halves the damage and negates the fright. A creature frightened in this way repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">psychic</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gourd with a face carved on it</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ABSORBING FIELD --> 
	<element name="Absorbing Field" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ABSORBING_FIELD">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cloak yourself in a protective field that absorbs incoming magic, rejuvenating your spell slots. When you are the target of a spell (including spells that affect multiple targets, but not area spells such as fireball), make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a successful check, the spell has no effect on you and is absorbed by the field. You regain a spell slot of the same level as the spell that was cast against you. If you have no expended spell slots of that level, you don’t regain a spell slot, but this spell remains in effect.</p>
			<p class="indent">Even if the spell manages to bypass the field, you gain advantage on your saving throw.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell slots,saving throw</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ACCELERATE --> 
	<element name="Accelerate" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ACCELERATE">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose up to three willing creatures within range, which can include you. For the duration of the spell, each target’s walking speed is doubled. Each target can also use a bonus action on each of its turns to take the Dash action, and it has advantage on Dexterity saving throws. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can affect one additional creature for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a toy top</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ACID GATE --> 	
	<element name="Acid Gate" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ACID_GATE">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a portal of swirling, acidic green vapor in an unoccupied space you can see. This portal connects with a target destination within 100 miles that you are personally familiar with and have seen with your own eyes, such as your wizard’s tower or an inn you have stayed at. You and up to three creatures of your choice can enter the portal and pass through it, arriving at the target destination (or within 10 feet of it, if it is currently occupied). If the target destination doesn’t exist or is inaccessible, the spell automatically fails and the gate doesn’t form. </p>
			<p class="indent">Any creature that tries to move through the gate, other than those selected by you when the spell was cast, takes 10d6 acid damage and is teleported 1d100 × 10 feet in a random, horizontal direction. If the creature makes a successful Intelligence saving throw, it can’t be teleported by this portal, but it still takes acid damage when it enters the acid-filled portal and every time it ends its turn in contact with it. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th level or higher, you can allow one additional creature to use the gate for each slot level above 7th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy,acid</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a vial of acid and a polished silver mirror worth 125 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ACID RAIN --> 
	<element name="Acid Rain" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ACID_RAIN">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You unleash a storm of swirling acid in a cylinder 20 feet wide and 30 feet high, centered on a point you can see. The area is heavily obscured by the driving acidfall. A creature that starts its turn in the area or that enters the area for the first time on its turn takes 6d6 acid damage, or half as much damage if it makes a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes half as much damage from the acid (as if it had made a successful saving throw) at the start of its first turn after leaving the affected area. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">150 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a drop of acid</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ALCHEMICAL FORM --> 
	<element name="Alchemical Form" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ALCHEMICAL_FORM">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You transform into an amoebic form composed of highly acidic and poisonous alchemical jelly. While in this form: </p>
			<p class="indent">-you are immune to acid and poison damage and to the poisoned and stunned conditions; </p>
			<p class="indent">-you have resistance to nonmagical fire, piercing, and slashing damage; </p>
			<p class="indent">-you can’t speak, cast spells, use items or weapons, or manipulate objects; </p>
			<p class="indent">-your gear melds into your body and reappears when the spell ends; </p>
			<p class="indent">-you don't need to breathe; </p>
			<p class="indent">-your speed is 20 feet; </p>
			<p class="indent">-your size doesn’t change, but you can move through and between obstructions as if you were two size categories smaller; and </p>
			<p class="indent">-you gain the following action: Melee Weapon Attack: spellcasting ability modifier + proficiency bonus to hit, range 5 ft., one target; Hit: 4d6 acid or poison damage (your choice), and the target must make a successful Constitution saving throw or be poisoned until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a vial of acid, poison, or alchemist's fire</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ALTER TIME FLOW --> 
	<element name="Alter Time Flow" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ALTER_TIME_FLOW">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You control the currents of time, affecting all creatures within 30 feet of yourself. You can choose to deliver either a haste or slow effect (as the spell) to each creature in the area. An unwilling creature makes a Constitution saving throw, avoiding the effect on a success. Each unwilling creature must make a new saving throw if it remains in the affected area at the end of its turn. Any affected creature returns to normal if it exits the area, but if a creature reenters the area while the spell is still active, it is subject to the effect of the spell (and receives another saving throw, if unwilling).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">time magic</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30-foot radius)</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an hourglass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ANTICIPATE ARCANA  -->
	<element name="Anticipate Arcana" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ANTICIPATE_ARCANA">
		<supports>Cleric,Paladin,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your foresight gives you an instant to ready your defenses against a magical attack. When you cast anticipate arcana, you have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects until the start of your next turn. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,time magic,reaction</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when an enemy you can see casts a spell</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ANTICIPATE ATTACK  -->	
	<element name="Anticipate Attack" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ANTICIPATE_ATTACK">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Paladin,Ranger,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>In a flash of foreknowledge, you spot an oncoming attack with enough time to avoid it. Upon casting this spell, you can move up to half your speed without provoking opportunity attacks. The oncoming attack still occurs but misses automatically if you are no longer within the attack’s range, are in a space that's impossible for the attack to hit, or can’t be targeted by that attack in your new position. If none of those circumstances apply but the situation has changed—you have moved into a position where you have cover, for example—then the attack is made after taking the new situation into account.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,reaction,time magic</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you are attacked but before the attack roll is made</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ANTICIPATE WEAKNESS --> 	
	<element name="Anticipate Weakness" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ANTICIPATE_WEAKNESS">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>With a quick glance into the future, you pinpoint where a gap is about to open in your foe’s defense, and then you strike. After casting anticipate weakness, you have advantage on attack rolls until the end of your turn. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,bonus action</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- AUSPICIOUS WARNING  -->
	<element name="Auspicious Warning" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_AUSPICIOUS_WARNING">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Just in time, you call out a fortunate warning to a creature within range. The target rolls a d4 and adds the number rolled to an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw that it has just made and uses the new result for determining success or failure.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,time magic,reaction</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when an ally makes an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BLOOD TO ACID --> 	
	<element name="Blood to Acid" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BLOOD_TO_ACID">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell, you designate a creature within range and convert its blood into virulent acid. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 10d12 acid damage and is stunned by the pain for 1d4 rounds. On a successful save, it takes half the damage and isn’t stunned. </p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures without blood, such as constructs and plants, are not affected by this spell. If blood to acid is cast on a creature composed mainly of blood, such as a blood elemental or a blood zombie (Creature Codex, p. 393), the creature is slain by the spell if its saving throw fails.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
 
<!-- BOILING OIL --> 
	<element name="Boiling Oil" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BOILING_OIL">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You conjure a shallow, 15-foot-radius pool of boiling oil centered on a point within range. The pool is difficult terrain, and any creature that enters the pool or starts its turn there must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 3d8 fire damage and falls prone. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and doesn’t fall prone. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a vial of oil</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BOTTLED ARCANA --> 
	<element name="Bottled Arcana" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BOTTLED_ARCANA">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By touching an empty, stoppered glass container such as a vial or flask, you magically enable it to hold a single spell. To be captured, the spell must be cast within 1 round of casting bottled arcana and it must be intentionally cast into the container. The container can hold one spell of 3rd level or lower. The spell can be held in the container for as much as 24 hours, after which the container reverts to a mundane vessel and any magic inside it dissipates harmlessly. </p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, any creature can unstop the container, thereby releasing the spell. If the spell has a range of self, the creature opening the container is affected; otherwise, the creature opening the container designates the target according to the captured spell’s description. If a creature opens the container unwittingly (not knowing that the container holds a spell), the spell targets the creature opening the container or is centered on its space instead (whichever is more appropriate). Dispel magic cast on the container targets bottled arcana, not the spell inside. If bottled arcana is dispelled, the container becomes mundane and the spell inside dissipates harmlessly. </p>
			<p class="indent">Until the spell in the container is released, its caster can’t regain the spell slot used to cast that spell. Once the spell is released, its caster regains the use of that slot normally. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the level of the spell the container can hold increases by one for every slot level above 5th. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">up to 24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an empty glass container</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BOTTOMLESS STOMACH --> 
	<element name="Bottomless Stomach" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BOTTOMLESS_STOMACH">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell, you gain the ability to consume dangerous substances and contain them in an extradimensional reservoir in your stomach. The spell allows you to swallow most liquids, such as acids, alcohol, poison, and even quicksilver, and hold them safely in your stomach. You are unaffected by swallowing the substance, but the spell doesn’t give you resistance or immunity to the substance in general; for example, you could safely drink a bucket of a black dragon’s acidic spittle, but you’d still be burned if you were caught in the dragon’s breath attack or if that bucket of acid were dumped over your head. </p>
			<p class="indent">The spell allows you to store up to 10 gallons of liquid at one time. The liquid doesn’t need to all be of the same type, and different types don’t mix while in your stomach. Any liquid in excess of 10 gallons has its normal effect when you try to swallow it. </p>
			<p class="indent">At any time before you stop concentrating on the spell, you can regurgitate up to 1 gallon of liquid stored in your stomach as a bonus action. The liquid is vomited into an adjacent 5-foot square. A target in that square must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or be affected by the liquid. The GM determines the exact effect based on the type of liquid regurgitated, using 1d6 damage of the appropriate type as the baseline. </p>
			<p class="indent">When you stop concentrating on the spell, its duration expires, or it’s dispelled, the extradimensional reservoir and the liquid it contains cease to exist. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BRIMSTONE INFUSION --> 
	<element name="Brimstone Infusion" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BRIMSTONE_INFUSION">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You infuse an ordinary flask of alchemist’s fire with magical brimstone. While so enchanted, the alchemist’s fire can be thrown 40 feet instead of 20, and it does 2d6 fire damage instead of 1d4. The Dexterity saving throw to extinguish the flames uses your spell save DC instead of DC 10. Infused alchemist’s fire returns to its normal properties after 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a flask of alchemist's fire and 5 gp worth of brimstone</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- CAUSTIC TORRENT --> 	
	<element name="Caustic Torrent" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CAUSTIC_TORRENT">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A swirling jet of acid sprays from you in a direction you choose. The acid fills a line 60 feet long and 5 feet wide. Each creature in the line takes 14d6 acid damage, or half as much damage if it makes a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature reduced to 0 hit points by this spell is killed, and its body is liquefied. In addition, each creature other than you that’s in the line or within 5 feet of it is poisoned for 1 minute by toxic fumes. Creatures that don’t breathe or that are immune to acid damage aren’t poisoned. A poisoned creature can repeat the Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (60 ft line)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a chip of bone pitted by acid</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
	
<!-- CHRONAL LANCE --> 	
	<element name="Chronal Lance" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CHRONAL_LANCE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You inflict the ravages of aging on up to three creatures within range, temporarily discomfiting them and making them appear elderly for a time. Each target must make a successful Wisdom saving throw, or its walking speed is halved (round up to the nearest 5-foot increment) and it has disadvantage on Dexterity checks (but not saving throws). An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal,clockwork">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- DECELERATE -->
	<element name="Decelerate" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DECELERATE">
		<supports>Druid,Paladin,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You slow the flow of time around a creature within range that you can see. The creature must make a successful Wisdom saving throw, or its walking speed is halved (round up to the nearest 5-foot increment). The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. Until the spell ends, on a failed save the target’s speed is halved again at the start of each of your turns. For example, if a creature with a speed of 30 feet fails its initial saving throw, its speed drops to 15 feet. At the start of your next turn, the creature’s speed drops to 10 feet on a failed save, then to 5 feet on the  following round on another failed save. Decelerate can’t reduce a creature’s speed to less than 5 feet. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can affect an additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,time magic</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a toy top</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- DELAY POTION --> 	
	<element name="Delay Potion" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DELAY_POTION">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Upon casting this spell, you delay the next potion you consume from taking effect for up to 1 hour. You must consume the potion within 1 round of casting delay potion; otherwise the spell has no effect. At any point during delay potion’s duration, you can use a bonus action to cause the potion to go into effect. When the potion is activated, it works as if you had just drunk it. While the potion is delayed, it has no effect at all and you can consume and benefit from other potions normally. </p>
			<p class="indent">You can delay only one potion at a time. If you try to delay the effect of a second potion, the spell fails, the first potion has no effect, and the second potion has its normal effect when you drink it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
	
<!-- FLICKERING FATE --> 	
	<element name="Flickering Fate" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FLICKERING_FATE">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You or a creature that you touch can see a few seconds into the future. When the spell is cast, each other creature within 30 feet of the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. Those that fail must declare, in initiative order, what their next action will be. The target of the spell declares his or her action last, after hearing what all other creatures will do. Each creature that declared an action must follow its declaration as closely as possible when its turn comes. For the duration of the spell, the target has advantage on attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws, and creatures that declared their actions have disadvantage on attack rolls against the target.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,time magic</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
 
<!-- FORETELL DISTRACTION --> 	
	<element name="Foretell Distraction" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FORETELL_DISTRACTION">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Thanks to your foreknowledge, you know exactly when your foe will take his or her eyes off you. Casting this spell has the same effect as making a successful Dexterity (Stealth) check, provided cover or concealment is available within 10 feet of you. It doesn’t matter whether enemies can see you when you cast the spell; they glance away at just the right moment. You can move up to 10 feet as part of casting the spell, provided you’re able to move (not restrained or grappled or reduced to a speed of less than 10 feet for any other reason). This move doesn’t count as part of your normal movement. After the spell is cast, you must be in a position where you can remain hidden: a lightly obscured space, for example, or a space where you have total cover. Otherwise, enemies see you again immediately and you’re not hidden.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,bonus action</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- GLUEY GLOBULE  -->	
	<element name="Gluey Globule" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GLUEY_GLOBULE">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You make a ranged spell attack to hurl a large globule of sticky, magical glue at a creature within 120 feet. If the attack hits, the target creature is restrained. A restrained creature can break free by using an action to make a successful Strength saving throw. When the creature breaks free, it takes 2d6 slashing damage from the glue tearing its skin. If your ranged spell attack roll was a critical hit or exceeded the target’s AC by 5 or more, the Strength saving throw is made with disadvantage. The target can also be freed by an application of universal solvent or by taking 20 acid damage. The glue dissolves when the creature breaks free or at the end of 1 minute. </p>
			<p class="indent">Alternatively, gluey globule can also be used to glue an object to a solid surface or to another object. In this case, the spell works like a single application of sovereign glue and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute or 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a drop of glue</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LIFE HACK --> 
	<element name="Life Hack" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LIFE_HACK">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose up to five creatures that you can see within range. Each of the creatures gains access to a pool of temporary hit points that it can draw upon over the spell’s duration or until the pool is used up. The pool contains 120 temporary hit points. The number of temporary hit points each individual creature can draw is determined by dividing 120 by the number of creatures with access to the pool. Hit points are drawn as a bonus action by the creature gaining the temporary hit points. Any number can be drawn at once, up to the maximum allowed. </p>
			<p class="indent">A creature can’t draw temporary hit points from the pool while it has temporary hit points from any source, including a previous casting of this spell. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a ruby worth 500 gp, which is consumed during the casting</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MEPHITIC CROAK --> 	
	<element name="Mephitic Croak" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MEPHITIC_CROAK">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You release an intensely loud burp of acidic gas in a 15-foot cone. Creatures in the area take 2d6 acid damage plus 2d6 thunder damage, or half as much damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature whose Dexterity saving throw fails must also make a successful Constitution saving throw or be stunned and poisoned until the start of your next turn. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, both acid and thunder damage increase by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (15-ft cone)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dead toad and a dram of arsenic worth 10 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- QUICK TIME --> 	
	<element name="Quick Time" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_QUICK_TIME">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You make one living creature or plant within range move rapidly in time compared to you. The target becomes one year older. For example, you could cast this spell on a seedling, which causes the plant to sprout from the soil, or you could cast this spell on a newly hatched duckling, causing it to become a full-grown duck. If the target is a creature with an Intelligence of 3 or higher, it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw to resist the aging. It can choose to fail the saving throw. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you increase the target’s age by one additional year for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">any seed</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- QUICKEN --> 	
	<element name="Quicken" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_QUICKEN_">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch one willing creature. Once before the duration of the spell expires, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to an initiative roll or Dexterity saving throw it has just made. The spell then ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- QUICKSILVER MANTLE -->	
	<element name="Quicksilver Mantle" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_QUICKSILVER_MANTLE">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You transform an ordinary cloak into a highly reflective, silvery garment. This mantle increases your AC by 2 and grants advantage on saving throws against gaze attacks. In addition, whenever you are struck by a ray such as a ray of enfeeblement, scorching ray, or even disintegrate, roll 1d4. On a result of 4, the cloak deflects the ray, which instead strikes a randomly selected target within 10 feet of you. The cloak deflects only the first ray that strikes it each round; rays after the first affect you as normal.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a nonmagical cloak and a dram of quicksilver worth 10 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- RAVAGES OF TIME --> 
	<element name="Ravages of Time" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_RAVAGES_OF_TIME">
		<supports>Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You accelerate the aging of one creature within range, causing it to take on the state of a decrepit version of its type. The target suffers three levels of exhaustion that cannot be removed by normal means. A greater restoration spell partially reverses the effect of this spell, removing one level of exhaustion. Constructs and undead are unaffected by this spell, and creatures who live to great age without negative effects, such as dragons, are also unaffected.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a wilted flower</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- RAY OF ALCHEMICAL NEGATION -->	
	<element name="Ray of Alchemical Negation" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_RAY_OF_ALCHEMICAL_NEGATION">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You launch a ray of blazing, polychromatic energy from your fingertips. Make a ranged spell attack against an alchemical item or a trap that uses alchemy to achieve its ends, such as a trap that sprays acid, releases poisonous gas, or triggers an explosion of alchemist’s fire. A hit destroys the alchemical reagents, rendering them harmless. The attack is made against the most suitable object Armor Class. </p>
			<p class="indent">This spell can also be used against a creature within range that is wholly or partially composed of acidic, poisonous, or alchemical components, such as an alchemical golem or an ochre jelly. In that case, a hit deals 6d6 force damage, and the target must make a successful Constitution saving throw or it deals only half as much damage with its acidic, poisonous, or alchemical attacks for 1 minute. A creature whose damage is halved can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- SALT LASH  -->	
	<element name="Salt Lash" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SALT_LASH">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a long, thin blade of razor-sharp salt crystals. You can wield it as a longsword, using your spellcasting ability to modify your weapon attack rolls. The sword deals 2d8 slashing damage on a hit, and any creature struck by the blade must make a successful Constitution saving throw or be stunned by searing pain until the start of your next turn. Constructs and undead are immune to the blade’s secondary (stun) effect; plants and creatures composed mostly of water, such as water elementals, also take an additional 2d8 necrotic damage if they fail the saving throw. </p>
			<p class="indent">The spell lasts until you stop concentrating on it, the duration expires, or you let go of the blade for any reason.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pinch of salt worth 1 sp, which is consumed during the casting</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>
