<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Deep Magic - Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.9">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Kobold%20Press/Deep%20Magic/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
<!-- ABHORRENCE -->
	<element name="Abhorrence" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ABHORRENCE">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You temporarily make a creature within range less appealing to others. The target makes a Wisdom saving throw against your spell. On a successful save, the spell is ineffective. On a failed save, the next time the creature makes a Charisma check before the spell ends, roll a d6 and subtract the result from the roll. The spell then ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Charisma</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
 
<!-- ABHORRENT APPARITION --> 
	<element name="Abhorrent Apparition" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ABHORRENT_APPARITION ">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You imbue a terrifying visage onto a gourd and toss it ahead of you to a spot of your choosing within range. Each creature within 15 feet of that spot takes 6d8 psychic damage and becomes frightened of you for 1 minute; a successful Wisdom saving throw halves the damage and negates the fright. A creature frightened in this way repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">psychic</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gourd with a face carved on it</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ABSORBING FIELD --> 
	<element name="Absorbing Field" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ABSORBING_FIELD">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cloak yourself in a protective field that absorbs incoming magic, rejuvenating your spell slots. When you are the target of a spell (including spells that affect multiple targets, but not area spells such as fireball), make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a successful check, the spell has no effect on you and is absorbed by the field. You regain a spell slot of the same level as the spell that was cast against you. If you have no expended spell slots of that level, you don’t regain a spell slot, but this spell remains in effect.</p>
			<p class="indent">Even if the spell manages to bypass the field, you gain advantage on your saving throw.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spell slots,saving throw</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ACCELERATE --> 
	<element name="Accelerate" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ACCELERATE">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose up to three willing creatures within range, which can include you. For the duration of the spell, each target’s walking speed is doubled. Each target can also use a bonus action on each of its turns to take the Dash action, and it has advantage on Dexterity saving throws. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can affect one additional creature for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a toy top</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ACID GATE --> 	
	<element name="Acid Gate" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ACID_GATE">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a portal of swirling, acidic green vapor in an unoccupied space you can see. This portal connects with a target destination within 100 miles that you are personally familiar with and have seen with your own eyes, such as your wizard’s tower or an inn you have stayed at. You and up to three creatures of your choice can enter the portal and pass through it, arriving at the target destination (or within 10 feet of it, if it is currently occupied). If the target destination doesn’t exist or is inaccessible, the spell automatically fails and the gate doesn’t form. </p>
			<p class="indent">Any creature that tries to move through the gate, other than those selected by you when the spell was cast, takes 10d6 acid damage and is teleported 1d100 × 10 feet in a random, horizontal direction. If the creature makes a successful Intelligence saving throw, it can’t be teleported by this portal, but it still takes acid damage when it enters the acid-filled portal and every time it ends its turn in contact with it. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th level or higher, you can allow one additional creature to use the gate for each slot level above 7th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy,acid</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a vial of acid and a polished silver mirror worth 125 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ACID RAIN --> 
	<element name="Acid Rain" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ACID_RAIN">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You unleash a storm of swirling acid in a cylinder 20 feet wide and 30 feet high, centered on a point you can see. The area is heavily obscured by the driving acidfall. A creature that starts its turn in the area or that enters the area for the first time on its turn takes 6d6 acid damage, or half as much damage if it makes a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes half as much damage from the acid (as if it had made a successful saving throw) at the start of its first turn after leaving the affected area. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">150 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a drop of acid</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ALCHEMICAL FORM --> 
	<element name="Alchemical Form" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ALCHEMICAL_FORM">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You transform into an amoebic form composed of highly acidic and poisonous alchemical jelly. While in this form: </p>
			<p class="indent">-you are immune to acid and poison damage and to the poisoned and stunned conditions; </p>
			<p class="indent">-you have resistance to nonmagical fire, piercing, and slashing damage; </p>
			<p class="indent">-you can’t speak, cast spells, use items or weapons, or manipulate objects; </p>
			<p class="indent">-your gear melds into your body and reappears when the spell ends; </p>
			<p class="indent">-you don't need to breathe; </p>
			<p class="indent">-your speed is 20 feet; </p>
			<p class="indent">-your size doesn’t change, but you can move through and between obstructions as if you were two size categories smaller; and </p>
			<p class="indent">-you gain the following action: Melee Weapon Attack: spellcasting ability modifier + proficiency bonus to hit, range 5 ft., one target; Hit: 4d6 acid or poison damage (your choice), and the target must make a successful Constitution saving throw or be poisoned until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a vial of acid, poison, or alchemist's fire</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ALTER TIME FLOW --> 
	<element name="Alter Time Flow" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ALTER_TIME_FLOW">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You control the currents of time, affecting all creatures within 30 feet of yourself. You can choose to deliver either a haste or slow effect (as the spell) to each creature in the area. An unwilling creature makes a Constitution saving throw, avoiding the effect on a success. Each unwilling creature must make a new saving throw if it remains in the affected area at the end of its turn. Any affected creature returns to normal if it exits the area, but if a creature reenters the area while the spell is still active, it is subject to the effect of the spell (and receives another saving throw, if unwilling).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">time magic</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30-foot radius)</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an hourglass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- AMPLIFY LIGHT -->
	<element name="Amplify Light" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_AMPLIFY_LIGHT">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch a nonmagical light source and increase its brightness. While the spell is in effect, the radius of the bright light around the source is doubled, and dim light extends for the same distance beyond that area. The light source’s duration is halved, however, so that a torch affected by amplify light would burn out in half an hour, or a hooded lantern would burn through its fuel in 3 hours. Adding new fuel to a light source while it is under the effect of amplify light will end the spell and return it to its normal brightness.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Special</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a nonmagical light source</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ANGELIC GUARDIAN --> 
	<element name="Angelic Guardian" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ANGELIC_GUARDIAN">
		<supports>Cleric,Paladin,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You conjure a minor celestial manifestation to protect a creature you can see within range. A faintly glowing image resembling a human head and shoulders hovers within 5 feet of the target for the duration. The manifestation moves to interpose itself between the target and any incoming attacks, granting the target a +2 bonus to AC. </p>
			<p class="indent">Also, the first time the target gets a failure on a Dexterity saving throw while the spell is active, it can use its reaction to reroll the save. The spell then ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
		
<!-- ANTICIPATE ARCANA  -->
	<element name="Anticipate Arcana" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ANTICIPATE_ARCANA">
		<supports>Cleric,Paladin,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your foresight gives you an instant to ready your defenses against a magical attack. When you cast anticipate arcana, you have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects until the start of your next turn. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,time magic,reaction</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when an enemy you can see casts a spell</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ANTICIPATE ATTACK  -->	
	<element name="Anticipate Attack" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ANTICIPATE_ATTACK">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Paladin,Ranger,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>In a flash of foreknowledge, you spot an oncoming attack with enough time to avoid it. Upon casting this spell, you can move up to half your speed without provoking opportunity attacks. The oncoming attack still occurs but misses automatically if you are no longer within the attack’s range, are in a space that's impossible for the attack to hit, or can’t be targeted by that attack in your new position. If none of those circumstances apply but the situation has changed—you have moved into a position where you have cover, for example—then the attack is made after taking the new situation into account.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,reaction,time magic</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you are attacked but before the attack roll is made</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ANTICIPATE WEAKNESS --> 	
	<element name="Anticipate Weakness" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ANTICIPATE_WEAKNESS">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>With a quick glance into the future, you pinpoint where a gap is about to open in your foe’s defense, and then you strike. After casting anticipate weakness, you have advantage on attack rolls until the end of your turn. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,bonus action</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ASPECT OF THE DRAGON --> 
	<element name="Aspect of the Dragon" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ASPECT_OF_THE_DRAGON">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell draws out the ancient nature within your blood, allowing you to assume the form of any dragon-type creature of challenge 10 or less. </p>
			<p class="indent">You assume the hit points and Hit Dice of the new form. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn’t reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren’t knocked unconscious. </p>
			<p class="indent">You retain the benefits of any features from your class, race, or other source and can use them, provided that your new form is physically capable of doing so. You can speak only if the dragon can normally speak. </p>
			<p class="indent">When you transform, you choose whether your equipment falls to the ground, merges into the new form, or is worn by it. Worn equipment functions normally, but equipment doesn’t change shape or size to match the new form. Any equipment that the new form can’t wear must either fall to the ground or merge into the new form. The GM has final say on whether the new form can wear or use a particular piece of equipment. Equipment that merges has no effect in that state.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dragon scale</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- AUSPICIOUS WARNING  -->
	<element name="Auspicious Warning" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_AUSPICIOUS_WARNING">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Just in time, you call out a fortunate warning to a creature within range. The target rolls a d4 and adds the number rolled to an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw that it has just made and uses the new result for determining success or failure.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,time magic,reaction</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when an ally makes an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BABBLE  -->
	<element name="Babble" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BABBLE">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell causes the speech of affected creatures to sound like nonsense. Each creature in a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw when you cast this spell or be affected by it. </p>
			<p class="indent">An affected creature cannot communicate in any spoken language that it knows. When it speaks, the words come out as gibberish. Spells with verbal components cannot be cast. The spell does not affect telepathic communication, nonverbal communication, or sounds emitted by any creature that does not have a spoken language. As an action, a creature under the effect of this spell can attempt another Intelligence saving throw against the effect. On a successful save, the spell ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- BAD TIMING  -->
	<element name="Bad Timing" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BAD_TIMING">
		<supports></supports>
		<description>
			<p>You point toward a creature that you can see and twist strands of chaotic energy around its fate. If the target gets a failure on a Charisma saving throw, the next attack roll or ability check the creature attempts within 10 minutes is made with disadvantage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BENEDICTION --> 
	<element name="Benediction" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BENEDICTION">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You call down a blessing in the name of an angel of protection. A creature you can see within range shimmers with a faint white light. The next time the creature takes damage, it rolls a d4 and reduces the damage by the result. The spell then ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- BITING ARROW  -->
	<element name="Biting Arrow" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BITING_ARROW">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As part of the action used to cast this spell, you make a ranged weapon attack with a bow, a crossbow, or a thrown weapon. The effect is limited to a range of 120 feet despite the weapon’s range, and the attack is made with disadvantage if the target is in the weapon’s long range. </p>
			<p class="indent">If the weapon attack hits, it deals damage as usual. In addition, the target becomes coated in thin frost until the start of your next turn. If the target uses its reaction before the start of your next turn, it immediately takes 1d6 cold damage and the spell ends. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b>The spell’s damage, for both the ranged attack and the cold damage, increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (+1d6 and 2d6), 11th level (+2d6 and 3d6), and 17th level (+3d6 and 4d6).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an arrow or a thrown weapon</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- BLADE OF WRATH --> 	
	<element name="Blade of Wrath" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BLADE_OF_WRATH">
		<supports>Cleric,Paladin,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a sword of pure white fire in your free hand. The blade is similar in size and shape to a longsword, and it lasts for the duration. The blade disappears if you let go of it, but you can call it forth again as a bonus action. </p>
			<p class="indent">You can use your action to make a melee spell attack with the blade. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 fire damage and 2d8 radiant damage. An aberration, fey, fiend, or undead creature damaged by the blade must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened until the start of your next turn. </p>
			<p class="indent">The blade sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, either the fire damage or the radiant damage (your choice) increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a rebuke of evil, written in Celestial</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- BLAZING CHARIOT  -->
	<element name="Blazing Chariot" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BLAZING_CHARIOT">
		<supports>Cleric,Paladin,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Calling upon the might of the angels, you conjure a flaming chariot made of gold and mithral in an unoccupied 10-foot square space you can see within range. Two horses made of fire and light pull the chariot. You and up to three other Medium or smaller creatures you designate can board the chariot (at the cost of 5 feet of movement) and are unharmed by the flames. Any other creature that touches the chariot or hits it (or a creature riding in it) with a melee attack while within 5 feet of the chariot takes 3d6 fire damage and 3d6 radiant damage. The chariot has AC 18 and 50 hit points, is immune to fire, poison, psychic, and radiant damage, and has resistance to all other nonmagical damage. The horses are not separate creatures but are part of the chariot. The chariot vanishes if it is reduced to 0 hit points, and any creature riding it falls out. The chariot has a speed of 50 feet and a flying speed of 40 feet. </p>
			<p class="indent">On your turn, you can guide the chariot in place of your own movement. You can use a bonus action to direct it to take the Dash, Disengage, or Dodge action. As an action, you can use the chariot to overrun creatures in its path. On this turn, the chariot can enter a hostile creature’s space. The creature takes damage as if it had touched the chariot, is shunted to the nearest unoccupied space that it can occupy, and must make a successful Strength saving throw or fall prone in that space. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" additon="angelic">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small golden wheel worth 250 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- BLESSED HALO  -->
	<element name="Blessed Halo" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BLESSED_HALO">
		<supports>Cleric,Paladin,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A nimbus of golden light surrounds your head for the duration. The halo sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. </p>
			<p class="indent">This spell grants you a pool of 10 points of healing. When you cast the spell and as an action on subsequent turns during the spell’s duration, you can expend points from this pool to restore an equal number of hit points to one creature within 20 feet that you can see. </p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you have advantage on Charisma checks made against good creatures within 20 feet. </p>
			<p class="indent">If any of the light created by this spell overlaps an area of magical darkness created by a spell of 2nd level or lower, the spell that created the darkness is dispelled. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the spell’s pool of healing points increases by 5 for each spell slot above 2nd, and the spell dispels magical darkness created by a spell of a level equal to the slot used to cast this spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- BLIZZARD  -->
	<element name="Blizzard" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BLIZZARD">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A howling storm of thick snow and ice crystals appears in a cylinder 40 feet high and 40 feet in diameter within range. The area is heavily obscured by the swirling snow. When the storm appears, each creature in the area takes 8d8 cold damage, or half as much damage with a successful Constitution saving throw. A creature also makes this saving throw and takes damage when it enters the area for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there. In addition, a creature that takes cold damage from this spell has disadvantage on Constitution saving throws to maintain concentration until the start of its next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- BLOOD TO ACID --> 	
	<element name="Blood to Acid" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BLOOD_TO_ACID">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell, you designate a creature within range and convert its blood into virulent acid. The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 10d12 acid damage and is stunned by the pain for 1d4 rounds. On a successful save, it takes half the damage and isn’t stunned. </p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures without blood, such as constructs and plants, are not affected by this spell. If blood to acid is cast on a creature composed mainly of blood, such as a blood elemental or a blood zombie (Creature Codex, p. 393), the creature is slain by the spell if its saving throw fails.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
 
<!-- BOILING OIL --> 
	<element name="Boiling Oil" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BOILING_OIL">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You conjure a shallow, 15-foot-radius pool of boiling oil centered on a point within range. The pool is difficult terrain, and any creature that enters the pool or starts its turn there must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 3d8 fire damage and falls prone. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and doesn’t fall prone. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a vial of oil</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BOREAS’S BREATH  -->
	<element name="Boreas' Breath" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BOREAS_BREATH">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Ranger,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You freeze standing water in a 20-foot cube or running water in a 10-foot cube centered on you. The water turns to solid ice. The surface becomes difficult terrain, and any creature that ends its turn on the ice must make a successful DC 10 Dexterity saving throw or fall prone. </p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures that are partially submerged in the water when it freezes become restrained. While restrained in this way, a creature takes 1d6 cold damage at the end of its turn. It can break free by using an action to make a successful Strength check against your spell save DC. </p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures that are fully submerged in the water when it freezes become incapacitated and cannot breathe. While incapacitated in this way, a creature takes 2d6 cold damage at the end of its turn. A trapped creature makes a DC 20 Strength saving throw after taking this damage at the end of its turn, breaking free from the ice on a success. </p>
			<p class="indent">The ice has AC 10 and 15 hit points. It is vulnerable to fire damage, has resistance to nonmagical slashing and piercing damage, and is immune to cold, necrotic, poison, psychic, and thunder damage. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the size of the cube increases by 10 feet for each slot level above 2nd. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter,ritual</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BOTTLED ARCANA --> 
	<element name="Bottled Arcana" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BOTTLED_ARCANA">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By touching an empty, stoppered glass container such as a vial or flask, you magically enable it to hold a single spell. To be captured, the spell must be cast within 1 round of casting bottled arcana and it must be intentionally cast into the container. The container can hold one spell of 3rd level or lower. The spell can be held in the container for as much as 24 hours, after which the container reverts to a mundane vessel and any magic inside it dissipates harmlessly. </p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, any creature can unstop the container, thereby releasing the spell. If the spell has a range of self, the creature opening the container is affected; otherwise, the creature opening the container designates the target according to the captured spell’s description. If a creature opens the container unwittingly (not knowing that the container holds a spell), the spell targets the creature opening the container or is centered on its space instead (whichever is more appropriate). Dispel magic cast on the container targets bottled arcana, not the spell inside. If bottled arcana is dispelled, the container becomes mundane and the spell inside dissipates harmlessly. </p>
			<p class="indent">Until the spell in the container is released, its caster can’t regain the spell slot used to cast that spell. Once the spell is released, its caster regains the use of that slot normally. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the level of the spell the container can hold increases by one for every slot level above 5th. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">up to 24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an empty glass container</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BOTTOMLESS STOMACH --> 
	<element name="Bottomless Stomach" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BOTTOMLESS_STOMACH">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell, you gain the ability to consume dangerous substances and contain them in an extradimensional reservoir in your stomach. The spell allows you to swallow most liquids, such as acids, alcohol, poison, and even quicksilver, and hold them safely in your stomach. You are unaffected by swallowing the substance, but the spell doesn’t give you resistance or immunity to the substance in general; for example, you could safely drink a bucket of a black dragon’s acidic spittle, but you’d still be burned if you were caught in the dragon’s breath attack or if that bucket of acid were dumped over your head. </p>
			<p class="indent">The spell allows you to store up to 10 gallons of liquid at one time. The liquid doesn’t need to all be of the same type, and different types don’t mix while in your stomach. Any liquid in excess of 10 gallons has its normal effect when you try to swallow it. </p>
			<p class="indent">At any time before you stop concentrating on the spell, you can regurgitate up to 1 gallon of liquid stored in your stomach as a bonus action. The liquid is vomited into an adjacent 5-foot square. A target in that square must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or be affected by the liquid. The GM determines the exact effect based on the type of liquid regurgitated, using 1d6 damage of the appropriate type as the baseline. </p>
			<p class="indent">When you stop concentrating on the spell, its duration expires, or it’s dispelled, the extradimensional reservoir and the liquid it contains cease to exist. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BREATHTAKING WIND  -->
	<element name="Breathtaking Wind" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BREATHTAKING_WIND">
		<supports>Druid,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You target a creature with a blast of wintry air. That creature must make a successful Constitution saving throw or become unable to speak or cast spells with a vocal component for the duration of the spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- BRIMSTONE INFUSION --> 
	<element name="Brimstone Infusion" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BRIMSTONE_INFUSION">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You infuse an ordinary flask of alchemist’s fire with magical brimstone. While so enchanted, the alchemist’s fire can be thrown 40 feet instead of 20, and it does 2d6 fire damage instead of 1d4. The Dexterity saving throw to extinguish the flames uses your spell save DC instead of DC 10. Infused alchemist’s fire returns to its normal properties after 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a flask of alchemist's fire and 5 gp worth of brimstone</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- BRITTLING  -->
	<element name="Brittling" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BRITTLING">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell uses biting cold to make a metal or stone object you touch become brittle and more easily shattered. The object’s hit points are reduced by a number equal to your level as a spellcaster, and Strength checks to shatter or break the object are made with advantage if they occur within 1 minute of the spell’s casting. If the object isn’t shattered during this time, it reverts to the state it was in before the spell was cast.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an icicle</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- BURNING RADIANCE  -->
	<element name="Burning Radiance" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_BURNING_RADIANCE">
		<supports>Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A line of light 60 feet long and 5 feet wide emanates from you in a direction of your choice. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 10d8 radiant damage and catches fire; until someone takes an action to douse the fire, the creature takes 1d10 fire damage at the start of each of its turns. A successful saving throw halves the damage and prevents a creature from catching fire. </p>
			<p class="indent">The burning radiance ignites flammable objects in the area that aren’t being worn or carried.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (60 ft. line)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- CALM OF THE STORM  -->
	<element name="Calm of the Storm" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CALM_OF_THE_STORM">
		<supports>Bard,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>While visualizing the world as you wish it was, you lay your hands upon a creature other than yourself and undo the effect of a chaos magic surge that affected the creature within the last minute. Reality reshapes itself as if the surge never happened, but only for that creature. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the time since the chaos magic surge can be 1 minute longer for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an amethyst worth 250 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- CATCH THE BREATH -->
	<element name="Catch the Breath" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CATCH_THE_BREATH">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can cast this spell as a reaction when you’re targeted by a breath weapon. Doing so gives you advantage on your saving throw against the breath weapon. If your saving throw succeeds, you take no damage from the attack even if a successful save normally only halves the damage. </p>
			<p class="indent">Whether your saving throw succeeded or failed, you absorb and store energy from the attack. On your next turn, you can make a ranged spell attack against a target within 60 feet. On a hit, the target takes 3d10 force damage. If you opt not to make this attack, the stored energy dissipates harmlessly. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage done by your attack increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 3rd. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you make a saving throw against a breath weapon attack</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- CAUSTIC TORRENT --> 	
	<element name="Caustic Torrent" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CAUSTIC_TORRENT">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A swirling jet of acid sprays from you in a direction you choose. The acid fills a line 60 feet long and 5 feet wide. Each creature in the line takes 14d6 acid damage, or half as much damage if it makes a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature reduced to 0 hit points by this spell is killed, and its body is liquefied. In addition, each creature other than you that’s in the line or within 5 feet of it is poisoned for 1 minute by toxic fumes. Creatures that don’t breathe or that are immune to acid damage aren’t poisoned. A poisoned creature can repeat the Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (60 ft line)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a chip of bone pitted by acid</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- CAVE DRAGON’S DOMINANCE  -->
	<element name="Cave Dragon's Dominanace" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CAVE_DRAGONS_DOMINANCE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You take on some of the physical characteristics and abilities of the cave dragon, growing protective scales and claws. Until the spell ends, your AC can’t be lower than 16, regardless of what kind of armor you are wearing. You gain blindsight out to a range of 60 feet. You can take two actions on your turn to attack with your claws, dealing 1d6 slashing damage on a hit. You have resistance to poison damage. Up to three times while the spell is active, as an action, you can breathe a 20-foot cone of poison gas, dealing 6d8 poison damage to each creature in the cone and making it poisoned until it finishes a long or short rest. A creature that succeeds on a Constitution saving throw takes half as much damage from your breath weapon and is not poisoned. Finally, you gain a climbing speed of 40 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- CELESTIAL FANFARE --> 	
	<element name="Celestial Fanfare" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CELESTIAL_FANFARE">
		<supports>Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A great blaring of trumpets from on high blasts down upon an area you designate. All evil creatures in a 30-foot radius take 4d6 thunder damage and 4d6 radiant damage and are blinded and deafened for 2d4 rounds. A successful Constitution saving throw reduces the damage and the duration of the blinded and deafened conditions by half. </p>
			<p class="indent">Neutral or unaligned creatures within the area take half as much damage and are blinded and deafened for 1d4 rounds. A successful save reduces the damage to one quarter and negates the blinding and deafening effects. </p>
			<p class="indent">Good-aligned creatures are not harmed by this spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">miniature trumpet worth 100 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- CHAOTIC FORM  -->
	<element name="Chaotic Form" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CHAOTIC_FORM">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cause the form of a willing creature to become malleable, dripping and flowing according to the target’s will as if the creature were a vaguely humanoid-shaped ooze. The creature is not affected by difficult terrain, it has advantage on Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks made to escape a grapple, and it suffers no penalties when squeezing through spaces one size smaller than itself. The target’s movement is halved while it is affected by chaotic form. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the duration increases by 10 minutes for each slot level above 4th. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- CHAOTIC VITALITY  -->		
	<element name="Chaotic Vitality" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CHAOTIC_VITALITY">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Make a melee spell attack against a creature that has a number of Hit Dice no greater than your level and has at least 1 hit point. On a hit, you conjure pulsating waves of chaotic energy within the creature and yourself. After a brief moment that seems to last forever, your hit point total changes, as does the creature’s. Roll a d100 and increase or decrease the number rolled by any number up to your spellcasting level, then find the result on the Hit Point Flux table. Apply that result both to yourself and the target creature. Any hit points gained beyond a creature’s normal maximum are temporary hit points that last for 1 round per caster level. </p>
			<p class="indent">For example, a 3rd-level spellcaster who currently has 17 of her maximum 30 hit points casts chaotic vitality on a creature with 54 hit points and rolls a 75 on the Hit Point Flux table. The two creatures have a combined total of 71 hit points. A result of 75 indicates that both creatures get 50 percent of the total, so the spellcaster and the target end up with 35 hit points each. In the spellcaster’s case, 5 of those hit points are temporary and will last for 3 rounds. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the maximum Hit Dice of the affected creature increases by 2 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d100</td><td>HP</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>01–09</td><td>0</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10–39</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td>40–69</td><td>25 percent of total</td></tr>
				<tr><td>70–84</td><td>50 percent of total</td></tr>
				<tr><td>85–94</td><td>75 percent of total</td></tr>
				<tr><td>95–99</td><td>100 percent of total</td></tr>
				<tr><td>100</td><td>200 percent of total, and both creatures gain the effect of a haste spell that lasts for 1 round per caster level</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- CHAOTIC WORLD  -->
	<element name="Chaotic World" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CHAOTIC_WORLD">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You throw a handful of colored cloth into the air while screaming a litany of disjointed phrases. A moment later, a 30-foot cube centered on a point within range fills with multicolored light, cacophonous sound, overpowering scents, and other confusing sensory information. The effect is dizzying and overwhelming. Each enemy within the cube must make a successful Intelligence saving throw or become blinded and deafened, and fall prone. An affected enemy cannot stand up or recover from the blindness or deafness while within the area, but all three conditions end immediately for a creature that leaves the spell’s area. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">seven irregular pieces of colored cloth that you throw into the air</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- CHRONAL LANCE --> 	
	<element name="Chronal Lance" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CHRONAL_LANCE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You inflict the ravages of aging on up to three creatures within range, temporarily discomfiting them and making them appear elderly for a time. Each target must make a successful Wisdom saving throw, or its walking speed is halved (round up to the nearest 5-foot increment) and it has disadvantage on Dexterity checks (but not saving throws). An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal,clockwork">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- CLAIM LAIR --> 
	<element name="Claim Lair" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CLAIM_LAIR">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By placing your personal wealth within an area and invoking the dragon’s territorial nature, you claim the area as your lair, imbuing you with extra power within its confines. You can claim an area of up to 2,500 square feet (a space 50 feet square, or one hundred 5-foot squares, or twenty-five 10-foot squares). The claimed area can be up to 20 feet tall and shaped as you desire. While within these confines, you can take one of the following lair actions once per round on initiative count 20: </p>
			<p class="indent">• Magical darkness spreads from a point you choose within 30 feet, filling a 15-foot-radius sphere until you dismiss it as an action, use this lair action again, or die. The darkness spreads around corners. A creature with darkvision can’t see through this darkness, and nonmagical light can’t illuminate it, but you can see in the area as if it were brightly lit. If any of the effect’s area overlaps with an area of light created by a spell of 2nd level or lower, the spell that created the light is dispelled. </p>
			<p class="indent">• Part of the ceiling collapses above one creature you can see within 60 feet of you. The creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take 3d6 bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone and buried. A buried target is restrained and unable to breathe or stand up. A creature can take an action to make a DC 10 Strength check, ending the buried state with a success. </p>
			<p class="indent">• A tremor shakes the lair in a 30-foot radius around you. Each creature on the ground in that area other than you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or be knocked prone. </p>
			<p class="indent">You can take an action to dismiss this spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hrs</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">material goods and wealth worth at least 2,000 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- CLASH OF GLACIERS  -->
	<element name="Clash of Glacieers" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CLASH_OF_GLACIERS">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You conjure up icy boulders that crush creatures in a line 100 feet long. Each creature in the area takes 5d6 bludgeoning damage plus 5d6 cold damage, or half the damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 5th. You decide whether each extra die deals bludgeoning or cold damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (100 ft line)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of cracked glass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- CLAWS OF THE EARTH DRAGON  -->
	<element name="Claws of the Earth Dragon" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CLAWS_OF_THE_EARTH_DRAGON">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon the power of the earth dragon and shoot a ray at one target within 60 feet. The target falls prone and takes 6d8 bludgeoning damage from being slammed to the ground. If the target was flying or levitating, it takes an additional 1d6 bludgeoning damage per 10 feet it falls. If the target makes a successful Strength saving throw, damage is halved, it doesn’t fall, and it isn’t knocked prone. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage done by the attack increases by 1d8 and the range increases by 10 feet for each slot level above 5th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- CONTROL ICE  -->
	<element name="Control Ice" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CONTROL_ICE">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Until the spell ends, you control any ice inside an area you choose within range that can be as large as a cube 100 feet on a side. You choose one of the following three effects when you cast this spell. As an action on each of your turns thereafter, you can use the same effect or choose a different one. Any alterations made to the ice remain after the spell ends, but can be altered by other effects (temperature, seismic action, or another application of this spell, for example). </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Crack</i></b>. You cause ice in the area to crack and splinter. On level terrain, this effect turns the ice into difficult terrain, possibly producing other hazards, depending on the terrain and the nature of the ice—ice over a deep chasm might open onto a pit, while ice over water can break into individual floes, for example. Using this effect on cliffs, walls, or ceilings made of ice can cause collapse, dealing 4d10 bludgeoning damage to creatures in the area below the collapse, or half the damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. After such a collapse, the area where the fallen ice collects becomes difficult terrain. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Reshape.</i></b> You cause ice in a portion of the area to rapidly melt, move, and re-form into whatever shape you command. You can block holes, open tunnels, form bridges, remove difficult terrain, or otherwise alter the form of the ice in the area. You can cause ice to become slippery, making it difficult terrain, or dry to remove difficult terrain. You can fill a hole up to a 20-foot cube, or create 20 feet (up to 20 feet wide) of a bridge across a chasm, or raise a 20-foot-tall pillar of ice (up to 20 feet square). You can continue this action on consecutive rounds to increase the size of the affected area while you maintain concentration on the spell. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Thicken/Thin.</i></b> You cause existing ice to increase or decrease in thickness, up to 1 inch per round over some or all of the total area, either making the surface stronger or creating thin ice that is hazardous to walk on. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">300 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a cube of white wax</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- CONVERSE WITH DRAGON  -->
	<element name="Converse with Dragon" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CONVERSE_WITH_DRAGON">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Ranger,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain limited telepathy, allowing you to communicate with any creature within 120 feet of you that has the dragon type, regardless of the creature’s languages. A dragon can choose to make a Charisma saving throw to prevent telepathic contact with itself. </p>
			<p class="indent">This spell doesn’t change a dragon’s disposition toward you or your allies, it only opens a channel of communication. In some cases, unwanted telepathic contact can worsen the dragon’s attitude toward you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- CREEPING ICE  -->
	<element name="Creeping Ice" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CREEPING_ICE">
		<supports>Druid,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a sheet of ice that covers a 5-foot square within range and lasts for the spell’s duration. The iced area is difficult terrain. </p>
			<p class="indent">A creature in the area where you cast the spell must make a successful Strength saving throw or be restrained by ice that rapidly encases it. A creature restrained by the ice takes 2d6 cold damage at the start of its turn. A restrained creature can use an action to make a Strength check against your spell save DC, freeing itself on a success, but it has disadvantage on this check. The creature can also be freed (and the spell ended) by dealing at least 20 damage to the ice. The restrained creature takes half the damage from any attacks against the ice. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th to 6th level, the area increases to a 10-foot square, the ice deals 4d6 cold damage, and 40 damage is needed to melt each 5-foot square. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the area increases to a 20-foot square, the ice deals 6d6 cold damage, and 60 damage is needed to melt each 5-foot square.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- CURSE OF BOREAS  -->
	<element name="Curse of Boreas" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_CURSE_OF_BOREAS">
		<supports>Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You designate a creature within range that you can see. If the target fails a Charisma saving throw, it and its equipment are frozen solid, becoming an inert statue of ice. The creature is effectively paralyzed, but mental activity does not cease, and signs of life are detectable; the creature still breathes and its heart continues to beat, though both acts are almost imperceptible. If the ice statue is broken or damaged while frozen, the creature will have matching damage or injury when returned to its original state. Dispel magic can’t end this spell, but it can allow the target to speak (but not move or cast spells) for a number of rounds equal to the spell slot used. Greater restoration or more potent magic is needed to free a creature from the ice.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Permanent</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- DEADLY STING --> 
	<element name="Deadly Sting" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DEADLY_STING">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You grow a 10-foot-long tail as supple as a whip, tipped with a horrible stinger. During the spell’s duration, you can use the stinger to make a melee spell attack with a reach of 10 feet. On a hit, the target takes 1d4 piercing damage plus 4d10 poison damage, and a creature must make a successful Constitution saving throw or become vulnerable to poison damage for the duration of the spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a thorn</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- DECELERATE -->
	<element name="Decelerate" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DECELERATE">
		<supports>Druid,Paladin,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You slow the flow of time around a creature within range that you can see. The creature must make a successful Wisdom saving throw, or its walking speed is halved (round up to the nearest 5-foot increment). The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. Until the spell ends, on a failed save the target’s speed is halved again at the start of each of your turns. For example, if a creature with a speed of 30 feet fails its initial saving throw, its speed drops to 15 feet. At the start of your next turn, the creature’s speed drops to 10 feet on a failed save, then to 5 feet on the  following round on another failed save. Decelerate can’t reduce a creature’s speed to less than 5 feet. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can affect an additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,time magic</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a toy top</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- DEEP FREEZE  -->
	<element name="Deep Freeze" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DEEP_FREEZE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You send a blast of deep cold at a creature, dealing 4d8 cold damage to it and encasing it in ice. An encased creature is grappled and takes an extra 2d8 cold damage at the start of its turn every round it remains encased. If the target of this spell makes a successful Dexterity saving throw, it takes half the damage and none of the extra damage and is not encased in ice, but the ice that clings to its body reduces its speed by 15 feet (to a minimum speed of 5 feet) until it takes an action to remove the ice. </p>
			<p class="indent">A grappled target can take an action to make a Strength check against your spell save DC, breaking free of the ice on a success. Alternatively, another creature within 5 feet of the target can make a Strength check on its turn, freeing the creature on a success. The ice can also be attacked. It has AC 12, 10 hit points, and vulnerability to fire damage. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of ice or quartz</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- DELAY POTION --> 	
	<element name="Delay Potion" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DELAY_POTION">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Upon casting this spell, you delay the next potion you consume from taking effect for up to 1 hour. You must consume the potion within 1 round of casting delay potion; otherwise the spell has no effect. At any point during delay potion’s duration, you can use a bonus action to cause the potion to go into effect. When the potion is activated, it works as if you had just drunk it. While the potion is delayed, it has no effect at all and you can consume and benefit from other potions normally. </p>
			<p class="indent">You can delay only one potion at a time. If you try to delay the effect of a second potion, the spell fails, the first potion has no effect, and the second potion has its normal effect when you drink it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- DETECT DRAGONS --> 
	<element name="Detect Dragons" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DETECT_DRAGONS">
		<supports>Bard,Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can detect the presence of dragons and other draconic creatures within your line of sight and 120 feet, regardless of disguises, illusions, and alteration magic such as polymorph. The information you uncover depends on the number of consecutive rounds you spend an action studying a subject or area. On the first round of examination, you detect whether any draconic creatures are present, but not their number, location, identity, or type. On the second round, you learn the number of such creatures as well as the general condition of the most powerful one. On the third and subsequent rounds, you make a DC 15 Intelligence (Arcana) check; if it succeeds, you learn the age, type, and location of one draconic creature. Note that the spell provides no information on the turn in which it is cast, unless you have the means to take a second action that turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- DEVA’S WINGS --> 	
	<element name="Deva's Wings" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DEVAS_WINGS">
		<supports>Cleric,Paladin,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch a willing creature. The target grows feathery wings of pure white that grant it a flying speed of 60 feet and the ability to hover. When the target takes the Attack action, it can use a bonus action to make a melee weapon attack with the wings, with a reach of 10 feet. If the wing attack hits, the target takes bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your spellcasting ability modifier and must make a successful Strength saving throw or fall prone. When the spell ends, the wings disappear, and the target falls if it was aloft. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can target one additional target for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a wing feather from any bird</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- DRACONIC MAJESTY  -->
	<element name="Draconic Majesty" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DRACONIC_MAJESTY">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You exude the powerful presence of a dragon, frightening your enemies. For the duration of the spell, all creatures who are aware of your presence and within 30 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the radius increases by 30 feet for each slot level above 3rd, to a maximum of 120 feet for a slot of 6th level or higher.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30ft. radius)</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- DRACONIC SENSES --> 
	<element name="Draconic Senses" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DRACONIC_SENSES">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You enhance your senses, granting yourself the keen perception of a dragon. For the duration of the spell, you gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, its range increases by 60 feet. You also gain blindsight out to a range of 60 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hrs</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- DRACONIC SMITE  -->
	<element name="Draconic Smite" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DRACONIC_SMITE">
		<supports>Druid,Paladin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The next time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack during the spell’s duration, your weapon takes on the form of a silver dragon’s head. Your attack deals an extra 1d6 cold damage, and up to four other creatures of your choosing within 30 feet of the attack’s target must each make a successful Constitution saving throw or take 1d6 cold damage. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the extra cold damage and the cold damage dealt to the secondary creatures increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- DRAGON BREATH  -->
	<element name="Dragon Breath" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DRAGON_BREATH">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon draconic power to gain a breath weapon. When you cast dragon breath, you can immediately exhale a cone or line of elemental energy, depending on the type of dragon you select. While the spell remains active, roll a d6 at the start of your turn. On a roll of 5 or 6, you can take a bonus action that turn to use the breath weapon again. </p>
			<p class="indent">When you cast the spell, choose one of the dragon types listed below. Your choice determines the affected area and the damage of the breath attack for the spell’s duration.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 2d6 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Dragon Type</td><td>Area</td><td>Damage</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Black</td><td>30-foot line, 5 feet wide</td><td>6d6 acid damage </td></tr>
				<tr><td>Blue </td><td>30-foot line, 5 feet wide</td><td>6d6 lightning damage </td></tr>
				<tr><td>Green</td><td>15-foot cone</td><td>	6d6 poison damage </td></tr>
				<tr><td>Red</td><td>15-foot cone</td><td>6d6 fire damage </td></tr>
				<tr><td>White</td><td>15-foot cone</td><td>	6d6 cold damage</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (15 ft. cone or 30 ft. line)</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of a dragon's tooth</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- DRAGON ROAR --> 
	<element name="Dragon Roar" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DRAGON_ROAR">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your voice is amplified to assault the mind of one creature. The target must make a Charisma saving throw. If it fails, the target takes 1d4 psychic damage and is frightened until the start of your next turn. A target can be affected by your dragon roar only once per 24 hours. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> This spell’s damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- DRAGON’S PRIDE -->
	<element name="Dragon's Pride" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_DRAGONS_PRIDE">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your sense of self grows to draconic proportions. Until the spell ends, you gain advantage on all Charisma checks and on all saving throws against being charmed or frightened.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ELEMENTAL TWIST  -->
	<element name="Elemental Twist" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ELEMENTAL _TWIST">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>During this spell’s duration, reality shifts around you whenever you cast a spell that deals acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison, or thunder damage. Assign each damage type a number and roll a d6 to determine the type of damage this casting of the spell deals. In addition, the spell’s damage increases by 1d6. All other properties or effects of the spell are unchanged. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a thin piece of copper twisted around itself</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ENHANCE GREED  -->
	<element name="Enhance Greed" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ENHANCE_GREED">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You detect precious metals, gems, and jewelry within 60 feet. You do not discern their exact location, only their presence and direction. Their exact location is revealed if you are within 10 feet of the spot. </p>
			<p class="indent">Enhance greed penetrates barriers but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of dirt or wood. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the duration of the spell increases by 1 minute, and another 10 feet can be added to its range, for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ENTOMB IN ICE  -->
	<element name="Entomb in Ice" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ENTOMB_IN_ICE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You trap a creature in a thick coating of ice. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be restrained for the duration. At the beginning of the trapped creature’s turn, it takes 2d4 cold damage. On its turn, an entombed creature (or an ally) can take an action to make a Strength check against your spell save DC. On a success, the entombed creature is freed. The icy tomb is also susceptible to damage and vulnerable to fire. Damage equal to your spell save DC will destroy the tomb and free the target.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 3rd. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- ENTROPIC DAMAGE FIELD  -->
	<element name="Entropic Damage Field" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ENTROPIC_DAMAGE_FIELD">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By twisting a length of silver wire around your finger, you tie your fate to those around you. When you take damage, that damage is divided equally between you and all creatures in range who get a failure on a Charisma saving throw. Any leftover damage that can’t be divided equally is taken by you. Creatures that approach to within 60 feet of you after the spell was cast are also affected. A creature is allowed a new saving throw against this spell each time you take damage, and a successful save ends the spell’s effect on that creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a silver wire</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- EVERCOLD  -->
	<element name="Evercold" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_EVERCOLD">
		<supports>Cleric,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You target a creature within the spell’s range, and that creature must make a successful Wisdom saving throw or take 1d6 cold damage. In addition, the target is cursed to feel as if it’s exposed to extreme cold. For the duration of evercold, the target must make a successful DC 10 Constitution saving throw at the end of each hour or gain one level of exhaustion. The target has advantage on the hourly saving throws if wearing suitable cold-weather clothing, but it has disadvantage on saving throws against other spells and magic that deal cold damage (regardless of its clothing) for the spell’s duration. </p>
			<p class="indent">The spell can be ended by its caster or by dispel magic or remove curse.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Until dispelled</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an insect that froze to death</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- FIRE DRAGON’S FURY --> 
	<element name="Fire Dragon'S Fury" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FIRE_DRAGONS_FURY">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You take on some of the physical characteristics and abilities of the fire dragon, growing protective scales, wings, and claws. Until the spell ends, your AC can’t be less than 16, regardless of what kind of armor you are wearing. You can take two actions on your turn to attack with your claws, dealing 1d6 slashing damage on a hit. You are resistant to fire. Up to three times while the spell is active, as an action, you can breathe a 20-foot cone of flames, dealing 6d8 fire damage to all creatures in the cone. A creature that succeeds on a Dexterity saving throw takes half as much damage from your breath weapon. Finally, the wings grant you a flying speed of 40 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- FLICKERING FATE --> 	
	<element name="Flickering Fate" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FLICKERING_FATE">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You or a creature that you touch can see a few seconds into the future. When the spell is cast, each other creature within 30 feet of the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. Those that fail must declare, in initiative order, what their next action will be. The target of the spell declares his or her action last, after hearing what all other creatures will do. Each creature that declared an action must follow its declaration as closely as possible when its turn comes. For the duration of the spell, the target has advantage on attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws, and creatures that declared their actions have disadvantage on attack rolls against the target.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,time magic</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- FLUCTUATING ALIGNMENT --> 		
	<element name="Fluctating Alignment" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FLUCTUATING_ALIGNMENT">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You channel the force of chaos to taint your target’s mind. A target that gets a failure on a Wisdom saving throw must roll 1d20 and consult the Alignment Fluctuation table to find its new alignment, and it must roll again after every minute of the spell’s duration. The target’s alignment stops fluctuating and returns to normal when the spell ends. These changes do not make the affected creature friendly or hostile toward the caster, but they can cause creatures to behave in unpredictable ways.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d20</td><td>Alignment</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1–2</td><td>Chaotic good</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3–4</td><td>Chaotic neutral</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5–7</td><td>Chaotic evil</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8–9</td><td>Neutral evil</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10–11</td><td>Lawful evil</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12–14</td><td>Lawful good</td></tr>
				<tr><td>15–16</td><td>Lawful neutral</td></tr>
				<tr><td>17–18</td><td>Neutral good</td></tr>
				<tr><td>19–20</td><td>Neutral</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- FLURRY  -->
	<element name="Flurry" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FLURRY">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Ranger,Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A flurry of snow surrounds you and extends to a 5-foot radius around you. While it lasts, anyone trying to see into, out of, or through the affected area (including you) has disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks and attack rolls.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a fleck of quartz</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- FORETELL DISTRACTION --> 	
	<element name="Foretell Distraction" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FORETELL_DISTRACTION">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Thanks to your foreknowledge, you know exactly when your foe will take his or her eyes off you. Casting this spell has the same effect as making a successful Dexterity (Stealth) check, provided cover or concealment is available within 10 feet of you. It doesn’t matter whether enemies can see you when you cast the spell; they glance away at just the right moment. You can move up to 10 feet as part of casting the spell, provided you’re able to move (not restrained or grappled or reduced to a speed of less than 10 feet for any other reason). This move doesn’t count as part of your normal movement. After the spell is cast, you must be in a position where you can remain hidden: a lightly obscured space, for example, or a space where you have total cover. Otherwise, enemies see you again immediately and you’re not hidden.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,bonus action</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- FREEZE BLOOD  -->
	<element name="Freeze Blood" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FREEZE_BLOOD">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast freeze blood as a successful melee spell attack against a living creature with a circulatory system, the creature’s blood freezes. For the spell’s duration, the affected creature’s speed is halved and it takes 2d6 cold damage at the start of each of its turns. If the creature takes bludgeoning damage from a critical hit, the attack’s damage dice are rolled three times instead of twice. At the end of each of its turns, the creature can make a Constitution saving throw, ending the effect on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- FREEZE POTION  -->
	<element name="Freeze Potion" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FREEZE_POTION">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A blue spark flies from your hand and strikes a potion vial, drinking horn, waterskin, or similar container, instantly freezing the contents. The substance melts normally thereafter and is not otherwise harmed, but it can’t be consumed while it’s frozen. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the range increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you see a creature about to consume a liquid</set>
			<set name="range">25 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- FRENZIED BOLT  -->
	<element name="Frenzied Bolt" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FRENZIED_BOLT">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You direct a bolt of rainbow colors toward a creature of your choice within range. If the bolt hits, the target takes 3d8 damage, of a type determined by rolling on the Random Damage Type table. If your attack roll (not the adjusted result) was odd, the bolt leaps to a new target of your choice within range that has not already been targeted by frenzied bolt, requiring a new spell attack roll to hit. The bolt continues leaping to new targets until you roll an even number on your spell attack roll, miss a target, or run out of potential targets. You and your allies are legal targets for this spell, if you are particularly lucky—or unlucky. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you create an additional bolt for each slot level above 2nd. Each potential target can be hit only once by each casting of the spell, not once per bolt. </p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Damage Type</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Acid</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Cold</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Force</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Lightning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Necrotic</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Poison</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>Psychic</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>Radiant</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>Thunder</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- FROSTBITE  -->
	<element name="Frostbite" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FROSTBITE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Biting cold settles onto a creature you can see. The creature must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 4d8 cold damage. In addition, for the duration of the spell, the creature’s speed is halved, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks, and it takes another 4d8 cold damage at the start of each of its turns. </p>
			<p class="indent">An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the start of each of its turns. The effect ends when the creature makes its third successful save. </p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures that are immune to cold damage are unaffected by frostbite. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can target two additional creatures for each slot level above 5th</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">90 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a strip of dried flesh that has been frozen at least once</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- FROSTBITTEN FINGERS  -->
	<element name="Frostbitten Fingers" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FROSTBITTEN_FINGERS">
		<supports>Druid,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You fire a ray of intense cold that instantly induces frostbite. With a successful ranged spell attack, this spell causes one of the target’s hands to lose sensation. When the spell is cast, the target must make a successful Dexterity saving throw to maintain its grip on any object with the affected hand. The saving throw must be repeated every time the target tries to manipulate, wield, or pick up an item with the affected hand. Additionally, the target has disadvantage on Dexterity checks or Strength checks that require the use of both hands. </p>
			<p class="indent">After every 10 minutes of being affected by frostbitten fingers, the target must make a successful Constitution saving throw, or take 1d6 cold damage and lose one of the fingers on the affected hand, beginning with the pinkie.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- FUSILLADE OF ICE  -->
	<element name="Fusillade of Ice" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_FUSILLADE_OF_ICE">
		<supports>Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You unleash a spray of razor-sharp ice shards. Each creature in the 30-foot cone takes 4d6 cold damage and 3d6 piercing damage, or half as much damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by your choice of 1d6 cold damage or 1d6 piercing damage for each slot level above 4th. You can make a different choice (cold damage or piercing damage) for each slot level above 4th. Casting this spell with a spell slot of 6th level or higher increases the range to a 60-foot cone.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30 ft. cone)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dagger shaped like an icicle</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- GLACIAL CASCADE  -->
	<element name="Glacial Cascade" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GLACIAL_CASCADE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By harnessing the power of ice and frost, you emanate pure cold, filling a 30-foot-radius sphere. Creatures other than you in the sphere take 10d8 cold damage, or half as much damage with a successful Constitution saving throw. A creature killed by this spell is transformed into ice, leaving behind no trace of its original body.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30 ft. radius sphere)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of alexandrite</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- GLACIAL FOG  -->
	<element name="Glacial Fog" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GLACIAL_FOG">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As you cast this spell, a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on a point within range becomes covered in a frigid fog. Each creature that is in the area at the start of its turn while the spell remains in effect must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 12d6 cold damage and gains one level of exhaustion, and it has disadvantage on Perception checks until the start of its next turn. On a successful save, the creature takes half the damage and ignores the other effects. </p>
			<p class="indent">Stored devices and tools are all frozen by the fog: crossbow mechanisms become sluggish, weapons are stuck </p>
			<p class="indent">in scabbards, potions turn to ice, bag cords freeze together, and so forth. Such items require the application of heat for 1 round or longer in order to become useful again. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 7th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">crystalline statue of a polar bear worth at least 25 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- GLUEY GLOBULE  -->	
	<element name="Gluey Globule" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GLUEY_GLOBULE">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You make a ranged spell attack to hurl a large globule of sticky, magical glue at a creature within 120 feet. If the attack hits, the target creature is restrained. A restrained creature can break free by using an action to make a successful Strength saving throw. When the creature breaks free, it takes 2d6 slashing damage from the glue tearing its skin. If your ranged spell attack roll was a critical hit or exceeded the target’s AC by 5 or more, the Strength saving throw is made with disadvantage. The target can also be freed by an application of universal solvent or by taking 20 acid damage. The glue dissolves when the creature breaks free or at the end of 1 minute. </p>
			<p class="indent">Alternatively, gluey globule can also be used to glue an object to a solid surface or to another object. In this case, the spell works like a single application of sovereign glue and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute or 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a drop of glue</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- GREATER PROTECTIVE NIMBUS --> 
	<element name="Greater Protective Nimbus" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GREATER_PROTECTIVE_NIMBUS">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You wrap yourself in a powerful corona that sheds bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. Until the spell ends, you have resistance to necrotic damage and radiant damage. You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it, which creates a blast of light in a 30-foot radius. The blast deals 4d8 radiant damage to each creature in the area while simultaneously healing yourself of an equal amount of damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a transparent gemstone worth at least 50 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- GREATER SEAL OF SANCTUARY --> 
	<element name="Greater Seal of Sanctuary" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GREATER_SEAL_OF_SANCTUARY">
		<supports>Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You inscribe an angelic seal on the ground, the floor, or other solid surface of a structure. The seal creates a spherical sanctuary with a radius of 100 feet, centered on the seal. For the duration, aberrations, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead that approach to within 5 feet of the boundary know they are about to come into contact with a deadly barrier. If such a creature moves so as to touch the boundary, or tries to cross the boundary by any means, including teleportation and extradimensional travel, it must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 15d8 radiant damage, is repelled to 5 feet outside the boundary, and can’t target anything inside the boundary with attacks, spells, or abilities until the spell ends. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much radiant damage and can cross the boundary. If the creature is a fiend that isn’t on its home plane, it is immediately destroyed (no saving throw) instead of taking damage. </p>
			<p class="indent">Aberrations, elementals, fey, and undead that are within 100 feet of the seal (inside the boundary) have disadvantage on ability checks, attack rolls, and saving throws, and each such creature takes 4d8 radiant damage at the start of its turn. </p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures other than aberrations, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead can’t be charmed or frightened while within 100 feet of the seal.</p>
			<p class="indent">The seal has AC 18, 75 hit points, resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, and immunity to psychic and poison damage. Ranged attacks against the seal are made with disadvantage. If it is scribed on the surface of an object that is later destroyed (such as a wooden door), the seal is not damaged and remains in place, perhaps suspended in midair. The spell ends only if the seal itself is reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic,ritual</set>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">incense and special inks worth 500 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- GUIDING STAR -->
	<element name="Guiding Star" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GUIDING_STAR">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By observing the stars or the position of the sun, you are able to determine the cardinal directions, as well as the direction and distance to a stated destination. You can’t become directionally disoriented or lose track of the destination. The spell doesn’t, however, reveal the best route to your destination or warn you about deep gorges, flooded rivers, or other impassable or treacherous terrain.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- ICE BURN  -->
	<element name="Ice Burn" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ICE_BURN">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You instill deep cold into the body of a creature within range, damaging it and impairing joints and muscles. The target takes 3d10 cold damage and has disadvantage on all Dexterity checks and Dexterity saving throws until this damage is healed. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can target one additional creature within range for each slot level above 3rd. Each additional target must be within 30 feet of at least one other target.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- ICE FORTRESS  -->
	<element name="Ice Fortress" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ICE_FORTRESS">
		<supports>Cleric, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A gleaming fortress of ice springs from a square area of ground that you can see within range. It is a 10-foot cube (including floor and roof). The fortress can’t overlap any other structures, but any creatures in its space are harmlessly lifted up as the ice rises into position. The walls are made of ice (AC 13), have 120 hit points each, and are immune to cold, necrotic, poison, and psychic damage. Reducing a wall to 0 hit points destroys it and has a 50 percent chance to cause the roof to collapse. A damaged wall can be repaired by casting a spell that deals cold damage on it, on a point-for-point basis. </p>
			<p class="indent">Each wall has two arrow slits. One wall also includes an ice door with an arcane lock. You designate at the time of the fort’s creation which creatures can enter the fortification. The door has AC 18 and 60 hit points, or it can be broken open with a successful DC 25 Strength (Athletics) check (DC 15 if the arcane lock is dispelled). </p>
			<p class="indent">The fortress catches and reflects light, so that creatures outside the fortress who rely on sight have disadvantage on Perception checks and attack rolls made against those within the fortress if it’s in an area of bright sunlight. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can increase the length or width of the fortification by 5 feet for every slot level above 5th. You can make a different choice (width or length) for each slot level above 5th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Until dispelled or destroyed</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a minuature keep carved from ice or glass that is consumed in the casting</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- ICE HAMMER  -->
	<element name="Ice Hammer" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ICE_HAMMER">
		<supports>Cleric, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast ice hammer, a warhammer fashioned from ice appears in your hands. This weapon functions as a standard warhammer in all ways, and it deals an extra 1d10 cold damage on a hit. You can drop the warhammer or give it to another creature. </p>
			<p class="indent">The warhammer melts and is destroyed when it or its user accumulates 20 or more fire damage, or when the spell ends. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can create one additional hammer for each slot level above 2nd. Alternatively, you can create half as many hammers (round down), but each is oversized (1d10 bludgeoning damage, or 1d12 if wielded with two hands, plus 2d8 cold damage). Medium or smaller creatures have disadvantage when using oversized weapons, even if they are proficient with them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a minuature hammer carved from ice or glass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- ICICLE DAGGERS  -->
	<element name="Icicle Daggers" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ICICLE_DAGGERS">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell, three icicles appear in your hand. Each icicle has the same properties as a dagger but deals an extra 1d4 cold damage on a hit. </p>
			<p class="indent">The icicle daggers melt a few seconds after leaving your hand, making it impossible for other creatures to wield them. If the surrounding temperature is at or below freezing, the daggers last for 1 hour. They melt instantly if you take 10 or more fire damage. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can create two additional daggers for each slot level above 1st. If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, daggers that leave your hand don’t melt until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous or special</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a miniature dagger shaped like an icicle</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- ILL-FATED WORD  -->
	<element name="Ill-Fated Word" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ILL_FATED_WORD">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Word</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You call out a distracting epithet to a creature, worsening its chance to succeed at whatever it’s doing. Roll a d4 and subtract the number rolled from an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw that the target has just made; the target uses the lowered result to determine the outcome of its roll. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when an enemy makes an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- KOBOLD’S FURY --> 
	<element name="Kobold's Fury" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_KOBOLDS_FURY">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your touch infuses the rage of a threatened kobold into the target. The target has advantage on melee weapon attacks until the end of its next turn. In addition, its next successful melee weapon attack against a creature larger than itself does an additional 2d8 damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a kobold scale</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- LAIR SENSE  --> 
	<element name="Lair Sense" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LAIR_SENSE">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You set up a magical boundary around your lair. The boundary can’t exceed the dimensions of a 100-foot cube, but within that maximum, you can shape it as you like— to follow the walls of a building or cave, for example. While the spell lasts, you instantly become aware of any Tiny or larger creature that enters the enclosed area. You know the creature’s type but nothing else about it. You are also aware when creatures leave the area. </p>
			<p class="indent">This awareness is enough to wake you from sleep, and you receive the knowledge as long as you’re on the same plane of existence as your lair. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, add 50 feet to the maximum dimensions of the cube and add 12 hours to the spell’s duration for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hrs</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">treasure worth at least 500 gp, which is not consumed in casting</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LAST RAYS OF THE DYING SUN  -->
	<element name="Last Rays of the Dying Sun" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LAST_RAYS_OF_THE_DYING_SUN">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A burst of searing heat explodes from you, dealing 6d6 fire damage to all enemies within range. Immediately afterward, a wave of frigid cold rolls across the same area, dealing 6d6 cold damage to enemies. A creature that makes a successful Dexterity saving throw takes half the damage. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th or 9th level, the damage from both waves increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 7th. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">40 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LEGEND KILLER  -->
	<element name="Legend Killer" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LEGEND_KILLER">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You tap into the life force of a creature that is capable of performing legendary actions. When you cast the spell, the target must make a successful Constitution saving throw or lose the ability to take legendary actions for the spell’s duration. A creature can’t use legendary resistance to automatically succeed on the saving throw against this spell. An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, regaining 1 legendary action on a successful save. The target continues repeating the saving throw until the spell ends or it regains all its legendary actions.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a silver scroll describing the spell's target wroth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LIFE HACK --> 
	<element name="Life Hack" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LIFE_HACK">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose up to five creatures that you can see within range. Each of the creatures gains access to a pool of temporary hit points that it can draw upon over the spell’s duration or until the pool is used up. The pool contains 120 temporary hit points. The number of temporary hit points each individual creature can draw is determined by dividing 120 by the number of creatures with access to the pool. Hit points are drawn as a bonus action by the creature gaining the temporary hit points. Any number can be drawn at once, up to the maximum allowed. </p>
			<p class="indent">A creature can’t draw temporary hit points from the pool while it has temporary hit points from any source, including a previous casting of this spell. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a ruby worth 500 gp, which is consumed during the casting</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MASS SURGE DAMPENER  -->
	<element name="Mass Surge Dampener" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MASS_SURGE_DAMPENER">
		<supports>Bard,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Using your strength of will, you protect up to three creatures other than yourself from the effect of a chaos magic surge. A protected creature can make a DC 13 Charisma saving throw to negate the effect of a chaos magic surge that does not normally allow a saving throw, or it gains advantage on a saving throw that is normally allowed. Once a protected creature makes a successful saving throw allowed by mass surge dampener, the spell’s effect ends for that creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">Using your strength of will, you protect up to three creatures other than yourself from the effect of a chaos magic surge. A protected creature can make a DC 13 Charisma saving throw to negate the effect of a chaos magic surge that does not normally allow a saving throw, or it gains advantage on a saving throw that is normally allowed. Once a protected creature makes a successful saving throw allowed by mass surge dampener, the spell’s effect ends for that creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute, or until expended</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MEPHITIC CROAK --> 	
	<element name="Mephitic Croak" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MEPHITIC_CROAK">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You release an intensely loud burp of acidic gas in a 15-foot cone. Creatures in the area take 2d6 acid damage plus 2d6 thunder damage, or half as much damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature whose Dexterity saving throw fails must also make a successful Constitution saving throw or be stunned and poisoned until the start of your next turn. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, both acid and thunder damage increase by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (15-ft cone)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dead toad and a dram of arsenic worth 10 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MISFORTUNE --> 
	<element name="Misfortune" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MISFORTUNE">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cast a pall of bad luck over all creatures in a 15-foot radius centered on a point within range. Each creature in that area must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be cursed with bad luck for the duration of the spell. A creature under the effect of this spell has disadvantage on all ability checks, saving throws, and attack rolls. A remove curse spell ends this effect. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Special.</i></b> If a targeted creature is carrying a stone of good luck, the creature is unaffected by the spell, but the item ceases to function for 24 hours. Likewise, if a targeted creature is carrying a luck blade, the creature is unaffected by the spell, but the sword’s Luck ability and saving throw bonuses cease to function for 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a broken mirror</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- MIST OF WONDERS  -->
	<element name="Mist of Wonders" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MIST_OF_WONDERS">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A colorful mist surrounds you out to a radius of 30 feet. Creatures inside the mist see odd shapes in it and hear random sounds that don’t make sense. The very concepts of order and logic don’t seem to exist inside the mist. </p>
			<p class="indent">Any 1st-level spell that’s cast in the mist by another caster or that travels through the mist is affected by its strange nature. The caster must make a Constitution saving throw when casting the spell. On a failed save, the spell transforms into another 1st-level spell the caster knows (chosen by the GM from those available), even if that spell is not currently prepared. The altered spell’s slot level or its original target or targeted area can’t be changed. Cantrips are unaffected. If (in the GM’s judgment) none of the caster’s spells known of that level can be transformed, the spell being cast simply fails. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, it affects any spell cast using a spell slot of any lower level. For instance, using a 6th-level slot enables you to transform a spell of 5th level or lower into another spell of the same level. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30 ft. radius)</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MITHRAL DRAGON’S MIGHT  --> 
	<element name="Mithral Dragon's Might" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MITHRAL_DRAGONS_MIGHT">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You take on some of the physical characteristics and abilities of the mithral dragon, growing protective scales, wings, and claws. Until the spell ends, your AC can’t be lower than 16, regardless of what armor you are wearing. You can take two actions on your turn to attack with your claws, dealing 1d6 slashing damage on a hit. You have resistance to to acid and thunder damage. Up to three times while the spell is active, as an action, you can breathe a 20-foot cone of metal shards, dealing 6d8 slashing damage to all creatures in the cone. A creature that succeeds on a Dexterity saving throw takes half as much damage from your breath weapon. Finally, the wings grant you a flying speed of 40 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- ORB OF LIGHT  -->
	<element name="Orb of Light" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ORB_OF_LIGHT">
		<supports>Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An orb of light the size of your hand shoots from your fingertips toward a creature within range, which takes 3d8 radiant damage and is blinded for 1 round. A target that makes a successful Dexterity saving throw takes half the damage and is not blinded. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- OVERWHELMING GREED -->
	<element name="Overwhelming Greed" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_OVERWHELMING_GREED">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You fill the target with a dragon’s greed for wealth. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be overcome with greed, coveting any coins, jewelry, or art objects it can see that have a value of at least 1 gold piece, as well as jealously guarding any wealth it already owns. The target fixates on the most valuable-looking item or items, or the largest concentration of valuables in sight. It will not willingly let the wealth out of its sight. If the target sees an opportunity, it will take the valuables it has fixated on, gaining them by whatever means necessary. If doing so provokes a situation where it takes damage or is otherwise harmed, the affected creature can make another Wisdom saving throw to end the effect. If the creature fails the save, it will continue to try to acquire the wealth, fighting back if necessary. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ending the Effect.</i></b> If the affected creature ends its turn in an area where it cannot see any obviously valuable objects to covet, nor any creatures that might conceivably attempt to take its own property (a horse, for example, would not be considered such a creature), then it can make another Wisdom saving throw. A successful save ends the spell, and the creature recognizes its feelings of greed as magically induced. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can affect one additional creature for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gold piece</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- PARAGON OF CHAOS  -->
	<element name="Paragon of Chaos" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_PARAGON_OF_CHAOS">
		<supports>Bard,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You become a humanoid-shaped swirling mass of color and sound. You gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. You are also immune to the following conditions: exhaustion, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, and unconscious. Finally, you gain truesight to 30 feet and can teleport 30 feet as a move. </p>
			<p class="indent">Each round, as a bonus action, you can cause an automatic chaos magic surge, choosing either yourself or another creature you can see within 60 feet as the caster for the purpose of resolving the effect. You must choose the target before rolling percentile dice to determine the nature of the surge. The DC of any required saving throw is calculated as if you were the caster. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- PHANTOM DRAGON -->
	<element name="Phantom Dragon" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_PHANTOM_DRAGON">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You tap your dragon magic to make an ally appear as a draconic beast. The target of the spell appears to be a dragon of size Large or smaller. When seeing this illusion, observers make a Wisdom saving throw to see through it. </p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action to make the illusory dragon seem ferocious. Choose one creature within 30 feet of the illusory dragon to make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, the creature is frightened. The creature remains frightened until it uses an action to make a successful Wisdom saving throw or the spell’s duration expires. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, increase the number of targets the illusion can affect by one for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of dragon egg shell</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- PHANTOM LIGHT -->
	<element name="Phantom Light" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_PHANTOM_LIGHT">
		<supports>Druid,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch one object that measures less than 10 feet in every dimension. Until the spell ends, the object sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. The light can be colored as you like. At the time of the casting, you designate up to six creatures. Only those creatures are able to see and gain benefit from the phantom light. </p>
			<p class="indent">The object can be covered with something opaque to block the light. You can use an action to dismiss this spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small sketch of a candle</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- PROTECTIVE ICE  -->
	<element name="Protective Ice" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_PROTECTIVE_ICE">
		<supports>Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast protective ice, you encase a willing target in icy, medium armor equivalent to a breastplate (AC 14). A creature without the appropriate armor proficiency has the usual penalties. If the target is already wearing armor, it only uses the better of the two armor classes. </p>
			<p class="indent">A creature striking a target encased in protective ice with a melee attack while within 5 feet of it takes 1d6 cold damage. </p>
			<p class="indent">If the armor’s wearer takes fire damage, an equal amount of damage is done to the armor, which has 30 hit points and is damaged only when its wearer takes fire damage. Damaged ice can be repaired by casting a spell that deals cold damage on it, on a point-for-point basis, but the armor can’t have more than 30 points repaired. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a 4th-level spell slot, it creates splint armor (AC 17, 40 hit points). If you cast this spell using a 5th-level spell slot, it creates plate armor (AC 18, 50 hit points). The armor’s hit points increase by 10 for each spell slot above 5th, but the AC remains 18. Additionally, if you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the armor deals an extra +2 cold damage for each spell slot above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a seed encased in ice or glass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- PROTECTIVE NIMBUS --> 
	<element name="Protective Nimbus" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_PROTECTIVE_NIMBUS">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You wrap yourself in a corona that sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. Until the spell ends, you have resistance to necrotic damage. You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a crystal or glass bead</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- PUFF OF SMOKE -->
	<element name="Puff of Smoke" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_PUFF_OF_SMOKE">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By harnessing the elemental power of fire, you warp nearby air into obscuring smoke. One creature you can see within range must make a Dexterity saving throw. If it fails, the creature is blinded until the start of your next turn. Puff of smoke has no effect on creatures that have tremorsense or blindsight.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- QUICK TIME --> 	
	<element name="Quick Time" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_QUICK_TIME">
		<supports>Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You make one living creature or plant within range move rapidly in time compared to you. The target becomes one year older. For example, you could cast this spell on a seedling, which causes the plant to sprout from the soil, or you could cast this spell on a newly hatched duckling, causing it to become a full-grown duck. If the target is a creature with an Intelligence of 3 or higher, it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw to resist the aging. It can choose to fail the saving throw. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you increase the target’s age by one additional year for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">any seed</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- QUICKEN --> 	
	<element name="Quicken" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_QUICKEN_">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch one willing creature. Once before the duration of the spell expires, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to an initiative roll or Dexterity saving throw it has just made. The spell then ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- QUICKSILVER MANTLE -->	
	<element name="Quicksilver Mantle" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_QUICKSILVER_MANTLE">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You transform an ordinary cloak into a highly reflective, silvery garment. This mantle increases your AC by 2 and grants advantage on saving throws against gaze attacks. In addition, whenever you are struck by a ray such as a ray of enfeeblement, scorching ray, or even disintegrate, roll 1d4. On a result of 4, the cloak deflects the ray, which instead strikes a randomly selected target within 10 feet of you. The cloak deflects only the first ray that strikes it each round; rays after the first affect you as normal.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a nonmagical cloak and a dram of quicksilver worth 10 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- QUINTESSENCE -->	
	<element name="Quintessence" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_QUINTESSENCE">
		<supports>Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By calling upon an archangel, you become infused with celestial essence and take on angelic features such as golden skin, glowing eyes, and ethereal wings. For the duration of the spell, your Armor Class can’t be lower than 20, you can’t be frightened, and you are immune to necrotic damage. </p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, each hostile creature that starts its turn within 120 feet of you or enters that area for the first time on a turn must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. A creature frightened in this way is restrained. A frightened creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature’s saving throw is successful or if the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to the frightening effect of the spell until you cast quintessence again.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (120 ft. radius)</set>
			<set name="duration"> Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- RAID THE LAIR -->
	<element name="Raid the Lair" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_RAID_THE_LAIR">
		<supports>Bard,Ranger,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create an invisible circle of protective energy centered on yourself with a radius of 10 feet. This field moves with you. The caster and all allies within the energy field are protected against dragons’ lair actions. </p>
			<p class="indent">- Attack rolls resulting directly from lair actions are made with disadvantage. </p>
			<p class="indent">- Saving throws resulting directly from lair actions are made with advantage, and damage done by these lair actions is halved. </p>
			<p class="indent">- Lair actions occur on an initiative count 10 lower than normal. </p>
			<p class="indent">- The caster has advantage on Constitution saving throws to maintain concentration on this spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of the dragon whose lair you are raiding</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- RAVAGES OF TIME --> 
	<element name="Ravages of Time" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_RAVAGES_OF_TIME">
		<supports>Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You accelerate the aging of one creature within range, causing it to take on the state of a decrepit version of its type. The target suffers three levels of exhaustion that cannot be removed by normal means. A greater restoration spell partially reverses the effect of this spell, removing one level of exhaustion. Constructs and undead are unaffected by this spell, and creatures who live to great age without negative effects, such as dragons, are also unaffected.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a wilted flower</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- RAY OF ALCHEMICAL NEGATION -->	
	<element name="Ray of Alchemical Negation" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_RAY_OF_ALCHEMICAL_NEGATION">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You launch a ray of blazing, polychromatic energy from your fingertips. Make a ranged spell attack against an alchemical item or a trap that uses alchemy to achieve its ends, such as a trap that sprays acid, releases poisonous gas, or triggers an explosion of alchemist’s fire. A hit destroys the alchemical reagents, rendering them harmless. The attack is made against the most suitable object Armor Class. </p>
			<p class="indent">This spell can also be used against a creature within range that is wholly or partially composed of acidic, poisonous, or alchemical components, such as an alchemical golem or an ochre jelly. In that case, a hit deals 6d6 force damage, and the target must make a successful Constitution saving throw or it deals only half as much damage with its acidic, poisonous, or alchemical attacks for 1 minute. A creature whose damage is halved can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- RESET --> 
	<element name="Reset" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_RESET">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Paladin,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose up to four creatures within range. If a target is your ally, it can reroll initiative, keeping whichever of the two results it prefers. If a target is your enemy, it must make a successful Wisdom saving throw or reroll initiative, keeping whichever of the two results you prefer. Changes to the initiative order go into effect at the start of the next round. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can affect one additional creature for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal, clockwork">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- RIGHT THE STARS  -->
	<element name="Right the Stars" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_RIGHT_THE_STARS">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You subtly warp the flow of space and time to enhance your conjurations with cosmic potency. Until the spell ends, the maximum duration of any conjuration spell you cast that requires concentration is doubled, any creature that you summon or create with a conjuration spell has 30 temporary hit points, and you have advantage on Charisma checks and Charisma saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,ritual</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">seven black candles and a circle of powdered charred bone or basalt</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- ROAMING PAIN  -->
	<element name="Roaming Pain" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ROAMING_PAIN">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You afflict a single humanoid within range with severe pain in a random part of its body. Roll a d6 and consult the table to determine the spell’s initial effect. </p>
			<p class="indent">The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a successful save, it is able to function despite the pain and ignore the effects. At the start of the target’s turn each round for the duration of the spell, roll again on the table to see where the pain affects the target in that round.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>Body Part</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Head</td><td>Incapacitated </td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Throat</td><td>Unable to speak coherently or cast spells with verbal components</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Chest</td><td>Cannot take reactions or bonus actions</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Abdomen</td><td>Disadvantage on Constitution saving throws</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Arm</td><td>Disadvantage on attack rolls, Strength and Dexterity skill checks</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Leg</td><td>Movement halved</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- ROARING WINDS OF LIMBO  -->
	<element name="Roaring Winds of Limbo" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_ROARING_WINDS_OF_LIMBO">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You tear open a breach to the planes of chaos, and the act of doing so fills an area with a dangerous windstorm. The area consists of twelve 10-foot cubes, which you can arrange as you wish. Each cube must have at least one face in common with a face of another cube. Each creature in the area is deafened, and any sound it makes cannot be heard outside the area. The wind disperses all gases and vapors and extinguishes all unprotected flames in the area, and has a 75 percent chance of extinguishing protected flames, such as lanterns. All Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight made by a creature in the area have disadvantage due to the dust, grit, and debris being cast about. </p>
			<p class="indent">Each creature in the area must make a Strength saving throw at the start of its turn. On a failed save, the creature is pushed 15 feet in a random direction. (Roll a d8, designating 1 as north, 2 as northeast, 3 as east, and so on around the points of the compass.) The wind also hampers movement; a creature in the area must spend 2 feet of movement for every 1 foot it moves. </p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action on each of your turns, you can bombard up to twelve creatures in the area with flying debris, dealing 2d10 bludgeoning, 2d10 piercing, and 2d10 slashing damage. A creature that makes a successful Dexterity saving throw takes half the damage. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">150 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- SALT LASH  -->	
	<element name="Salt Lash" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SALT_LASH">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a long, thin blade of razor-sharp salt crystals. You can wield it as a longsword, using your spellcasting ability to modify your weapon attack rolls. The sword deals 2d8 slashing damage on a hit, and any creature struck by the blade must make a successful Constitution saving throw or be stunned by searing pain until the start of your next turn. Constructs and undead are immune to the blade’s secondary (stun) effect; plants and creatures composed mostly of water, such as water elementals, also take an additional 2d8 necrotic damage if they fail the saving throw. </p>
			<p class="indent">The spell lasts until you stop concentrating on it, the duration expires, or you let go of the blade for any reason.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pinch of salt worth 1 sp, which is consumed during the casting</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- SCALE ROT --> 
	<element name="Scale Rot" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SCALE_ROT">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon death and decay to plague your enemies. For dragons, this act often takes the form of attacking a foe’s armor and scales, as a way of weakening an enemy dragon and leaving it plagued by self-doubt and fear. (This enchantment is useful against any armored creature, not just dragons.) </p>
			<p class="indent">One creature of your choice within range that has natural armor must make a Constitution saving throw. If it fails, attacks against that creature’s Armor Class are made with advantage, and the creature can’t regain hit points through any means while the spell remains in effect. An affected creature can end the spell by making a successful Constitution saving throw, which also makes the creature immune to further castings of scale rot for 24 hours. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the number of affected targets increases by one for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of rotten meat</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>


<!-- SCALY HIDE -->
	<element name="Scaly Hide" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SCALY_HIDE">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A creature you touch grows a protective layer of scales that resembles that of a dragon. Until the spell ends, the target’s AC can’t be lower than 16, regardless of the type of armor it is wearing. Additionally, the target gains resistance to either acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison damage for the duration of the spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dragon scale of the appropriate color</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- SCRY AMBUSH  -->
	<element name="Scry Ambush" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SCRY_AMBUSH">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You foresee your foe’s strike a split second before it occurs. When you cast this spell successfully, you also designate a number of your allies that can see or hear you equal to your spellcasting ability modifier + your proficiency bonus. Those allies are also not surprised by the attack and can act normally in the first round of combat. </p>
			<p class="indent">If you would be surprised, you must make a check using your spellcasting ability at the moment your reaction would be triggered. The check DC is equal to the current initiative count. On a failed check, you are surprised and can’t use your reaction to cast this spell until after your next turn. On a successful check, you can use your reaction to cast this spell immediately.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when an enemy tries to make a surprise attack against you</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- SCULPT SNOW  -->
	<element name="Sculpt Snow" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SCULPT_SNOW">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast sculpt snow in an area filled with snow, you can create one Large object, two Medium objects, or four smaller objects from snow. With a casting time of 1 action, your sculptings bear only a crude resemblance to generic creatures or objects. If you increase the casting time to 1 minute, your creations take on a more realistic appearance and can even vaguely resemble specific creatures; the resemblance isn’t strong enough to fool anyone, but the creature can be recognized. The sculptures are as durable as a typical snowman. </p>
			<p class="indent">Sculptures created by this spell can be animated with animate objects or comparable magic. Animated sculptures gain the AC, hit points, and other attributes provided by that spell. When they attack, they deal normal damage plus a similar amount of cold damage; an animated Medium sculpture, for example, deals 2d6 + 1 bludgeoning damage plus 2d6 + 1 cold damage. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can sculpt one additional Large object for each slot level above 2nd. Two Large objects can be replaced with one Huge object.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- SEAL OF SANCTUARY --> 
	<element name="Seal of Sanctuary" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SEAL_OF_SANCTUARY">
		<supports>Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You inscribe an angelic seal on the ground, the floor, or other solid surface of a structure. The seal creates a spherical sanctuary with a radius of 50 feet, centered on the seal. For the duration, aberrations, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead that approach to within 5 feet of the boundary know they are about to come into contact with a deadly barrier. If such a creature moves so as to touch the boundary, or tries to cross the boundary by any means, including teleportation and extradimensional travel, it must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 10d8 radiant damage, is repelled to 5 feet outside the boundary, and can’t target anything inside the boundary with attacks, spells, or abilities until the spell ends. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much radiant damage and can cross the boundary. If the creature is a fiend that isn’t on its home plane, it is immediately destroyed (no saving throw) instead of taking damage. </p>
			<p class="indent">Aberrations, elementals, fey, and undead that are within 50 feet of the seal (inside the boundary) have disadvantage on ability checks, attack rolls, and saving throws, and each such creature takes 2d8 radiant damage at the start of its turn. </p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures other than aberrations, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead can’t be charmed or frightened while within 50 feet of the seal. </p>
			<p class="indent">The seal has AC 18, 50 hit points, resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, and immunity to psychic and poison damage. Ranged attacks against the seal are made with disadvantage. If it is scribed on the surface of an object that is later destroyed (such as a wooden door), the seal is not damaged and remains in place, perhaps suspended in midair. The spell ends only if the seal is reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic,ritual</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hrs</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">incense and special inks worth 250 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- SEARING SUN  -->
	<element name="Searing Sun" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SEARING_SUN">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell intensifies the light and heat of the sun, so that it burns exposed flesh. You must be able to see the sun when you cast the spell. The searing sunlight affects a cylindrical area 50 feet in radius and 200 feet high, centered on the a point within range. Each creature that starts its turn in that area takes 5d8 fire damage, or half the damage with a successful Constitution saving throw. A creature that’s shaded by a solid object —such as an awning, a building, or an overhanging boulder— has advantage on the saving throw. On your turn, you can use an action to move the center of the cylinder up to 20 feet along the ground in any direction.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">200 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a magnifying lens</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- SEER’S REACTION  -->
	<element name="Seer's Reaction" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SEERS_REACTION">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Ranger,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your foreknowledge allows you to act before others, because you knew what was going to happen. When you cast this spell, make a new initiative roll with a +5 bonus. If the result is higher than your current initiative, your place in the initiative order changes accordingly. If the result is also higher than the current place in the initiative order, you take your next turn immediately and then use the higher number starting in the next round.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your foreknowledge allows you to act before others, because you knew what was going to happen. When you cast this spell, make a new initiative roll with a +5 bonus. If the result is higher than your current initiative, your place in the initiative order changes accordingly. If the result is also higher than the current place in the initiative order, you take your next turn immediately and then use the higher number starting in the next round.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take at the start of another creature's turn</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- SHADE -->
	<element name="Shade" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SHADE">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a magical screen across your eyes. While the screen remains, you are immune to blindness caused by visible effects, such as color spray. The spell doesn’t alleviate blindness that’s already been inflicted on you. If you normally suffer penalties on attacks or ability checks while in sunlight, those penalties don’t apply while you’re under the effect of this spell. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the duration of the spell increases by 10 minutes for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- SHEEN OF ICE  -->
	<element name="Sheen of Ice" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SHEEN_OF_ICE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A small icy globe shoots from your finger to a point within range and then explodes in a spray of ice. Each creature within 20 feet of that point must make a successful Dexterity saving throw or become coated in ice for 1 minute. Ice-coated creatures move at half speed. An invisible creature becomes outlined by the ice so that it loses the benefits of invisibility while the ice remains. The spell ends for a specific creature if that creature takes 5 or more fire damage. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a water within a glass globe</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- SHIELD OF STARLIGHT -->
	<element name="Shield of Starlight" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_STARLIGHT">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You wrap yourself in a protective shroud of the night sky made from swirling shadows and punctuated by twinkling motes of light. The shroud grants you resistance against either radiant or necrotic damage (your choice when the spell is cast). You also shed dim light in a 10-foot radius. You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a star chart</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- SHIFTING THE ODDS  -->		
	<element name="Shifting the Odds" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SHIFTING_THE_ODDS">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By wrapping yourself in strands of chaotic energy, you gain advantage on the next attack roll or ability check that you make. Fate is a cruel mistress, however, and her scales must always be balanced. The second attack roll or ability check (whichever occurs first) that you make after casting shifting the odds is made with disadvantage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- SHIVER --> 
	<element name="Shiver" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SHIVER">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You fill a humanoid creature with such cold that its teeth begin to chatter and its body shakes uncontrollably. Roll 5d8; the total is the maximum hit points of a creature this spell can affect. The affected creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw, or it cannot cast a spell or load a missile weapon until the end of your next turn. Once a creature has been affected by this spell, it is immune to further castings of this spell for 24 hours. </p>
			<p class="indent"><i><b>At Higher Levels</b></i> The maximum hit points you can affect increases by 4d8 when you reach 5th level (9d8), 11th level (13d8), and 17th level (17d8).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a humanoid tooth</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- SNOW BOULDER  -->
	<element name="Snow Boulder" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SNOW_BOULDER">
		<supports>Druid,Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A ball of snow forms 5 feet away from you and rolls in the direction you point at a speed of 30 feet, growing larger as it moves. To roll the boulder into a creature, you must make a successful ranged spell attack. If the boulder hits, the creature must make a successful Dexterity saving throw or be knocked prone and take the damage indicated below. Hitting a creature doesn’t stop the snow boulder’s movement or impede its growth, as long as you continue to maintain concentration on the effect. When the spell ends, the boulder stops moving.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Round</td><td>Size</td><td>Damage</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Small</td><td>1d6 bludgeoning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Medium</td><td>2d6 bludgeoning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Large</td><td>4d6 bludgeoning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Huge</td><td>6d6 bludgeoning</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">90 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 4 rounds</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a handful of snow</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- SNOW FORT  -->
	<element name="Snow Fort" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SNOW_FORT">
		<supports>Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell creates a simple “fort” from packed snow. The snow fort springs from the ground in an unoccupied space within range. It encircles a 10-foot area with sloping walls 4 feet high. The fort provides half cover (+2 AC) against ranged and melee attacks coming from outside the fort. The walls have AC 12, 30 hit points per side, are immune to cold, necrotic, poison, and psychic damage, and are vulnerable to fire damage. A damaged wall can be repaired by casting a spell that deals cold damage on it, on a point-for-point basis, up to a maximum of 30 points. </p>
			<p class="indent">The spell also creates a dozen snowballs that can be thrown (range 20/60) and that deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage plus 1d4 cold damage on a hit.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a ring carved from chalk or white stone</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- SNOWY COAT  -->
	<element name="Snowy Coat" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SNOWY_COAT">
		<supports>Druid,Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell makes a slight alteration to a target creature’s appearance that gives it advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks to hide in snowy terrain. In addition, the target can use a bonus action to make itself invisible in snowy terrain for 1 minute. The spell ends at the end of the minute or when the creature attacks or casts a spell. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- SOOTHING INCANDESCENCE -->
	<element name="Soothing Incandescence" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SOOTHING_INCANDESCENCE">
		<supports>Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A soft, white radiance spreads out from a point just above your head, creating bright light in a 30-foot radius around your present location. If you move from your present location, the area of light remains fixed. A creature in the area other than a fiend or an undead regains 1 hit point at the start of each of its turns while within the bright light. Each fiend or undead in the area takes 2d4 radiant damage at the start of each of its turns.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30 ft. radius)</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- STARBURST  -->
	<element name="Starburst" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_STARBURST">
		<supports>Druid,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cause a mote of starlight to appear and explode in a 5-foot cube you can see within range. If a creature is in the cube, it must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or take 1d8 radiant damage. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> This spell’s damage increases to 2d8 when you reach 5th level, 3d8 when you reach 11th level, and 4d8 when you reach 17th level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- STARFALL  -->
	<element name="Starfall" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_STARFALL">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cause bolts of shimmering starlight to fall from the heavens, striking up to five creatures that you can see within range. Each bolt strikes one target, dealing 6d6 radiant damage, knocking the target prone, and blinding it until the start of your next turn. A creature that makes a successful Dexterity saving throw takes half the damage, is not knocked prone, and is not blinded. If you name fewer than five targets, excess bolts strike the ground harmlessly.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can create one additional bolt for each slot level above 5th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- STAR’S HEART --> 
	<element name="Star's Heart" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_STARS_HEART">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell increases gravity tenfold in a 50-foot radius centered on you. Each creature in the area other than you drops whatever it’s holding, falls prone, becomes incapacitated, and can’t move. If a solid object (such as the ground) is encountered when a flying or levitating creature falls, the creature takes three times the normal falling damage. Any creature except you that enters the area or starts its turn there must make a successful Strength saving throw or fall prone and become incapacitated and unable to move. A creature that starts its turn prone and incapacitated makes a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 8d6 bludgeoning damage; on a successful save, it takes 4d6 bludgeoning damage, it’s no longer incapacitated, and it can move at half speed. </p>
			<p class="indent">All ranged weapon attacks inside the area have a normal range of 5 feet and a maximum range of 10 feet. The same applies to spells that create missiles that have mass, such as flaming sphere. A creature under the influence of a freedom of movement spell or comparable magic has advantage on the Strength saving throws required by this spell, and its speed isn’t reduced once it recovers from being incapacitated. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">50 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an ioun stone</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- STEAL WARMTH  -->
	<element name="Steal Warmth" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_STEAL_WARMTH">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast steal warmth after taking cold damage, you select a living creature within 5 feet of you. That creature takes the cold damage instead, or half the damage with a successful Constitution saving throw. You regain hit points equal to the amount of cold damage taken by the target. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the distance to the target you can affect with this spell increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you take cold damage from magic</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- SUMMON STAR  -->
	<element name="Summon Star" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SUMMON_STAR">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon a friendly star from the heavens to do your bidding. It appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range and takes the form of a glowing humanoid with long white hair. All creatures other than you who view the star must make a successful Wisdom saving throw or be charmed for the duration of the spell. A creature charmed in this way can repeat the Wisdom saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, the creature is no longer charmed and is immune to the effect of this casting of the spell. In all other ways, the star is equivalent to a deva. It understands and obeys verbal commands you give it. If you do not give the star a command, it defends itself and attacks the last creature that attacked it. The star disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">90 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- SURGE DAMPENER  -->
	<element name="Surge Dampener" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_SURGE_DAMPENER">
		<supports>Bard,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Using your strength of will, you cause one creature other than yourself that you touch to become so firmly entrenched within reality that it is protected from the effects of a chaos magic surge. The protected creature can make a DC 13 Charisma saving throw to negate the effect of a chaos magic surge that does not normally allow a saving throw, or it gains advantage on a saving throw that is normally allowed. Once the protected creature makes a successful saving throw allowed by surge dampener, the spell ends. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute, until expended</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- THUNDER BOLT  -->
	<element name="Thunder Bolt" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_THUNDER_BOLT">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cast a knot of thunder at one enemy. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. If it hits, the target takes 1d8 thunder damage and can’t use reactions until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- THUNDERSTORM -->
	<element name="Thunderstorm" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_THUNDERSTORM">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch a willing creature, and it becomes surrounded by a roiling storm cloud 30 feet in diameter, erupting with (harmless) thunder and lightning. The creature gains a flying speed of 60 feet. The cloud heavily obscures the creature inside it from view, though it is transparent to the creature itself.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of lightning-fused glass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TIME IN A BOTTLE  -->
	<element name="Time in a Bottle" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_IN_A_BOTTLE">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You designate a spot within your sight. Time comes under your control in a 20-foot radius centered on that spot. You can freeze it, reverse it, or move it forward by as much as 1 minute as long as you maintain concentration. Nothing and no one, yourself included, can enter the field or affect what happens inside it. You can choose to end the effect at any moment as an action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal, clockwork">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Sight</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME JAUNT  -->		
	<element name="Time Jaunt" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_JAUNT">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell, you step outside the normal time stream, seeming to vanish as 1 round of time passes. You can make minor alterations to the scene being played out, becoming visible for an instant each time you make an adjustment that aids an ally or hinders foes. To everyone else, you disappear when the spell is cast, then flicker into and out of view during the next round, before reappearing for good in the space you vanished from 1 round later, whereupon the spell ends. You cannot be attacked by any means while under the effect of this spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">As the round progresses, you can choose to bestow a single effect on each creature involved in the combat, choosing from the list below. You cannot take any other actions during the round. </p>
			<p class="indent">-Give a creature advantage or disadvantage on a saving throw it is about to make. </p>
			<p class="indent">-Give a creature advantage or disadvantage on an attack roll it is about to make. </p>
			<p class="indent">-Alter the location of a mobile object to provide or remove cover for a creature. </p>
			<p class="indent">-Shift objects into the path of a creature; the first 10 feet of terrain it must travel becomes difficult terrain. </p>
			<p class="indent">-After an attack roll is determined to be successful, adjust the angle of the strike or the positioning of the target, either causing the strike to deal half as much damage or providing a bonus to damage equal to half your level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Special</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME JUMP  -->
	<element name="Time Jump" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_JUMP">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch a construct and throw it forward in time if it fails a Constitution saving throw. The construct disappears for 1d4 + 1 rounds, during which time it cannot act or be acted upon in any way. When the construct returns, it is unaware that any time has passed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal, clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal, clockwork">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME LOOP  -->
	<element name="Time Loop" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_LOOP">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You capture a creature within range in a loop of time. The target is teleported to the space where it began its most recent turn. The target then makes a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the spell ends. On a failed save, the creature must repeat the activities it undertook on its previous turn, following the sequence of moves and actions to the best of its ability. It doesn’t need to move along the same path or attack the same target, but if it moved and then attacked on its previous turn, its only option is to move and then attack on this turn. If the space where the target began its previous turn is occupied or if it’s impossible for the target to take the same action (if it cast a spell but is now unable to do so, for example), the target becomes incapacitated. </p>
			<p class="indent">An affected target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. For as long as the spell lasts, the target teleports back to its starting point at the start of each of its turns, and it must repeat the same sequence of moves and actions.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a metal loop</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TIME SLIPPAGE --> 
	<element name="Time Slippage" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_SLIPPAGE">
		<supports>Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You ensnare a creature within range in an insidious trap, causing different parts of its body to function at different speeds. The creature must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, it is stunned until the end of its next turn. On a success, the creature’s speed is halved and it has disadvantage on attack rolls and saving throws until the end of its next turn. The creature repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, with the same effects for success and failure. In addition, the creature has disadvantage on Strength or Dexterity saving throws but advantage on Constitution or Charisma saving throws for the spell’s duration (a side effect of the chronal anomaly suffusing its body). The spell ends if the creature makes three successful saves in a row.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal, clockwork">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">the heart of a chaotic creature CR5 or higher, worth 500 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME STEP  -->
	<element name="Time Step" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_STEP">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Ranger,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You briefly step forward in time. You disappear from your location and reappear at the start of your next turn in a location of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of the space you disappeared from. You can’t be affected by anything that happens during the time you’re missing, and you aren’t aware of anything that happens during that time.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME VORTEX  -->
	<element name="Time Vortex" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_VORTEX">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell destabilizes the flow of time, enabling you to create a vortex of temporal fluctuations that are visible as a spherical distortion with a 10-foot radius, centered on a point within range. Each creature in the area when you cast the spell must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be affected by the time vortex. While the spell lasts, a creature that enters the sphere or starts its turn inside the sphere must also succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be affected. On a succesful save, it becomes immune to this casting of the spell. </p>
			<p class="indent">An affected creature can’t take reactions and rolls a d10 at the start of its turn to determine its behavior for that turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can move the temporal vortex 10 feet each round as a bonus action. An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the radius of the sphere increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 4th.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1-2</td><td>The creature is affected as if by a slow spell until the start of its next turn. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>3-5</td><td>The creature is stunned until the start of its next turn. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>6-8</td><td>The creature’s current initiative result is reduced by 5. The creature begins using this new initiative result in the next round. Multiple occurrences of this effect for the same creature are cumulative. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>9-10</td><td>The creature’s speed is halved (round up to the nearest 5-foot increment) until the start of its next turn. </td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">90 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TIMELY DISTRACTION  -->
	<element name="Timely Distraction" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIMELY_DISTRACTION">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You call forth a swirling, crackling wave of constantly shifting pops, flashes, and swept-up debris. This chaos can confound one creature. If the target gets a failure on a Wisdom saving throw, roll a d4 and consult the following table to determine the result. An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Otherwise, the spell ends when its duration expires.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d4</td><td>Mutation</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Blinded</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Stunned</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Deafened</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Prone</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">25 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">3 rounds</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a handful of sand or dirt thrown in the air</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 	

<!-- TORRENT OF FIRE -->
	<element name="Torrent of Fire" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TORRENT_OF_FIRE">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You harness the power of fire contained in ley lines with this spell. You create a 60-foot cone of flame. Creatures in the cone take 6d6 fire damage, or half as much damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. You can then flow along the flames, reappearing anywhere inside the cone’s area. This repositioning doesn’t count as movement and doesn’t trigger opportunity attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">Self (60 ft. cone)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of obsidian</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TRACKING BEACON -->
	<element name="Tracking Beacon" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TRACKING_BEACON">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You choose a creature within range to mark with a glowing orb of light, which floats 120 feet above the creature’s head. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the spell ends. On a failed save, the light hovers above the target’s location, moving as the target moves, which enables you to track the creature’s direction and distance by staying within sight of the beacon. The beacon continues to function even when you cannot see it, as long as the target remains on the same plane as you. If either you or the target travels to another plane, the spell ends. </p>
			<p class="indent">You can use a bonus action on your turn to adjust the height of the beacon, ranging from its starting point of 120 feet to as low as 5 feet above the head of the target.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 8 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TREASURE CHASM -->
	<element name="Treasure Chasm" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TREASURE_CHASM">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cause the glint of a golden coin to haze over the vision of one creature in range. The target creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, it sees a gorge, trench, or other hole in the ground, at a spot within range chosen by you, which is filled with gold and treasure. On its next turn, the creature must move toward that spot. When it reaches the spot, it becomes incapacitated, as it devotes all its attention to scooping imaginary treasure into its pockets or a pouch. </p>
			<p class="indent">An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. The effect also ends if the creature takes damage from you or one of your allies. </p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures with the dragon type have disadvantage on the initial saving throw but have advantage on saving throws against this spell made after reaching the designated spot.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gold coin</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TRIUMPH OF ICE --> 
	<element name="Triumph of Ice" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TRIUMP_OF_ICE">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You transform one of the four elements—air, earth, fire, or water—into ice or snow. The affected area is a sphere with a radius of 100 feet, centered on you. The specific effect depends on the element you choose. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Air.</i></b> Vapor condenses into snowfall. If the effect of a fog cloud spell, a stinking cloud, or similar magic is in the area, this spell negates it. A creature of elemental air within range takes 8d6 cold damage—and, if airborne, it must make a successful Constitution saving throw at the start of its turn to avoid being knocked prone (no falling damage). </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Earth.</i></b> Soil freezes into permafrost to a depth of 10 feet. A creature burrowing through the area has its speed halved until the area thaws, unless it can burrow through solid rock. A creature of elemental earth within range must make a successful Constitution saving throw or take 8d6 cold damage. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fire.</i></b> Flames or other sources of extreme heat (such as molten lava) on the ground within range transform into shards of ice, and the area they occupy becomes difficult terrain. Each creature in the previously burning area takes 2d6 slashing damage when the spell is cast and 1d6 slashing damage for every 5 feet it moves in the area (unless it is not hindered by icy terrain) until the spell ends; a successful Dexterity saving throw reduces the slashing damage by half. A creature of elemental fire within range must make a successful Constitution saving throw or take 8d6 cold damage and be stunned for 1d6 rounds. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Water.</i></b> Open water (a pond, lake, or river) freezes to a depth of 4 feet. A creature on the surface of the water when it freezes must make a successful Dexterity saving throw to avoid being trapped in the ice. A trapped creature can free itself by using an action to make a successful Strength (Athletics) check. A creature of elemental water within range takes no damage from the spell but is paralyzed for 1d6 rounds unless it makes a successful Constitution saving throw, and it treats the affected area as difficult terrain. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a stone extracted from glacial ice</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- UNCONTROLLABLE TRANSFORMATION  -->
	<element name="Uncontrollable Transformation" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_UNCONTROLLABLE_TRANSFORMATION">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You infuse your body with raw chaos and will it to adopt a helpful mutation. Roll a d10 and consult the Uncontrollable Transformation table below to determine what mutation occurs. You can try to control the shifting of your body to gain a mutation you prefer, but doing so is taxing; you can roll a d10 twice and choose the result you prefer, but you gain one level of exhaustion. At the end of the spell, your body returns to its normal form. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th level or higher, you gain an additional mutation for each slot level above 7th. You gain one level of exhaustion for each mutation you try to control.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Mutation</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>A spindly third arm sprouts from your shoulder. As a bonus action, you can use it to attack with a light weapon. You have advantage on Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) checks and any checks that require the manipulation of tools. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Your skin is covered by rough scales that increase your AC by 1 and give you resistance to a random damage type (roll on the Damage Type table in the frenzied bolt spell description). </td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>A puckered orifice grows on your back. You can forcefully expel air from it, granting you a flying speed of 30 feet. You must land at the end of your turn. In addition, as a bonus action, you can try to push a creature away with a blast of air. The target is pushed 5 feet away from you if it fails a Strength saving throw with a DC equal to 10 + your Constitution modifier. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>A second face appears on the back of your head. You gain darkvision out to a range of 120 feet and advantage on sight based and scent-based Wisdom (Perception) checks. You become adept at carrying on conversations with yourself. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>You grow gills that not only allow you to breathe underwater but also filter poison out of the air. You gain immunity to inhaled poisons. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Your hindquarters elongate, and you grow a second set of legs. Your base walking speed increases by 10 feet, and your carrying capacity becomes your Strength score multiplied by 20. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>You become incorporeal and can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. You take 1d10 force damage if you end your turn inside an object. You can’t pick up or interact with physical objects that you weren’t carrying when you became incorporeal. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>Your limbs elongate and flatten into prehensile paddles. You gain a swimming speed equal to your base walking speed and have advantage on Strength (Athletics) checks made to climb or swim. In addition, your unarmed strikes deal 1d6 bludgeoning damage. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>Your head fills with a light gas and swells to four times its normal size, causing your hair to fall out. You have advantage on Intelligence and Wisdom ability checks and can levitate up to 5 feet above the ground. </td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>You grow three sets of feathered wings that give you a flying speed equal to your walking speed and the ability to hover. </td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">the bill of platypus</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- UNDERMINE ARMOR  --> 
	<element name="Undermine Armor" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_UNDERMINE_ARMOR">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You unravel the bonds of reality that hold a suit of armor together. A target wearing armor must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or its armor softens to the consistency of candle wax, decreasing the target’s AC by 2. </p>
			<p class="indent">Undermine armor has no effect on creatures that aren’t wearing armor. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- UNRULY ITEM  --> 
	<element name="Unruly Item" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_UNRULY_ITEM">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You animate an object in the possession of a creature within range, giving the object limited movement and a compulsion to thwart its possessor. The effect of the spell varies depending on the kind of object you affect. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Weapon:</i></b> A weapon being wielded by a creature fights and twists, trying to free itself from the creature’s grasp. The creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature has disadvantage on any attacks it makes in that round with the weapon. On a save that fails by 5 or more, the creature drops the weapon. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Armor:</i></b> The creature’s armor shifts and moves, becoming noisy and uncomfortable. If the armor does not normally impart disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks, it does so while this spell is in effect. The creature wearing it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take a 10-foot penalty to its speed and be unable to use the Dash action. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Other Items:</i></b> The effects on other carried items can vary at the GM’s discretion. A potion might behave as a weapon, trying not to be drunk, falling to the ground and becoming ruined if the Dexterity save is failed by 5 or more. A backpack might try to empty itself, disgorging a random item each round on a failed save.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- UNSHACKLED MAGIC  -->
	<element name="Unshackled Magic" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_UNSHACKLED_MAGIC">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You designate a creature within range that has the Spellcasting or Innate Spellcasting special trait and imbue it with wild magic, causing it to lose control of its magical ability. If the target gets a failure on a Charisma saving throw, then on its next turn, it rolls randomly to select one of its available spells. The target then spontaneously casts that spell as an action. If the spell can be cast using a spell slot higher than its level, roll randomly to determine what slot is used to cast the spell. The target still determines factors such as the location of the spell’s area or which creatures it affects, as normal, but it is compelled to cast that particular spell at that particular time. </p>
			<p class="indent">Each round while this spell remains in effect, the target makes another Charisma saving throw. On a successful save, it can act normally in that round, but the unshackled magic spell does not end.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- WAFT  -->
	<element name="Waft" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_WAFT">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell was first invented by dragon parents to assist their offspring when learning to fly. You gain a flying speed of 60 feet for 1 round. At the start of your next turn, you float rapidly down and land gently on a solid surface beneath you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a topaz worth at least 10 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- WALL OF TIME  -->
	<element name="Wall of Time" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_WALL_OF_TIME">
		<supports>Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a wall of shimmering, transparent blocks on a solid surface within range. You can make a straight wall up to 60 feet long, 20 feet high, and 1 foot thick, or a cylindrical wall up to 20 feet high, 1 foot thick, and 20 feet in diameter. Nonmagical ranged attacks that cross the wall vanish into the time stream with no other effect. Ranged spell attacks and ranged weapon attacks made with magic weapons that pass through the wall are made with disadvantage. A creature that intentionally enters or passes through the wall is affected as if it had just failed its initial saving throw against a slow spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal, clockwork">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range"> 120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an hourglass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- WILD SHIELD  --> 
	<element name="Wild Shield" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_WILD_SHIELD">
		<supports>Bard,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You surround yourself with the forces of chaos. Wild lights and strange sounds engulf you, making stealth impossible. While wild shield is active, you can use a reaction to repel a spell of 4th level or lower that targets you or whose area you are within. A repelled spell has no effect on you, but doing this causes the chance of a chaos magic surge as if you had cast a spell, with you considered the caster for any effect of the surge. </p>
			<p class="indent">Wild shield ends when the duration expires or when it absorbs 4 levels of spells. If you try to repel a spell whose level exceeds the number of levels remaining, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level – the number of levels wild shield can still repel. If the check succeeds, the spell is repelled; if the check fails, the spell has its full effect. The chance of a chaos magic surge exists regardless of whether the spell is repelled. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can repel one additional spell level for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- WILD TRAJECTORY  -->
	<element name="Wild Trajectory" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_WILD_TRAJECTORY">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a 30-foot cube of magical instability that causes spell effects passing through it to diverge wildly from their original paths. When a spell with a visible or tangible manifestation (such as fireball, lightning bolt, or a ray or projectile such as magic missile or ray of frost) passes through the area, roll a d8. On a 1, the spell continues on its original path or toward its original target; on a 2, it diverts 45 degrees to the right; on a 3, it diverts 90 degrees to the right; on a 4, it diverts 135 degrees to the right; on a 5, it turns 180 degrees, back the way it came (striking the caster if it is a targeted spell); on a 6, the spell diverts 45 degrees to the left; on a 7, it diverts 90 degrees to the left; on an 8, it diverts 135 degrees to the left. </p>
			<p class="indent">A spell that affects anything in its path, such as lightning bolt, continues to do so along its new trajectory, up to the limit of its range. A fireball spell will travel in the new direction up to the limit of its range before detonating. A targeted spell will strike the first viable target it encounters along its new trajectory.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- WINTERDARK  -->
	<element name="Winterdark" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_WINDERDARK">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell invokes the deepest part of night on the winter solstice. You target a 40-foot-radius, 60-foot-high cylinder centered on a point within range, which is plunged into darkness and unbearable cold. Each creature in the area when you cast the spell and at the start of its turn must make a successful Constitution saving throw or take 1d6 cold damage and gain one level of exhaustion. Creatures immune to cold damage are also immune to the exhaustion effect, as are creatures wearing cold weather gear or otherwise adapted for a cold environment. </p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can move the center of the effect 20 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- WINTER’S RADIANCE  -->
	<element name="Winter's Radiance" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_WINTERS_RADIANCE">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell, the piercing rays of a day’s worth of sunlight reflecting off fresh snow blankets the area. A creature caught in the spell’s area must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or have disadvantage on ranged attacks and Wisdom (Perception) checks for the duration of the spell. In addition, an affected creature’s vision is hampered such that foes it targets are treated as having three-quarters cover.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">400 ft. (30 ft cube)</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of polished glass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- WINTRY GLIDE -->
	<element name="Wintery Glide" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_WINTERY_GLIDE">
		<supports>Druid,Ranger,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Upon casting wintry glide, you can travel via ice or snow without crossing the intervening space. If you are adjacent to a mass of ice or snow, you can enter it by expending 5 feet of movement. By expending another 5 feet of movement, you can immediately exit from that mass at any point—within 500 feet—that’s part of the contiguous mass of ice or snow. When you enter the ice or snow, you instantly know the extent of the material within 500 feet. You must have at least 10 feet of movement available when you cast the spell, or it fails. </p>
			<p class="indent">If the mass of ice or snow is destroyed while you are transiting it, you must make a successful Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC to avoid taking 4d6 bludgeoning damage and falling prone at the midpoint of a line between your entrance point and your intended exit point.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>  

</elements>
