<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name></name>
		<update version="0.0.5">
			<file name="items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Kobold%20Press/Vault%20of%20Magic/items-weapons.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
<!-- Appending IDs for weapon groups -->
	<element name="Weapon Group (Daggers)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_DAGGERS" />
	    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_WEAPON_DAGGER">
		    <supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_DAGGERS</supports>
	    </append>
	<element name="Weapon Group (Heavy Crossbows)" type="Weapon Group" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_HEAVY_CROSSBOWS" />
	    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_WEAPON_CROSSBOW_HEAVY">
		    <supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_HEAVY_CROSSBOWS</supports>
	    </append>
	
<!-- Akaasit Blade -->
	<element name="Akaasit Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_AKAASIT_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>This dagger is crafted from the arm blade of a defeated akaasit (see Tome of Beasts 2).</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. You can use an action to activate a small measure of prescience within the dagger for 1 minute. If you are attacked by a creature you can see within 5 feet of you while this effect is active, you can use your reaction to make one attack with this dagger against the attacker. If your attack hits, the dagger loses its prescience, and its prescience can’t be activated again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- Anchor of Striking -->
	<element name="Anchor of Striking" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ANCHOR_OF_STRIKING">
		<description>
			<p>This small rusty iron anchor feels sturdy in spite of its appearance. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic war pick.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon, the target is wrapped in ethereal golden chains that extend from the bottom of the anchor. As an action, the chained target can make a DC 15 Strength or Dexterity check, freeing itself from the chains on a success. Alternatively, you can use a bonus action to command the chains to disappear, freeing the target. The chains are constructed of magical force and can’t be damaged, though they can be destroyed with a disintegrate spell. While the target is wrapped in these chains, you and the target can’t move further than 50 feet from each other.</p>
	  	</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="war pick">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">War Pick</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>


<!-- Angry Hornet -->
	<element name="Angry Hornet" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ANGRY_HORNET">
		<description>
		  <p>This black ammunition has yellow fletching or yellow paint.</p>
		  <p class="indent">When you fire this magic ammunition, it makes an angry buzzing sound, and it multiplies in flight. As it flies, 2d4 identical pieces of ammunition magically appear around it, all speeding toward your target. Roll separate attack rolls for each additional arrow or bullet. Duplicate ammunition disappears after missing or after dealing its damage. If the angry hornet and all its duplicates miss, the angry hornet remains magical and can be fired again, otherwise it is destroyed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
		  <set name="category">Ammunition</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
		  <set name="type">Ammunition</set>
		  <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		  <set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Anointing Mace --> 

	<element name="Anointing Mace" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ANOINTING_MACE">
		<description>
		  <p>Also called an anointing gada, you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
		  <p class="indent">In addition, the ornately decorated head of the mace holds a reservoir perforated with small holes. As an action, you can fill the reservoir with a single potion or vial of liquid, such as holy water or alchemist’s fire. You can press a button on the haft of the weapon as a bonus action, which opens the holes. If you hit a target with the weapon while the holes are open, the weapon deals damage as normal and the target suffers the effects of the liquid. For example, an anointing mace filled with holy water deals an extra 2d6 radiant damage if it hits a fiend or undead. After you press the button and make an attack roll, the liquid is expended, regardless if your attack hits.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
		  <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
		  <set name="type" addition="maul">Weapon</set>
		  <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		  <set name="enhancement">1</set>
		  <set name="weapon">Maul</set>
		  <set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Arrow of Grabbing -->

	<element name="Arrow of Grabbing" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ARROW_OF_GRABBING">
		<description>
			<p>This arrow has a barbed head and is wound with a fine but strong thread that unravels as the arrow soars. If a creature takes damage from the arrow, the creature must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or take 4d6 damage and have the arrowhead lodged in its flesh. A creature grabbed by this arrow can’t move farther away from you. At the end of its turn, the creature can attempt a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking 4d6 piercing damage and dislodging the arrow on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can attempt to pull the grabbed creature up to 10 feet in a straight line toward you, forcing the creature to repeat the saving throw. If the creature fails, it moves up to 10 feet closer to you. If it succeeds, it takes 4d6 piercing damage and the arrow is dislodged.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
		  	<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
		  	<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
		  	<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
		  	<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
		  	<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- Arrow of Unpleasant Herbs -->

	<element name="Arrow of Unpleasant Herbs" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ARROW_OF_UNPLEASANT_HERBS">
		<description>
		  <p>This arrow’s tip is filled with magically preserved, poisonous herbs. When a creature takes damage from the arrow, the arrowhead breaks, releasing the herbs. The creature must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be incapacitated until the end of its next turn as it retches and reels from the poison.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
		  	<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
		  	<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
		  	<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
		  	<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
		  	<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- Asp’s Kiss -->
	
	<element name="Asp's Kiss" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ASPS_KISS">
		<description>
			<p>This haladie features two short, slightly curved blades attached to a single hilt with a short, blue-sheened spike on the hand guard. You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While attuned to this sword, you have immunity to poison damage, and, when you take the Dash action, the extra movement you gain is double your speed instead of equal to your speed. When you use the Attack action with this sword, you can make one attack with its hand guard spike (treat as a dagger) as a bonus action. You can use an action to cause indigo poison to coat the blades of this sword. </p>
			<p class="indent">The poison remains for 1 minute or until two attacks using the blade of this weapon hit one or more creatures. The target must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or take 2d10 poison damage and its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the poison damage taken. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0. The sword can’t be used this way again until the next dawn. </p>
			<p class="indent">When you kill a creature with this weapon, it sheds a single, blue tear as it takes its last breath.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a bard, fighter, ranger, or rogue">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Axe of the Ancients -->
	<element name="Axe of the Ancients" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_AXE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you draw this weapon, you can use a bonus action to cast the thaumaturgy spell from it. You can have only one of the spell’s effects active at a time when you cast it in this way.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="handaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Handaxe</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY" />
		</rules>
	</element>

<!-- Black and White Daggers -->
	<element name="Black and White Daggers" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLACK_AND_WHITE_DAGGERS">
		<description>
			<p>These matched daggers are identical except for the stones set in their pommels. One pommel is chalcedony (opaque white), the other is obsidian (opaque black).</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with both magic weapons. </p>
			<p class="indent">The bonus increases to +3 when you use the white dagger to attack a monstrosity, and it increases to +3 when you use the black dagger to attack an undead.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit a monstrosity or undead with both daggers in the same turn, that creature takes an extra 1d6 piercing damage from the second attack.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
		    <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Blackguard’s Blade -->
	
	<element name="Blackguard's Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLACKGUARDS_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>You have advantage on attack rolls made with this weapon against a target if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, and it has no allies within 5 feet of it</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger or shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger||Shortsword</set>
			<set name="name-format">Blackguard's {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Blade of Petals -->
	<element name="Blade of Petals" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLADE_OF_PETALS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">This brightly-colored shortsword is kept in a wooden scabbard with eternally blooming flowers. The blade is made of dull green steel, and its pommel is fashioned from hard rosewood. As a bonus action, you can conjure a flowery mist which fills a 20-foot area around you with pleasant-smelling perfume. The scent dissipates after 1 minute. </p>
			<p class="indent">A creature damaged by the blade must succeed on a DC 15 Charisma saving throw or be charmed by you until the end of its next turn. A creature can’t be charmed this way more than once every 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Blade of the Dervish -->

	<element name="Blade of the Dervish" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLADE_OF_THE_DERVISH">
		<description>
			<p>This magic scimitar is empowered by your movements. For every 10 feet you move before making an attack, you gain a +1 bonus to the attack and damage rolls of that attack, and the scimitar deals an extra 1d6 slashing damage if the attack hits (maximum of +3 and 3d6). </p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, if you use the Dash action and move within 5 feet of a creature, you can attack that creature as a bonus action. On a hit, the target takes an extra 2d6 slashing damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="scimitar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Scimitar</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Blade of the Temple Guardian --> 
	<element name="Blade of the Temple Guardian" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLADE_OF_THE_TEMPLE_GUARDIAN">
		<description>
			<p>This simple but elegant shortsword is a magic weapon. When you are wielding it and use the Flurry of Blows class feature, you can make your bonus attacks with the sword rather than unarmed strikes. If you deal damage to a creature with this weapon and reduce it to 0 hit points, you absorb some of its energy, regaining 1 expended ki point.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a monk">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- Bloodbow -->

	<element name="Bloodbow" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLOODBOW">
		<description>
			<p>This longbow is carved of a light, sturdy wood such as hickory or yew, and it is almost always stained a deep maroon hue, lacquered and aged under layers of sundried blood. The bow is sometimes decorated with reptilian teeth, centaur tails, or other battle trophies. </p>
			<p class="indent">The bow is designed to harm the particular type of creature whose blood most recently soaked the weapon. When you make a ranged attack roll with this magic weapon against a creature of that type, you have a +1 bonus to the attack and damage rolls. If the attack hits, the target must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or become enraged until the end of your next turn. While enraged, the target suffers a random short-term madness. Bloodbows are most commonly soaked in the blood of bandits, thieves, or other humanoids. If you soak this weapon in the blood of a different type of creature for at least 1 hour, it ceases to affect the previous type of creature. The bow affects the new type of creature after you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longbow</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>


<!-- Blooddrinker Spear -->
	<element name="Blooddrinker Spear" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLOODDRINKER_SPEAR">
		<description>
			<p>Prized by gnolls, the upper haft of this spear is decorated with tiny animal skulls, feathers, and other adornments. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit a creature with this spear, you mark that creature for 1 hour. Until the mark ends, you deal an extra 1d6 damage to the target whenever you hit it with the spear, an dyou have advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) or Wisdom (Survival) check you make to find the target. If the target drops to 0 hit points, the mark ends. This property can't be used on a different creature until you spend a short rest cleaning the previous target's blood from the spear.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Bloodfuel Weapon -->

	<element name="Bloodfuel Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLOODFUEL_WEAPON">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. The first time you attack with the weapon on each of your turns, you can spend one or more Hit Dice, up to your maximum Hit Dice. For each Hit Die spent in this way, you roll the die and add your Constitution modifier to it. You lose hit points equal to the total, and the target takes extra necrotic damage equal to the total. You can’t use this feature of the weapon if you don’t have blood. </p>
			<p class="indent">Hit Dice spent using this weapon’s feature can’t be used to regain hit points during a short rest. You regain spent Hit Dice as normal.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any that deals piercing or slashing">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING||ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="name-format">Bloodfuel {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Bloodthirsty Weapon -->
	<element name="Bloodthirsty Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLOODTHIRSTY_WEAPON">
		<description>
			<p>This magic weapon bears long, branching channels inscribed into its blade or head, and it gives off a coppery scent. When you damage a creature that has blood with this weapon, it loses an additional 2d6 hit points from blood loss. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Thirsting.</i></b> The weapon acquires a taste for creatures it damaged. When you miss an attack with this weapon against a creature you damaged with this weapon within the last 1 minute, the target loses 2d6 hit points due to blood loss as the weapon draws blood out of open wounds as it passes. If the wounded creature uses an action to stanch the wound with a successful DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check or the creature receives magical healing, the blade no longer has a taste for it, preventing this property from triggering. This property doesn’t work against creatures that don’t have blood.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any weapon that deals piercing or slashing damage">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING|ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="name-format">Bloodthirsty {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Bludgeon of Nightmares -->
	<element name="Bludgeon of Nightmares" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BLUDGEON_OF_NIGHTMARES">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon. The weapon appears to be a mace of disruption, and an identify spell reveals it to be such.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> This weapon is cursed. Becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. As long as you remain cursed, you are unwilling to part with the weapon, keeping it on your person at all times. While attuned to this weapon, you have disadvantage on attack rolls made with weapons other than this one.</p>
			<p class="indent">The first time you use this weapon to kill a creature that has an Intelligence score of 5 or higher, you begin having nightmares and disturbing visions that disrupt your rest. Each time you complete a long rest, you must make a Wisdom saving throw. The DC equals 10 + the total number of creatures with Intelligence 5 or higher that you’ve reduced to 0 hit points with this weapon. On a failure, you gain no benefits from that long rest, and you gain one level of exhaustion.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="flail, mace, or morningstar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Flail||Mace||Morningstar</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Bone Whip --> 
	<element name="Bone Whip" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BONE_WHIP">
		<description>
			<p>This whip is constructed of humanoid vertebrae with their edges magically sharpened and pointed. The bones are joined together into a coiled line by strands of steel wire. The handle is half a femur wrapped in soft leather of tanned humanoid skin. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action to cause fiendish energy to coat the whip. For 1 minute, you gain 5 temporary hit points the first time you hit a creature on each turn. In addition, when you deal damage to a creature with this weapon, the creature must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced by an amount equal to the damage dealt. This reduction lasts until the creature finishes a long rest. Once used, this property of the whip can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="whip">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Whip</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Bonebreaker Mace -->
	<element name="Bonebreaker Mace" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BONEBREAKER_MACE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus on attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. The bonus increases to +3 when you use it to attack an undead creature. Often given to the grim enforcers of great necropolises, these weapons can reduce the walking dead to splinters with a single strike.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit an undead creature with this magic weapon, treat that creature as if it is vulnerable to bludgeoning damage. If it is already vulnerable to bludgeoning damage, your attack deals an additional 1d6 radiant damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any weapon that deals bludgeoning damage">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Bow of Accuracy -->
	<element name="Bow of Accuracy" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BOW_OF_ACCURACY">
		<description>
			<p>The normal range of this bow is doubled, but its long range remains the same.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any bow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_BOWS</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Breaker Lance -->
	<element name="Breaker Lance" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BREAKER_LANCE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this magic weapon. When you attack an object or structure with this magic lance and hit, maximize your weapon damage dice against the target.</p>
			<p class="indent">The lance has 3 charges. As part of an attack action with the lance, you can expend a charge while striking a barrier created by a spell, such as a wall of fire or wall of force, or an entryway protected by the arcane lock spell. You must make a Strength check against a DC equal to 10 + the spell’s level. On a successful check, the spell ends. The lance regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="lance">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Lance</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Bullseye Arrow -->
	<element name="Bullseye Arrow" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BULLSEYE_ARROW">
		<description>
			<p>This arrow has bright red fletching and a blunt, red tip. You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls made with this magic arrow. On a hit, the arrow deals no damage, but it paints a magical red dot on the target for 1 minute. While the dot lasts, the target takes an extra 1d4 damage of the weapon’s type from any ranged attack that hits it. In addition, ranged weapon attacks against the target score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20. When this arrow hits a target, the arrow vanishes in a flash of red light and is destroyed.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Buzzing Blade -->
	<element name="Buzzing Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_BUZZING_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>You can use a bonus action to speak this weapon’s command word, causing the blade to emit a loud buzzing sound. The buzzing noise is audible out to 100 feet. While the sword is buzzing, it deals an extra 2d6 thunder damage to any target it hits. The buzzing lasts until you use a bonus action to speak the command word again or until you drop or sheathe the weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword or axe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
		
<!-- Candied Axe -->
	<element name="Candied Axe" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_CANDIED_AXE">
		<description>
			<p>This battleaxe bears a golden head spun from crystalized honey. Its wooden handle is carved with reliefs of bees. You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Blessing of the Bee.</i></b> While you are attuned to the axe, you have immunity to poison damage, and you have advantage on any Charisma check to interact with beasts.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Honey Drip.</i></b> While you are holding the battleaxe, you can use an action to cast the slow spell (save DC 15) from the weapon. Once used, this property can’t be used again until the next dawn. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> The axe bears a curse that affects any non bearfolk that attunes to it. Even if the attunement ends, the curse remains. With each passing day, the creature’s physical appearance and stature become more bearlike. After 7 days, the creature looks like a typical bearfolk, but the creature neither loses its racial traits nor gains the racial traits of a bearfolk. </p>
			<p class="indent">The physical changes wrought by the axe can’t be dispelled, but they can be undone by any effect that removes a curse, such as the remove curse spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" />
		</rules>
	</element>

<!-- Chainbreaker Blade -->
	<element name="Chainbreaker Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_CHAINBREAKER_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you use this weapon to attack or break chains, manacles, or similar metal objects restraining creatures, you have advantage on the attack roll or ability check. In addition, such items have vulnerability to this sword’s weapon damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Chainbreaker {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Chieftain’s Axe -->
	<element name="Chieftain's Axe" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_CHIEFTAINS_AXE">
		<description>
			<p>Furs conceal the worn runes lining the haft of this oversized, silver-headed battleaxe. You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this silvered, magic weapon. Chieftain’s Rally. You can use an action to raise the axe while shouting a rallying cry. All allies who can hear and see you can use a reaction to make a melee attack. Once used, this property can’t be used again until the next dawn. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Bearfolk Belonging.</i></b> If you aren’t a bearfolk, bearfolk who see you carrying the chieftain’s axe are immediately hostile. In addition, you have disadvantage on Charisma checks to influence bearfolk. However, if you turn the axe over to bearfolk, provided you haven’t used the axe against bearfolk to their knowledge, they become friendly and, at the GM’s discretion, might provide aid to you and your allies.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Clockwork Mace of Divinity -->
	<element name="Clockwork Mace of Divinity" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_CLOCKWORK_MACE_OF_DIVINITY">
		<description>
			<p>This clockwork mace is composed of several different metals. While attuned to this magic weapon, you have proficiency with it. As a bonus action, you can command the mace to transform into a trident. When you hit with an attack using this weapon’s trident form, the target takes an extra 1d6 radiant damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Mace</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MACE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

<!-- Constant Dagger -->
	 <element name="Constant Dagger" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_CONSTANT_DAGGER">
		 <description>
			 <p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon, the target loses its resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage until the start of your next turn. If it has immunity to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, its immunity instead becomes resistance to such damage until the start of your next turn. If the creature doesn’t have resistance or immunity to such damage, you roll your damage dice three times, instead of twice.</p>
			 <p class="indent"></p>
		 </description>
		 <setters>
			 <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			 <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			 <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			 <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			 <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			 <set name="enhancement">1</set>
			 <set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		 </setters>
	 </element>

<!-- Consuming Rod -->
	<element name="Consuming Rod" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_CONSUMING_ROD">
		<description>
			<p>This bone mace is crafted from a humanoid femur. One end is carved to resemble a ghoulish face, its mouth open wide and full of sharp fangs. The mace has 8 charges, and it recovers 1d6 + 2 charges daily at dawn. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic mace. When it hits a creature, the mace’s mouth stretches gruesomely wide and bites the target, adding 3 (1d6) piercing damage to the attack. As a reaction, you can expend 1 charge to regain hit points equal to the piercing damage dealt.</p>
			<p class="indent">Alternatively, you can use your reaction to expend 5 charges when you hit a Medium or smaller creature and force the mace to swallow the target. The target must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or be swallowed into an extra-dimensional space within the mace. While swallowed, the target is blinded and restrained, and it has total cover against attacks and other effects outside the mace. The target can still breathe. As an action, you can force the mace to regurgitate the creature, which falls prone in a space within 5 feet of the mace. The mace automatically regurgitates a trapped creature at dawn when it regains charges.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Mace</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Crimson Starfall Arrow -->
	<element name="Crimson Starfall Arrow" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_CRIMSON_STARFALL_ARROW">
		<description>
			<p>This arrow is a magic weapon powered by the sacrifice of your own life energy and explodes upon impact. If you hit a creature with this arrow, you can spend one or more Hit Dice, up to your maximum Hit Dice. For each Hit Die spent in this way, you roll the die and add your Constitution modifier to it. You lose hit points equal to the total, and each creature within 10 feet of the target, including the target, must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking necrotic damage equal to the hit points you lost on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. </p>
			<p class="indent">You can’t use this feature of the arrow if you don’t have blood. Hit Dice spent on this arrow’s feature can’t be used to regain hit points during a short rest. You regain spent Hit Dice as normal.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- Dimensional Net -->
	<element name="Dimensional Net" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_DIMENSIONAL_NET">
		<description>
			<p>Woven from the hair of celestials and fiends, this shimmering iridescent net can subdue and capture otherworldly creatures. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls with this magic weapon. In addition to the normal effects of a net, this net prevents any Large or smaller aberration, celestial, or fiend hit by it from using any method of extradimensional movement, including teleportation or travel to a different plane of existence. When such a creature is bound in this way, a creature must succeed on a DC 30 Strength (Athletics) check to free the bound creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">The net has immunity to damage dealt by the bound creature, but another creature can deal 20 slashing damage to the net and free the bound creature, ending the effect.</p>
			<p class="indent">The net has AC 15 and 30 hit points. It regains 1 hit point every 5 minutes as long as it has at least 1 hit point. If the net drops to 0 hit points, it is destroyed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="net">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Net</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Dirgeblade -->
	<element name="Dirgeblade" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_DIRGEBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>This weapon is an exquisitely crafted rapier set in a silver and leather scabbard. The blade glows a faint stormy blue and is encircled by swirling wisps of clouds. You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">This weapon, when unsheathed, sheds dim blue light in a 20-foot radius. When you hit a creature with it, you can expend 1 Bardic Inspiration to impart a sense of overwhelming grief in the target. A creature affected by this grief must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or fall prone and become incapacitated by sadness until the end of its next turn. </p>
			<p class="indent">Once a month under an open sky, you can use a bonus action to speak this magic sword’s command word and cause the sword to sing a sad dirge. This dirge conjures heavy rain (or snow in freezing temperatures) in the region for 2d6 hours. The precipitation falls in an X-mile radius around you, where X is equal to your level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="rapier">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Rapier</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a bard">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Dagger of the Barbed Devil -->
	<element name="Dagger of the Barbed Devil" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_DAGGER_OF_THE_BARBED_DEVIL">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action to cause sharp, pointed barbs to sprout from this blade. The barbs remain for 1 minute. When you hit a creature while the barbs are active, the creature must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or a barb breaks off into its flesh and the dagger loses its barbs. At the start of each of its turns, a creature with a barb in its flesh must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the start of its next turn as it is wracked with pain. The barb remains until a creature uses its action to remove the barb, dealing 1d4 piercing damage to the barbed creature. Once you cause barbs to sprout from the dagger, you can’t do so again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Dawn Shard -->
	<element name="Dawn Shard" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_DAWN_SHARD">
		<description>
			<p>The blade of this magic weapon gleams with a faint golden shine, and the pommel is etched with a sunburst. As a bonus action, you can command the weapon to shed dim light out to 5 feet, to shed bright light out to 20 feet and dim light for an additional 20 feet, or to douse the light.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon deals an extra 1d6 radiant damage to any creature it hits. This increases to 2d6 radiant damage if the target is undead or a creature of shadow.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword or dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_DAGGERS</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="name-format">Dawn Shard {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Dirk of Daring -->
	<element name="Dirk of Daring" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_DIRK_OF_DARING">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While holding the dagger, you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- Deadfall Arrow -->
	<element name="Deadfall Arrow" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_DEADFALL_ARROW">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic arrow. On a hit, the arrow transforms into a 10-foot-long wooden log centered on the target, destroying the arrow. The target and each creature in the log’s area must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 3d6 bludgeoning damage and is knocked prone and restrained under the log. On a success, a creature takes half the damage and isn’t knocked prone or restrained. A restrained creature can take its action to free itself by succeeding on a DC 15 Strength check. The log lasts for 1 minute then crumbles to dust, freeing those restrained by it.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- Dragonstooth Blade -->
	<element name="Dragonstooth Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_DRAGONSTOOTH_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>This razor-sharp blade, little more than leather straps around the base of a large tooth, still carries the power of a dragon. This weapon’s properties are determined by the type of dragon that once owned this tooth. The GM chooses the dragon type or determines it randomly from the options below. When you hit with an attack using this magic sword, the target takes an extra 1d6 damage of a type determined by the kind of dragon that once owned the tooth. In addition, you have resistance to the type of damage associated with that dragon.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>Dragon</td><td>Damage</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Black or Copper</td><td>Acid</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Brass, Gold, or Red</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Green</td><td>Poison</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Blue or Bronze</td><td>Lightning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Silver or White</td><td>Cold</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Undead</td><td>Necrotic</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword or longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword||Longsword</set>
			<set name="name-format">Dragonstooth {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- Enraging Ammunition  -->
	<element name="Enraging Ammunition" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ENRAGING_AMMUNITION">
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with a ranged attack using this magical ammunition, the target must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or become enraged for 1 minute. On its turn, an enraged creature moves toward you by the most direct route, trying to get within 5 feet of you. It doesn’t avoid opportunity attacks, but it moves around or avoids damaging terrain, such as lava or a pit. If the enraged creature is within 5 feet of you, it attacks you. An enraged creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Ensnaring Ammunition -->
	 <element name="Ensnaring Ammunition" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ENSNARING_AMMUNITION">
		 <description>
			 <p>When you hit a creature with a ranged attack using this magical ammunition, the target takes only half the damage from the attack, and the target is restrained as the ammunition bursts into entangling strands that wrap around it. As an action, the restrained target can make a DC 13 Strength check, bursting the bonds on a success. The strands can also be attacked and destroyed (AC 10; hp 5; immunity to bludgeoning, poison, and psychic damage).</p>
		 </description>
		 <setters>
			 <set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			 <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			 <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			 <set name="type">Ammunition</set>
			 <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		 </setters>
	 </element>

<!-- Entrenching Mattock -->
	<element name="Entrenching Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ENTRENCHING_MATTOCK">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 to attack and damage rolls with this magic weapon. This bonus increases to +3 when you use the pick to attack a creature made of earth or stone, such as an earth elemental or stone golem. As a bonus action, you can slam the head of the pick into earth, sand, mud, or rock within 5 feet of you to create a wall of that material up to 30 feet long, 3 feet high, and 1 foot thick along that surface. The wall provides half cover to creatures behind it. The pick can’t be used this way again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="war pick">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">War Pick</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Exsanguinating Blade -->
	<element name="Exsanguinating Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_EXSANGUINATING_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>This double-bladed dagger has an ivory hilt, and its gold pommel is shaped into a woman’s head with ruby eyes and a fanged mouth opened in a scream. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. </p>
			<p class="indent">When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon against a creature that has blood, the dagger gains 1 charge. The dagger can hold 1 charge at a time. You can use a bonus action to expend 1 charge from the dagger to cause one of the following effects: </p>
			<p class="indent">You or a creature you touch with the blade regains 2d8 hit points. </p>
			<p class="indent">The next time you hit a creature that has blood with this weapon, it deals an extra 2d8 necrotic damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
	
<!-- Flash Bullet -->
	 <element name="Flash Bullet" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_FLASH_BULLET">
		 <description>
			 <p>When you hit a creature with a ranged attack using this shiny, polished stone, it releases a sudden flash of bright light. The target takes damage as normal and must succeed on a DC 11 Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the end of its next turn. Creatures with the Sunlight Sensitivity trait have disadvantage on this saving throw.</p>
		 </description>
		 <setters>
			 <set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			 <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			 <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			 <set name="type" addition="sling bullet">Ammunition</set>
			 <set name="rarity">Common</set>
		 </setters>
	 </element>

<!-- Fog Stone -->
	 <element name="Fog Stone" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_FOG_STONE">
		 <description>
			 <p>This sling stone is carved to look like a fluffy cloud. Typically, 1d4 + 1 fog stones are found together. When you fire the stone from a sling, it transforms into a miniature cloud as it flies through the air, and it creates a 20-foot-radius sphere of fog centered on the target or point of impact. The sphere spreads around corners, and its area is heavily obscured. It lasts for 10 minutes or until a wind of moderate or greater speed (at least 10 miles per hour) disperses it.</p>
			 <p class="indent"></p>
		 </description>
		 <setters>
			 <set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			 <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			 <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			 <set name="type" addition="sling bullet">Ammunition</set>
			 <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		 </setters>
	 </element>

<!-- Forgefire Hammer -->
	<element name="Forgefire Hammer" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_FORGEFIRE_HAMMER">
		<description>
			<p>The head of this weapon is shaped like an anvil, and engravings of fire and arcane runes decorate it. You can use a bonus action to speak this magic weapon’s command word, causing its head to glow red-hot. While red-hot, the weapon deals an extra 1d6 fire damage to any target it hits. The weapon’s anvil-like head remains red-hot until you use a bonus action to speak the command word again or until you drop or sheathe the weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="maul or warhammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon against a target holding or wearing a metal object, such as a metal weapon or metal armor, the target takes an extra 1d4 fire damage and the metal object becomes red-hot for 1 minute. While the object is red-hot and the creature still wears or carries it, the creature takes 1d4 fire damage at the start of each of its turns.</set>
			<set name="weapon">Maul||Warhammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- Gale Javelin -->
	<element name="Gale Javelin" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_GALE_JAVELIN">
		<description>
			<p>The metallic head of this javelin is embellished with three small wings. When you speak a command word while making a ranged weapon attack with this magic weapon, a swirling vortex of wind follows its path through the air. Draw a line between you and the target of your attack; each creature within 10 feet of this line must make a DC 13 Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is pushed backward 10 feet and falls prone. In addition, if this ranged weapon attack hits, the target must make a DC 13 Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the target is pushed backward 15 feet and falls prone. </p>
			<p class="indent">The javelin’s property can’t be used again until the next dawn. In the meantime, it can still be used as a magic weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="javelin">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Javelin</set>
		</setters>
	</element>


<!-- Glazed Blade -->
	 <element name="Glazed Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_GLAZED_BLADE">
		 <description>
			 <p>A pleasant scent emerges from this weapon. While it is on your person, you have advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks made to interact with humanoids and fey.</p>
			 <p class="indent"></p>
		 </description>
		 <setters>
			 <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			 <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			 <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			 <set name="type" addition="any sword or axe">Weapon</set>
			 <set name="rarity">Common</set>
			 <set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES</set>
			 <set name="name-format">Glazed {{parent}}</set>
		 </setters>
	 </element>

<!-- Gnawing Spear -->
	<element name="Gnawing Spear" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_GNAWING_SPEAR">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this magic weapon. </p>
			<p class="indent">When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this spear, its head animates, grows serrated teeth, and lodges itself in the target. While the spear is lodged in the target and you are wielding the spear, the target is grappled by you. At the start of each of your turns, the spear twists and grinds, dealing 2d6 piercing damage to the grappled target. If you release the spear, it remains lodged in the target, dealing damage each round as normal, but the target is no longer grappled by you. While the spear is lodged in a target, you can’t make attacks with it. A creature, including the restrained target, can take its action to remove the spear by succeeding on a DC 15 Strength check. The target takes 1d6 piercing damage when the spear is removed. You can use an action to speak the spear’s command word, causing it to dislodge itself and fall into an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the target.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- Golden Bolt -->
	 <element name="Golden Bolt" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_GOLDEN_BOLT">
		 <description>
			 <p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. This crossbow doesn’t have the loading property, and it doesn’t require ammunition. Immediately after firing a bolt from this weapon, another golden bolt forms to take its place.</p>
			 <p class="indent"></p>
		 </description>
		 <setters>
			 <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			 <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			 <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			 <set name="type" addition="heavy crossbow">Weapon</set>
			 <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			 <set name="enhancement">1</set>
			 <set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_HEAVY_CROSSBOWS</set>
			 <set name="attunement">true</set>
		 </setters>
	 </element>
	
<!-- Hammer of Throwing -->
	<element name="Hammer of Throwing" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_HAMMER_OF_THROWING">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this magic weapon. In addition, when you throw the hammer, it returns to your hand at the end of your turn. If you have no hand free, it falls to the ground at your feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="light hammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Light Hammer</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Hexen Blade -->
	<element name="Hexen Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_HEXEN_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>The colorful surface of this sleek adamantine shortsword exhibits a perpetually shifting, iridescent sheen. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The sword has 5 charges and regains 1d4 + 1 charges daily at dawn. While holding it, you can use an action and expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using spell save DC 15: disguise self (1 charge), hypnotic pattern (3 charges), or mirror image (2 charges).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Hidden Armament -->  <!-- come back to, may make weapon group with one handed melee weapons so this restriction works -->
	<element name="Hidden Armament" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_HIDDEN_ARMAMENT">
		<description>
			<p>While holding this magic weapon, you can use an action to transform it into a tattoo on the palm of your hand. You can use a bonus action to transform the tattoo back into a weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any melee weapon that isn't two-handed">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement"></set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Humble Cudgel of Temperance -->
	<element name="Humble Cudgel of Temperance" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_HUMBLE_CUDGEL_OF_TEMPERANCE">
		<description>
			<p>This simple, polished club has a studded iron band around one end. When you attack a poisoned creature with this magic weapon, you have advantage on the attack roll.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon, the target becomes poisoned for 1 minute. If the target was already poisoned, it becomes incapacitated instead. The target can make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the poisoned or incapacitated condition on itself on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="club">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Club</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Iceblink -->
	<element name="Iceblink" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_ICEBLINK">
		<description>
			<p>The blade of this weapon is cool to the touch and gives off a yellow-white radiance, shedding bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. In temperatures above freezing, vapor wafts off the chilled blade. When you hit with an attack using this magic sword, the target takes an extra 1d6 cold damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Freeze Water.</i></b> While holding the sword, you can use an action to plunge the blade into a body of water, causing its surface to freeze over. The water freezes to a depth of 3 inches within a 60-foot radius of the point where you plunged the blade. Creatures that were swimming on the surface of the water must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or be restrained by the ice. A restrained creature can use an action to make a DC 15 Strength check, breaking free on a success. The ice is not magical and melts after 1 minute if temperatures in the area are not cold enough to sustain it. Once used, this property can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Snowblind.</i></b> While holding the sword, you can use an action to generate a bright flash of light from the blade at one creature you can see within 5 feet of you. The target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be blinded for 1 minute. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Once used, this property can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Impact Club --> 
	<element name="Impact Club" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_IMPACT_CLUB">
		<description>
			<p>This magic weapon has 3 charges and regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. When you hit a target on your turn, you can take a bonus action to spend 1 charge and attempt to shove the target. The club grants you a +1 bonus on your Strength (Athletics) check to shove the target. If you roll a 20 on your attack roll with the club, you have advantage on your Strength (Athletics) check to shove the target, and you can push the target up to 10 feet away.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="club">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Club</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Impaling Weapon -->
	<element name="Impaling Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_IMPALING_WEAPON">
		<description>
			<p>When you attack a creature with this magic weapon and roll a 20 on the attack roll, you embed the weapon in the target. If the target is Medium or smaller and is within 5 feet of a wall or other solid object when you hit with this weapon, it is also restrained while the weapon is embedded. At the end of the target’s turn while the weapon is embedded in it, the target takes damage equal to the weapon’s damage, with no additional modifiers. A creature, including the target, can use its action to make a DC 13 Strength check, removing the weapon from the target on a success. You can remove the embedded weapon from the target by speaking the weapon’s command word.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any melee weapon that deals piercing damage">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="name-format">Impaling {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Knockabout Billet -->
	
	<element name="Knockabout Billet" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_KNOCKABOUT_BILLET">
		<description>
			<p>This stout, oaken cudgel helps you knock your opponents to the ground or away from you. When you hit a creature with this magic weapon, you can shove the target as part of the same attack, using your attack roll in place of a Strength (Athletics) check. The weapon deals damage as normal, regardless of the result of the shove. This property of the club can be used no more than once per hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="club">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="weapon">Club</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Kyshaarth’s Fang -->
	<element name="Kyshaarth's Fang" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_KYSHAARTHS_FANG">
		<description>
			<p>This dagger’s blade is composed of black, bone-like material. Tales suggest the weapon is fashioned from a voidling’s (see Tome of Beasts) tendril barb. When you hit with an attack using this magic weapon, the target takes an extra 2d6 necrotic damage. If you are in dim light or darkness, you regain a number of hit points equal to half the necrotic damage dealt.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- Labyrs of the Raging Bull -->
	<element name="Labyrs of the Raging Bull" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_LABYRS_OF_THE_RAGING_BULL">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While you wield the axe, you have advantage on Strength (Athletics) checks to shove a creature, and you can shove a creature up to two sizes larger than you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe or greataxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe||Greataxe</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- Leaf-Bladed Sword -->
	<element name="Leaf-Bladed Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_LEAF_BLADED_SWORD">
		<description>
			<p>This thin, curved blade has a bell guard shaped like a curled, golden leaf. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this magic weapon. </p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit an aberration or undead creature with it, that target takes an extra 1d8 damage of the weapon’s type.You can use an action to cast the barkskin spell on yourself for 1 hour, requiring no concentration. Once used, this property can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="name-format">Leaf-Bladed {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" />
		</rules>
	</element>
<!-- Lockbreaker -->
	<element name="Lockbreaker" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_LOCKBREAKER">
		<description>
			<p>You can use this stiletto-bladed dagger to open locks by using an action and making a Strength check. The DC is 5 less than the DC to pick the lock (minimum DC 10). On a success, the lock is broken.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<!-- Manticore’s Tail -->
	<element name="Manticore’s Tail" type="Magic Item" source="Vault of Magic" id="ID_KBP_VOM_MAGIC_ITEM_MANTICORES_TAIL">
		<description>
			<p>Ten spikes stick out of the head of this magic weapon. While holding the morningstar, you can fire one of the spikes as a ranged attack, using your Strength modifier for the attack and damage rolls. This attack has a normal range of 100 feet and a long range of 200 feet. On a hit, the spike deals 1d8 piercing damage. Once all of the weapon’s spikes have been fired, the morningstar deals bludgeoning damage instead of the piercing damage normal for a morningstar until the next dawn, at which time the spikes regrow.</p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="morningstar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Morningstar</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	 	
</elements>
