<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Cleric - Moon Domain</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="cleric-moondomain.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Critcal%20Role%3A%20Tal'Dorei%20Campaign%20Setting%20Reborn/archetypes/cleric-moondomain.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <!-- Cleric - Moon Domain -->
    
        <element name="Moon Domain" type="Archetype" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_MOON_DOMAIN">
            <supports>Divine Domain</supports>
            <description>
                <p class="indent">Since the Founding, all mortal creatures have looked to the skies and sensed the power and mystery carried by Catha and Ruidus, the two moons of Exandria. The Moonweaver herself is said to guide her worshipers from within the pale glow of Catha, revealing hidden paths and granting inspired dreams to those who pray to that moon. Distant, dark Ruidus is often regarded with awe and apprehension, considered a portent for fell deeds and bad luck.</p>
                <p class="indent">Clerics of the Moon Domain draw on their divine connection to the moons to wield light and shadow, invoke good fortune and ill favor, and reveal or conceal as they see fit. Most Moon clerics worship the Moonweaver herself, but her followers are as varied as the stars in the sky. Some seek to protect the vulnerable and do good in the world, while others meddle with impunity and distort the truth for selfish gain. Other Moon clerics worship not the gods but the moons themselves, especially those with an innate connection to the lunar cycles through lycanthropy.</p>

                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_CLARITY_OF_CATHA" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_BLESSING_OF_THE_FULL_MOON" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_MIND_OF_TWO_MOONS" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_EMPOWERED_CANTRIPS" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_ECLIPSE_OF_ILL_OMEN" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_SPELLS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_CLARITY_OF_CATHA" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_BLESSING_OF_THE_FULL_MOON" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_MIND_OF_TWO_MOONS" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_EMPOWERED_CANTRIPS" level="8" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_ECLIPSE_OF_ILL_OMEN" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
  
        <!-- Moon Domain Archetype Feature Spells -->
        
            <element name="Domain Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_SPELLS">
                <description>
			        <p><em>1st-level Moon Domain feature</em></p>
			        <p class="indent">You gain domain spells at the cleric levels listed in the Moon Domain Spells table. See the Divine Domain class feature in the <i>Player’s Handbook</i> for how domain spells work.</p>
			        <h5 class="caption">Moon Domain Spells</h5>
			        <table>
			        	<thead>
			        		<tr><td>Cleric Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
			        	</thead>
			        	<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>faerie fire, silent image</em></td></tr>
			        	<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>invisibility, moonbeam</em></td></tr>
			        	<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>hypnotic pattern, major image</em></td></tr>
			        	<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>greater invisibility, hallucinatory terrain</em></td></tr>
			        	<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dream, passwall</em></td></tr>
			        </table>
		        </description>
		        <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="1" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE" level="1" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" level="3" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM" level="3" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN" level="5" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE" level="5" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" level="7" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN" level="7" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" level="9" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
			        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASSWALL" level="9" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
		        </rules>
            </element>
        
        <!-- Moon Domain Archetype Feature Clarity of Catha -->
        
            <element name="Clarity of Catha" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_CLARITY_OF_CATHA">
                <description>
                    <p><em>1st-level Moon Domain feature</em></p>
                    <p>You learn to shine light upon the mind’s most dire moments, shielding those you protect. When a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see makes a Wisdom saving throw, you can use your reaction to grant that creature advantage on the save. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Clarity of Catha" action="Reaction" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>When a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see makes a Wisdom saving throw, you can use your reaction to grant that creature advantage on the save.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        
        <!-- Moon Domain Archetype Feature Channel Divinity Blessing of the Full Moon -->
        
            <element name="Channel Divinity: Blessing of the Full Moon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_BLESSING_OF_THE_FULL_MOON">
                <description>
                    <p><em>2nd-level Moon Domain feature</em></p>
                    <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to infuse your allies with bestial power. As an action, you instill a willing creature of your choice within 30 feet of you that you can see with one of the following blessings of your choice: 
                    <ul>
                    <li><em>Blessing of the Watchful Moon.</em> For 1 hour, the blessed creature’s speed increases by 10 feet, and it has advantage on Wisdom (Perception or Survival) checks involving smell or made to track a creature.</li>
                    <li><em>Blessing of the Blood-Drenched Moon.</em> For 10 minutes, the blessed creature has advantage on attack rolls against a target if at least one of the blessed creature’s allies is within 5 feet of the target and the ally isn’t incapacitated.</li>
                    </ul></p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Blessing of the Full Moon" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
                    <description> You instill a willing creature of your choice within 30 feet of you that you can see with one of the following blessings of your choice: 
                        <em>Blessing of the Watchful Moon.</em> For 1 hour, the blessed creature’s speed increases by 10 feet, and it has advantage on Wisdom (Perception or Survival) checks involving smell or made to track a creature.
                        <em>Blessing of the Blood-Drenched Moon.</em> For 10 minutes, the blessed creature has advantage on attack rolls against a target if at least one of the blessed creature’s allies is within 5 feet of the target and the ally isn’t incapacitated.
                    </description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        
        <!-- Moon Domain Archetype Feature Channel Divinity Mind of Two Moons -->
        
            <element name="Mind of Two Moons" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_MIND_OF_TWO_MOONS">
                <description>
                    <p><em>6th-level Moon Domain feature</em></p>
                    <p>Starting at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to invoke the twofold arcana of Exandria’s moons. By expending one use of Channel Divinity, you can cast a second concentration spell while already concentrating on a first spell, as long as both spells are on your list of Moon Domain spells. If you need to make a Constitution saving throw to maintain your concentration on both spells, you make the save with disadvantage. On a failure, you lose concentration on both spells.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Mind of Two Moons" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
                    <description>By expending one use of Channel Divinity, you can cast a second concentration spell while already concentrating on a first spell, as long as both spells are on your list of Moon Domain spells. If you need to make a Constitution saving throw to maintain your concentration on both spells, you make the save with disadvantage. On a failure, you lose concentration on both spells.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        
        <!-- Moon Domain Archetype Feature Empowered Cantrips -->
        
            <element name="Empowerwed Cantrips" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_EMPOWERED_CANTRIPS">
                <description>
                    <p><em>8th-level Moon Domain feature</em></p>
                    <p>Starting at 8th level, your cleric cantrips deal extra damage equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your cleric cantrips deal extra damage equal to {{wisdom:modifier}}.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        
        <!-- Moon Domain Archetype Feature Eclipse of Ill Omen -->
    
            <element name="Eclipse of Ill Omen" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOON_DOMAIN_ECLIPSE_OF_ILL_OMEN">
                <description>
                    <p><em>17th-level Moon Domain feature</em></p>
                    <p>At 17th level, you can call upon the vermillion moon Ruidus to flare in the sky above you, eclipsing all other light. Its power surrounds you even where the sky can’t be seen, and even on other planes. As a bonus action, you can manifest an area of reddish, dim light in a 60-foot radius around you. In addition to the normal effects of dim light, creatures in the area make saving throws with disadvantage. When you create this eclipse, you can choose any number of creatures that are unaffected by it.</p> 
                    <p class="indent">This eclipse lasts while you concentrate (as if concentrating on a spell) for up to 1 minute. Concentrating on this feature counts as concentrating on a Moon Domain spell for the purpose of your Mind of Two Moons feature.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, once per turn when you deal radiant damage to any creatures in this area of dim light, you can curse one of those creatures until the eclipse ends (no action required). A creature cursed in this way has its speed halved and can’t regain hit points. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Eclipse of Ill Omen" action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can manifest an area of reddish, dim light in a 60-foot radius around you. In addition to the normal effects of dim light, creatures in the area make saving throws with disadvantage. When you create this eclipse, you can choose any number of creatures that are unaffected by it.
                    <em>This eclipse lasts while you concentrate (as if concentrating on a spell) for up to 1 minute. Concentrating on this feature counts as concentrating on a Moon Domain spell for the purpose of your Mind of Two Moons feature.</em>
                    <em>Additionally, once per turn when you deal radiant damage to any creatures in this area of dim light, you can curse one of those creatures until the eclipse ends (no action required). A creature cursed in this way has its speed halved and can’t regain hit points.</em>
                    </description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
    
</elements>
