<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Misc Weapons</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="item-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Miscellaneous/item-weapons.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    	<element name="Kiss of the Sea" type="Magic Item" source="Magwa’s Magic Item Compendium" id="ID_MMIC_MAGIC_ITEM_KISS_OF_THE_SEA">
		<description>
			<p>Appears to be a handle of a whip, with runes carved along the side.</p>
			<p class="indent">As part of your action you speak a command word to make the whip of crystal clear water extend outward from the handle. The whip stays extended until you speak the command word again, or drop it.</p>
			<p class="indent">The whip deals 1d4 slashing, and an additional 2d6 ice damage as the water crystallizes into ice.</p>
			<p class="indent">A number of times equal to your proficiency bonus you can expend a blast of ice dealing 1d6 ice damage to all creaturees in a 10ft radius spehere (no save).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="whip">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Whip</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Chaos Quiver" type="Magic Item" source="Unknown" id="ID_UNKNOWN_MAGIC_ITEM_CHAOS_QUIVER">
		<description>
			<p>On the first attack of your turn, you pull a random magic arrow from the quiver. Arrow is chosen based upon a d4 roll. Chaos Quiver has 5 charges that reset each day at dawn. </p>
			<p class="indent">Second attack also yields non-magical arrows.</p>
			<h5>Arrow Type</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-10">d6</td><td>Arrow</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td><b>Angry Hornet</b> - This black ammunition has yellow fletching or yellow paint. When you fire this magic ammunition, it makes an angry buzzing sound and multiplies in flight. As it flies, 2d4 identical pieces of ammunition magically appear around it, all speeding toward your target. Roll separate attack rolls for each additional arrow or bullet. Duplicate ammunition disappears after a hit or miss. If the Angry Hornet and all its duplicates miss, it remains magical and can be fired again. Otherwise, it is destroyed.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td><b>Arrow of Unpleasant Herbs</b> - This arrow's tip is filled with magically perserved, poisonous herbs. When a creature takes damage from this arrow, the arrowhead breaks releasing the herbs. The creature must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution save or be incapacitated until the end of its next turn as it retches and reels from the poison.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td><b>Enraging Ammunition</b> - When you hit a creature with a ranged attack using this magical ammunition, the target must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or become enraged for 1 minute. On its turn, an enraged creature moves toward you by the most direct route, trying to get within 5 feet of you. It doesn't avoid opportunity attacks, but it moves around or avoids damaging terrain, such as lava or a pit. If the enraged creature is within 5 feet of you, it attacks you. An enraged creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td><b>Ensnaring Ammunition</b> - When you hit a creature with a ranged attack using this magical ammunition, the target takes only half the damage from the attack, and the target is restrained as the ammunition bursts into entangling strands that wrap around it. As an action, the restrained target can make a DC 13 Strength check, bursting the bonds on a success. The strands can also be attacked and destroyed (AC 10; hp 5; immunity to bludgeoning, poison, and psychic damage).</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Chaos Quiver (Upgraded)" type="Magic Item" source="Unknown" id="ID_UNKNOWN_MAGIC_ITEM_CHAOS_QUIVER_UPGRADED">
		<description>
			<p>On the first attack of your turn, you pull a random magic arrow from the quiver. Arrow is chosen based upon a d6 roll. Chaos Quiver has 5 charges that reset each day at dawn. </p>
			<p class="indent">Second attack also yields non-magical arrows.</p>
			<h5>Arrow Type</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-10">d6</td><td>Arrow</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td><b>Angry Hornet</b> - This black ammunition has yellow fletching or yellow paint. When you fire this magic ammunition, it makes an angry buzzing sound and multiplies in flight. As it flies, 2d4 identical pieces of ammunition magically appear around it, all speeding toward your target. Roll separate attack rolls for each additional arrow or bullet. Duplicate ammunition disappears after a hit or miss. If the Angry Hornet and all its duplicates miss, it remains magical and can be fired again. Otherwise, it is destroyed.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td><b>Arrow of Unpleasant Herbs</b> - This arrow's tip is filled with magically perserved, poisonous herbs. When a creature takes damage from this arrow, the arrowhead breaks releasing the herbs. The creature must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution save or be incapacitated until the end of its next turn as it retches and reels from the poison.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td><b>Enraging Ammunition</b> - When you hit a creature with a ranged attack using this magical ammunition, the target must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or become enraged for 1 minute. On its turn, an enraged creature moves toward you by the most direct route, trying to get within 5 feet of you. It doesn't avoid opportunity attacks, but it moves around or avoids damaging terrain, such as lava or a pit. If the enraged creature is within 5 feet of you, it attacks you. An enraged creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td><b>Ensnaring Ammunition</b> - When you hit a creature with a ranged attack using this magical ammunition, the target takes only half the damage from the attack, and the target is restrained as the ammunition bursts into entangling strands that wrap around it. As an action, the restrained target can make a DC 13 Strength check, bursting the bonds on a success. The strands can also be attacked and destroyed (AC 10; hp 5; immunity to bludgeoning, poison, and psychic damage).</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td><b>Sand Arrow</b> - The shaft of this arrow is made of tightly packed white sand that discorporates into a blast of grit when it strikes a target. On a hit, the sand catches in the fittings and joints of metal armor, and the target's speed is reduced by 10 feet until it cleans or removes the armor. In addition, the target must succeed on a DC 11 Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the end of its next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td><b>Arrow of Grabbing</b> - This arrow has a barbed head and is wound with a fine but strong thread that unravels as the arrow soars. If a creature takes damage from the arrow, the creature must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or take 4d6 damage and have the arrowhead lodged in its flesh. A creature grabbed by this arrow can't move farther away from you. At the end of its turn, the creature can attempt a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking 4d6 piercing damage and dislodging the arrow on a success. As an action, you can attempt to pull the grabbed creature up to 10 feet in a straight line toward you, forcing the creature to repeat the saving throw. If the creature fails, it moves up to 10 feet closer to you. If it succeeds, it takes 4d6 piercing damage and the arrow is dislodged.</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>
