<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Deep Magic Spells - G</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="g-spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Kobold%20Press/Deep%20Magic/spells/g-spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

<!-- GLACIAL CASCADE  -->
	<element name="Glacial Cascade" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GLACIAL_CASCADE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By harnessing the power of ice and frost, you emanate pure cold, filling a 30-foot-radius sphere. Creatures other than you in the sphere take 10d8 cold damage, or half as much damage with a successful Constitution saving throw. A creature killed by this spell is transformed into ice, leaving behind no trace of its original body.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30 ft. radius sphere)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of alexandrite</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- GLACIAL FOG  -->
	<element name="Glacial Fog" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GLACIAL_FOG">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As you cast this spell, a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on a point within range becomes covered in a frigid fog. Each creature that is in the area at the start of its turn while the spell remains in effect must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 12d6 cold damage and gains one level of exhaustion, and it has disadvantage on Perception checks until the start of its next turn. On a successful save, the creature takes half the damage and ignores the other effects. </p>
			<p class="indent">Stored devices and tools are all frozen by the fog: crossbow mechanisms become sluggish, weapons are stuck </p>
			<p class="indent">in scabbards, potions turn to ice, bag cords freeze together, and so forth. Such items require the application of heat for 1 round or longer in order to become useful again. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 7th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">crystalline statue of a polar bear worth at least 25 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- GLIMPSE THE END --> 
	<element name="Glimpse the End" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GLIMPSE_THE_END">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You examine the life force in a creature you touch and sense when it will expire. You and the creature share a vision of the most likely way in which the creature will die. You both sense approximately how far into the future the event occurs. The vision is not a prophecy or a definite fate; life can take unexpected twists and turns. It is, however, the most likely outcome at the current time unless the creature alters the course of its life. The vision can seem to last as little as a few moments or as long as 30 minutes to you and the spell’s target, but in the objective world, the knowledge is received instantaneously.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">apocalypse</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="apocalypse">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pinch of grave dust or a piece from a tombstone</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- GLUEY GLOBULE  -->	
	<element name="Gluey Globule" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GLUEY_GLOBULE">
		<supports>Artificer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You make a ranged spell attack to hurl a large globule of sticky, magical glue at a creature within 120 feet. If the attack hits, the target creature is restrained. A restrained creature can break free by using an action to make a successful Strength saving throw. When the creature breaks free, it takes 2d6 slashing damage from the glue tearing its skin. If your ranged spell attack roll was a critical hit or exceeded the target’s AC by 5 or more, the Strength saving throw is made with disadvantage. The target can also be freed by an application of universal solvent or by taking 20 acid damage. The glue dissolves when the creature breaks free or at the end of 1 minute. </p>
			<p class="indent">Alternatively, gluey globule can also be used to glue an object to a solid surface or to another object. In this case, the spell works like a single application of sovereign glue and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute or 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a drop of glue</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- GRAVE SENSE  -->
	<element name="Grave Sense" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GRAVE_SENSE">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch a willing undead creature or one that’s under your control. For the duration of the spell, you can use an action to see what the undead creature sees (including through darkvision, blindsight, tremorsense, or truesight), and to hear what it hears, until the start of your next turn. You use your own ability scores and skill proficiencies to spot things and to interpret the sensations you’re receiving.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">apocalypse</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="apocalypse">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- GREATER PROTECTIVE NIMBUS --> 
	<element name="Greater Protective Nimbus" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GREATER_PROTECTIVE_NIMBUS">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You wrap yourself in a powerful corona that sheds bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. Until the spell ends, you have resistance to necrotic damage and radiant damage. You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it, which creates a blast of light in a 30-foot radius. The blast deals 4d8 radiant damage to each creature in the area while simultaneously healing yourself of an equal amount of damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a transparent gemstone worth at least 50 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- GREATER SEAL OF SANCTUARY --> 
	<element name="Greater Seal of Sanctuary" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GREATER_SEAL_OF_SANCTUARY">
		<supports>Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You inscribe an angelic seal on the ground, the floor, or other solid surface of a structure. The seal creates a spherical sanctuary with a radius of 100 feet, centered on the seal. For the duration, aberrations, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead that approach to within 5 feet of the boundary know they are about to come into contact with a deadly barrier. If such a creature moves so as to touch the boundary, or tries to cross the boundary by any means, including teleportation and extradimensional travel, it must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 15d8 radiant damage, is repelled to 5 feet outside the boundary, and can’t target anything inside the boundary with attacks, spells, or abilities until the spell ends. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much radiant damage and can cross the boundary. If the creature is a fiend that isn’t on its home plane, it is immediately destroyed (no saving throw) instead of taking damage. </p>
			<p class="indent">Aberrations, elementals, fey, and undead that are within 100 feet of the seal (inside the boundary) have disadvantage on ability checks, attack rolls, and saving throws, and each such creature takes 4d8 radiant damage at the start of its turn. </p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures other than aberrations, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead can’t be charmed or frightened while within 100 feet of the seal.</p>
			<p class="indent">The seal has AC 18, 75 hit points, resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, and immunity to psychic and poison damage. Ranged attacks against the seal are made with disadvantage. If it is scribed on the surface of an object that is later destroyed (such as a wooden door), the seal is not damaged and remains in place, perhaps suspended in midair. The spell ends only if the seal itself is reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">angelic,ritual</set>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school" addition="angelic">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">incense and special inks worth 500 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	

<!-- GRIM SIPHON  -->
	<element name="Grim Siphon" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GRIM_SIPHON">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You twist the forces of entropy around two creatures, bringing distress to one while staving off the demise of the other. A creature you can see within range must make a successful Constitution saving throw or take poison damage equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier. Another creature you choose that is within 5 feet of the target regains hit points equal to half the amount of poison damage dealt.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the poison damage increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">apocalypse</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="apocalypse">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">the skull of a Tiny mammal or bird</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- GUEST OF HONOR  -->
	<element name="Guest of Honor" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GUEST_OF_HONOR">
		<supports>Bard,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You whisper words of encouragement, and a creature that you touch gains confidence along with approval from strangers. For the spell’s duration, the target puts its best foot forward and strangers associate the creature with positive feelings. The target adds 1d4 to all Charisma (Persuasion) checks made to influence the attitudes of others. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the effect lasts for an additional 10 minutes for each slot level above 1st. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ritual Focus.</i></b> If you expend your ritual focus, the effect lasts for 24 hours. Also, once you've expended your ritual focus this mental energy has been expended, a caster’s ritual focus can’t be used again until he or she finishes a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ritual</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="ritual only">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a signet ring worth 25gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- GUIDING STAR -->
	<element name="Guiding Star" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_GUIDING_STAR">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By observing the stars or the position of the sun, you are able to determine the cardinal directions, as well as the direction and distance to a stated destination. You can’t become directionally disoriented or lose track of the destination. The spell doesn’t, however, reveal the best route to your destination or warn you about deep gorges, flooded rivers, or other impassable or treacherous terrain.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>