<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Deep Magic Spells - J-K</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="jk-spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Kobold%20Press/Deep%20Magic/spells/jk-spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

<!-- JERILYN’S CADAVEROUS UPRISING --> 
	<element name="Jerilyn's Cadaverous Uprising" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_JERILYNS_CADAVEROUS_UPRISING">
		<supports>Cleric,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Specify a 5-foot-square space of natural ground (not solid stone) that you can see within range, then choose any undead creature of challenge rating 1 or lower (such as a specter, ghoul, shadow, zombie, or skeleton). That creature claws its way up out of the ground and immediately tries to grapple or attack a creature within 5 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">The undead uses its standard stat block, but it has only 10 hit points and is prone until it stands up. It takes its turn immediately after yours. You can use a bonus action to issue a mental command to the undead when you cast the spell, and you can change the command by using a bonus action on your turn while the spell is active. Once given an order, the creature continues to follow it until its task is complete. If you issue no command, the creature defends itself and attacks the last enemy that attacked it.</p>
			<p class="indent">The creature remains under your control for 1 hour, after which it crumbles to dust or disappears.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> The number of undead you summon increases when you cast this spell with a higher-level spell slot: two when cast with a 5th-level slot, three with a 7th-level slot, and four with a 9th-level slot.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">apocalypse</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="apocalypse">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">the severed hand of a humanoid creature</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>     
    
<!-- KOBOLD’S FURY --> 
	<element name="Kobold's Fury" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_KOBOLDS_FURY">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your touch infuses the rage of a threatened kobold into the target. The target has advantage on melee weapon attacks until the end of its next turn. In addition, its next successful melee weapon attack against a creature larger than itself does an additional 2d8 damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a kobold scale</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>  

</elements>