<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Deep Magic Spells - L</name>
        <update version="0.0.4">
            <file name="l-spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Kobold%20Press/Deep%20Magic/spells/l-spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

<!-- LABYRINTH MASTERY  --> 
	<element name="Labyrinth Mastery" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LABYRINTH_MASTERY">
		<supports>Bard,Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Upon casting this spell, you immediately gain a sense of your surroundings. If you are in a physical maze or any similar structure with multiple paths and dead ends, this spell guides you to the nearest exit, although not necessarily along the fastest or shortest route.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, while the spell is guiding you out of such a structure, you have advantage on ability checks to avoid being surprised and on initiative rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a perfect memory of all portions of the structure you move through during the spell’s duration. If you revisit such a portion, you recognize that you’ve been there before and automatically notice any changes to the environment.</p>
			<p class="indent">Also, while under the effect of this spell, you can exit any maze spell (and its lesser and greater varieties) as an action without needing to make an Intelligence check.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">labyrinth</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="labyrinth">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of blank parchment</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 
	
<!-- LABYRINTHINE HOWL  -->
	<element name="Labyrinthine Howl" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LABYRINTHINE_HOWL">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You let loose the howl of a ravenous beast, causing each enemy within range that can hear you to make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, a creature believes it has been transported into a labyrinth and is under attack by savage beasts. An affected creature must choose either to face the beasts or to curl into a ball for protection. A creature that faces the beasts takes 7d8 psychic damage, and then the spell ends on it. A creature that curls into a ball falls prone and is stunned until the end of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 2d8 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">labyrinth</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="labyrinth">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dead mouse</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LAIR SENSE  --> 
	<element name="Lair Sense" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LAIR_SENSE">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You set up a magical boundary around your lair. The boundary can’t exceed the dimensions of a 100-foot cube, but within that maximum, you can shape it as you like— to follow the walls of a building or cave, for example. While the spell lasts, you instantly become aware of any Tiny or larger creature that enters the enclosed area. You know the creature’s type but nothing else about it. You are also aware when creatures leave the area.</p>
			<p class="indent">This awareness is enough to wake you from sleep, and you receive the knowledge as long as you’re on the same plane of existence as your lair.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, add 50 feet to the maximum dimensions of the cube and add 12 hours to the spell’s duration for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">treasure worth at least 500 gp, which is not consumed in casting</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LAST RAYS OF THE DYING SUN  -->
	<element name="Last Rays of the Dying Sun" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LAST_RAYS_OF_THE_DYING_SUN">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A burst of searing heat explodes from you, dealing 6d6 fire damage to all enemies within range. Immediately afterward, a wave of frigid cold rolls across the same area, dealing 6d6 cold damage to enemies. A creature that makes a successful Dexterity saving throw takes half the damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th or 9th level, the damage from both waves increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 7th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">40 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LEGEND KILLER  -->
	<element name="Legend Killer" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LEGEND_KILLER">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You tap into the life force of a creature that is capable of performing legendary actions. When you cast the spell, the target must make a successful Constitution saving throw or lose the ability to take legendary actions for the spell’s duration. A creature can’t use legendary resistance to automatically succeed on the saving throw against this spell. An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, regaining 1 legendary action on a successful save. The target continues repeating the saving throw until the spell ends or it regains all its legendary actions.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a silver scroll describing the spell's target wroth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LEGION  --> 
	<element name="Legion" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LEGION">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You call down a legion of shadowy soldiers in a 10-foot cube. Their features resemble a mockery of once-living creatures. Whenever a creature starts its turn inside the cube or within 5 feet of it, or enters the cube for the first time on its turn, the conjured shades make an attack using your melee spell attack modifier; on a hit, the target takes 3d8 necrotic damage. The space inside the cube is difficult terrain.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shadow</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="shadow">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a toy soldier</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- LESSER MAZE  -->
	<element name="Lesser Maze" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LESSER_MAZE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell functions as maze, but the target can resist being sent to the extradimensional prison with a successful Intelligence saving throw. In addition, the maze is easier to navigate, requiring only a DC 12 Intelligence check to escape.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">labyrinth</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="labyrinth">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LIFE DRAIN  --> 
	<element name="Life Drain" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LIFE_DRAIN">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>With a snarled word of Void Speech, you create a swirling vortex of purple energy. Choose a point you can see within range. Creatures within 15 feet of the point take 10d6 necrotic damage, or half that damage with a successful Constitution saving throw. For each creature damaged by the spell, you can choose one other creature within range, including yourself, that is not a construct or undead. The secondary targets regain hit points equal to half the necrotic damage you dealt.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the vortex’s damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 6th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">void</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="void">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">90 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- LIFE HACK --> 
	<element name="Life Hack" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LIFE_HACK">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose up to five creatures that you can see within range. Each of the creatures gains access to a pool of temporary hit points that it can draw upon over the spell’s duration or until the pool is used up. The pool contains 120 temporary hit points. The number of temporary hit points each individual creature can draw is determined by dividing 120 by the number of creatures with access to the pool. Hit points are drawn as a bonus action by the creature gaining the temporary hit points. Any number can be drawn at once, up to the maximum allowed.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature can’t draw temporary hit points from the pool while it has temporary hit points from any source, including a previous casting of this spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a ruby worth 500 gp, which is consumed during the casting</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>    

<!-- LIVING SHADOWS  -->
	<element name="Living Shadows" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LIVING_SHADOWS">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You whisper sibilant words of Void Speech that cause shadows to writhe with unholy life. Choose a point you can see within range. Writhing shadows spread out in a 15-foot-radius sphere centered on that point, grasping at creatures in the area. A creature that starts its turn in the area or that enters the area for the first time on its turn must make a successful Strength saving throw or be restrained by the shadows. A creature that starts its turn restrained by the shadows must make a successful Constitution saving throw or gain one level of exhaustion.</p>
			<p class="indent">A restrained creature can use its action to make a Strength or Dexterity check (its choice) against your spell save DC. On a success, it frees itself.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">void</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="void">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>    

 <!-- LOCK ARMOR  -->
	<element name="Lock Armor" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_LOCK_ARMOR">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You target a piece of metal equipment or a metal construct. If the target is a creature wearing metal armor or is a construct, it makes a Wisdom saving throw to negate the effect. On a failed save, the spell causes metal to cling to metal, making it impossible to move pieces against each other. This effectively paralyzes a creature that is made of metal or that is wearing metal armor with moving pieces; for example, scale mail would lock up because the scales must slide across each other, but a breastplate would be unaffected. Limited movement might still be possible, depending on how extensive the armor is, and speech is usually not affected. Metal constructs are paralyzed. An affected creature or construct can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. A grease spell dispels lock armor on everything in its area.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b>  When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="clockwork">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pinch of rust and metal shavings</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>