<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Deep Magic Spells - M</name>
        <update version="0.0.5">
            <file name="m-spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Kobold%20Press/Deep%20Magic/spells/m-spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

<!-- MADDENING WHISPERS --> 
	<element name="Maddening Whispers" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MADDENING_WHISPERS">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You whisper a string of Void Speech toward a target within range that can hear you. The target must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be incapacitated. While incapacitated by this spell, the target’s speed is 0, and it can’t benefit from increases to its speed. To maintain the effect for the duration, you must use your action on subsequent turns to continue whispering; otherwise, the spell ends. The spell also ends if the target takes damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">void</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="void">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MAGMA SPRAY --> 
	<element name="Magma Spray" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MAGMA_SPRAY">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A 5-foot-diameter, 5-foot-tall cylindrical fountain of magma erupts from the ground in a space of your choice within range. A creature in that space takes 3d8 fire damage, or half as much damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature that enters the area on its turn or ends its turn there also takes 3d8 fire damage, or half as much damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature can take this damage only once per turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature whose hit points are reduced to 0 by this damage is killed immediately, and its body burns to ash.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">apocalypse</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="apocalypse">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">40 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pinch of sulfur or a piece of brimstone</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MAMMON’S AVARICE -->
	<element name="Mammon's Avarice" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MAMMONS_AVARICE">
		<supports>Cleric,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By casting this spell, you tap into the power of greed that is Mammon’s sphere of influence, which manifests as a heightened olfactory sense. You can pinpoint, by smell, the location of any precious metals or gemstones within 30 feet of you. If you find anything, you can use an action to determine the exact types and amounts of any such materials. If materials of this sort are completely enclosed by, or separated from you by, more than 6 feet of earth or wood, 2 feet of stone, or 2 inches of common metal, you cannot detect them even if they are in range.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fiendish</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="fiendish">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30 ft. radius)</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
<!-- MASS SURGE DAMPENER  -->
	<element name="Mass Surge Dampener" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MASS_SURGE_DAMPENER">
		<supports>Bard,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Using your strength of will, you protect up to three creatures other than yourself from the effect of a chaos magic surge. A protected creature can make a DC 13 Charisma saving throw to negate the effect of a chaos magic surge that does not normally allow a saving throw, or it gains advantage on a saving throw that is normally allowed. Once a protected creature makes a successful saving throw allowed by mass surge dampener, the spell’s effect ends for that creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">Using your strength of will, you protect up to three creatures other than yourself from the effect of a chaos magic surge. A protected creature can make a DC 13 Charisma saving throw to negate the effect of a chaos magic surge that does not normally allow a saving throw, or it gains advantage on a saving throw that is normally allowed. Once a protected creature makes a successful saving throw allowed by mass surge dampener, the spell’s effect ends for that creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute, or until expended</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MEPHITIC CROAK --> 	
	<element name="Mephitic Croak" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MEPHITIC_CROAK">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You release an intensely loud burp of acidic gas in a 15-foot cone. Creatures in the area take 2d6 acid damage plus 2d6 thunder damage, or half as much damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. A creature whose Dexterity saving throw fails must also make a successful Constitution saving throw or be stunned and poisoned until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, both acid and thunder damage increase by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">alkemancy</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="alkemancy">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (15-ft cone)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dead toad and a dram of arsenic worth 10 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MIND EXCHANGE  -->
	<element name="Mind Exchange" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MIND_EXCHANGE">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>One humanoid of your choice that you can see within range must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, you project your mind into the body of the target. You use the target’s statistics but don’t gain access to its knowledge, class features, or proficiencies, retaining your own instead. Meanwhile, the target’s mind is shunted into your body, where it uses your statistics but likewise retains its own knowledge, class features, and proficiencies.</p>
			<p class="indent">The exchange lasts until either of the the two bodies drops to 0 hit points, until you end it as a bonus action, or until you are forced out of the target body by an effect such as a dispel magic or dispel evil and good spell (the latter spell defeats mind exchange even though possession by a humanoid isn’t usually affected by that spell). When the effect of this spell ends, both switched minds return to their original bodies. The target of the spell is immune to mind exchange for 24 hours after succeeding on the saving throw or after the exchange ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">The effects of the exchange can be made permanent with a wish spell or comparable magic.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mythos</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="mythos">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a prism and silver coin</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MISFORTUNE --> 
	<element name="Misfortune" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MISFORTUNE">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cast a pall of bad luck over all creatures in a 15-foot radius centered on a point within range. Each creature in that area must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be cursed with bad luck for the duration of the spell. A creature under the effect of this spell has disadvantage on all ability checks, saving throws, and attack rolls. A remove curse spell ends this effect.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Special.</i></b> If a targeted creature is carrying a stone of good luck, the creature is unaffected by the spell, but the item ceases to function for 24 hours. Likewise, if a targeted creature is carrying a luck blade, the creature is unaffected by the spell, but the sword’s Luck ability and saving throw bonuses cease to function for 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a broken mirror</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- MISSTEP  -->
	<element name="Misstep" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MISSTEP">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gesture to a creature within range that you can see. If the target fails a Wisdom saving throw, it uses its reaction to move 5 feet in a direction you dictate. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks. The spell automatically fails if you direct the target into a dangerous area such as a pit trap, a bonfire, or off the edge of a cliff, or if the target has already used its reaction.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">labyrinth</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="labyrinth">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MIST OF WONDERS  -->
	<element name="Mist of Wonders" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MIST_OF_WONDERS">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A colorful mist surrounds you out to a radius of 30 feet. Creatures inside the mist see odd shapes in it and hear random sounds that don’t make sense. The very concepts of order and logic don’t seem to exist inside the mist.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any 1st-level spell that’s cast in the mist by another caster or that travels through the mist is affected by its strange nature. The caster must make a Constitution saving throw when casting the spell. On a failed save, the spell transforms into another 1st-level spell the caster knows (chosen by the GM from those available), even if that spell is not currently prepared. The altered spell’s slot level or its original target or targeted area can’t be changed. Cantrips are unaffected. If (in the GM’s judgment) none of the caster’s spells known of that level can be transformed, the spell being cast simply fails.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, it affects any spell cast using a spell slot of any lower level. For instance, using a 6th-level slot enables you to transform a spell of 5th level or lower into another spell of the same level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30 ft. radius)</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MITHRAL DRAGON’S MIGHT  --> 
	<element name="Mithral Dragon's Might" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MITHRAL_DRAGONS_MIGHT">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You take on some of the physical characteristics and abilities of the mithral dragon, growing protective scales, wings, and claws. Until the spell ends, your AC can’t be lower than 16, regardless of what armor you are wearing. You can take two actions on your turn to attack with your claws, dealing 1d6 slashing damage on a hit. You have resistance to to acid and thunder damage. Up to three times while the spell is active, as an action, you can breathe a 20-foot cone of metal shards, dealing 6d8 slashing damage to all creatures in the cone. A creature that succeeds on a Dexterity saving throw takes half as much damage from your breath weapon. Finally, the wings grant you a flying speed of 40 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- MOON TRAP -->
	<element name="Moon Trap" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_MOON_TRAP">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>While casting this spell under the light of the moon, you inscribe a glyph that covers a 10-foot-square area on a flat, stationary surface such as a floor or a wall. Once the spell is complete, the glyph is invisible in moonlight but glows with a faint white light in darkness.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any creature that touches the glyph, except those you designate during the casting of the spell, must make a successful Wisdom saving throw or be drawn into an inescapable maze until the sun rises.</p>
			<p class="indent">The glyph lasts until the next sunrise, at which time it flares with bright light, and any creature trapped inside returns to the space it last occupied, unharmed. If that space has become occupied or dangerous, the creature appears in the nearest safe unoccupied space.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">labyrinth</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="labyrinth">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">up to 8 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">powdered silver worth 250 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>