<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Deep Magic Spells - T</name>
        <update version="0.0.6">
            <file name="t-spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/main/Kobold%20Press/Deep%20Magic/spells/t-spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
 
<!-- THOUSAND DARTS  -->
	<element name="Thousand Darts" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_THOUSAND_DARTS">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You launch thousands of needlelike darts in a 5-foot wide line that is 120 feet long. Each creature in the line takes 6d6 piercing damage, or half as much damage if it makes a successful Dexterity saving throw. The first creature struck by the darts makes the saving throw with disadvantage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b>  When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="clockwork">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (120-foot line)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a set of mithral darts worth 25 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
<!-- THUNDER BOLT  -->
	<element name="Thunder Bolt" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_THUNDER_BOLT">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cast a knot of thunder at one enemy. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. If it hits, the target takes 1d8 thunder damage and can’t use reactions until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- THUNDEROUS CHARGE  -->
	<element name="Thunderous Charge" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_THUNDEROUS_CHARGE">
		<supports>Ranger,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>With a thunderous battle cry, you move up to 10 feet in a straight line and make a melee weapon attack. If it hits, you can choose to either gain a +5 bonus on the attack’s damage or shove the target 10 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the distance you can move increases by 10 feet, and the attack deals an additional 1d6 thunder damage, for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">labyrinth</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="labyrinth">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 
	
<!-- THUNDEROUS STAMPEDE  -->
	<element name="Thunderous Stampede" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_THUNDEROUS_STAMPEDE">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell acts as thunderous charge, but affecting up to three targets within range, including yourself. A target other than you must use its reaction to move and attack under the effect of thunderous stampede.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the distance your targets can move increases by 10 feet, and the attack deals an additional 1d6 thunder damage, for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">labyrinth</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="labyrinth">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (30 ft. radius)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- THUNDERSTORM -->
	<element name="Thunderstorm" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_THUNDERSTORM">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch a willing creature, and it becomes surrounded by a roiling storm cloud 30 feet in diameter, erupting with (harmless) thunder and lightning. The creature gains a flying speed of 60 feet. The cloud heavily obscures the creature inside it from view, though it is transparent to the creature itself.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of lightning-fused glass</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TIME IN A BOTTLE  -->
	<element name="Time in a Bottle" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_IN_A_BOTTLE">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You designate a spot within your sight. Time comes under your control in a 20-foot radius centered on that spot. You can freeze it, reverse it, or move it forward by as much as 1 minute as long as you maintain concentration. Nothing and no one, yourself included, can enter the field or affect what happens inside it. You can choose to end the effect at any moment as an action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal, clockwork">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Sight</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME JAUNT  -->		
	<element name="Time Jaunt" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_JAUNT">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell, you step outside the normal time stream, seeming to vanish as 1 round of time passes. You can make minor alterations to the scene being played out, becoming visible for an instant each time you make an adjustment that aids an ally or hinders foes. To everyone else, you disappear when the spell is cast, then flicker into and out of view during the next round, before reappearing for good in the space you vanished from 1 round later, whereupon the spell ends. You cannot be attacked by any means while under the effect of this spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">As the round progresses, you can choose to bestow a single effect on each creature involved in the combat, choosing from the list below. You cannot take any other actions during the round.</p>
			<p class="indent">-Give a creature advantage or disadvantage on a saving throw it is about to make.</p>
			<p class="indent">-Give a creature advantage or disadvantage on an attack roll it is about to make.</p>
			<p class="indent">-Alter the location of a mobile object to provide or remove cover for a creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">-Shift objects into the path of a creature; the first 10 feet of terrain it must travel becomes difficult terrain.</p>
			<p class="indent">-After an attack roll is determined to be successful, adjust the angle of the strike or the positioning of the target, either causing the strike to deal half as much damage or providing a bonus to damage equal to half your level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Special</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME JUMP  -->
	<element name="Time Jump" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_JUMP">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch a construct and throw it forward in time if it fails a Constitution saving throw. The construct disappears for 1d4 + 1 rounds, during which time it cannot act or be acted upon in any way. When the construct returns, it is unaware that any time has passed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal, clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal, clockwork">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME LOOP  -->
	<element name="Time Loop" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_LOOP">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You capture a creature within range in a loop of time. The target is teleported to the space where it began its most recent turn. The target then makes a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the spell ends. On a failed save, the creature must repeat the activities it undertook on its previous turn, following the sequence of moves and actions to the best of its ability. It doesn’t need to move along the same path or attack the same target, but if it moved and then attacked on its previous turn, its only option is to move and then attack on this turn. If the space where the target began its previous turn is occupied or if it’s impossible for the target to take the same action (if it cast a spell but is now unable to do so, for example), the target becomes incapacitated.</p>
			<p class="indent">An affected target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. For as long as the spell lasts, the target teleports back to its starting point at the start of each of its turns, and it must repeat the same sequence of moves and actions.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">30 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a metal loop</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TIME SLIPPAGE --> 
	<element name="Time Slippage" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_SLIPPAGE">
		<supports>Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You ensnare a creature within range in an insidious trap, causing different parts of its body to function at different speeds. The creature must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, it is stunned until the end of its next turn. On a success, the creature’s speed is halved and it has disadvantage on attack rolls and saving throws until the end of its next turn. The creature repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, with the same effects for success and failure. In addition, the creature has disadvantage on Strength or Dexterity saving throws but advantage on Constitution or Charisma saving throws for the spell’s duration (a side effect of the chronal anomaly suffusing its body). The spell ends if the creature makes three successful saves in a row.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal,clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">8</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal, clockwork">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">60 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">the heart of a chaotic creature CR5 or higher, worth 500 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME STEP  -->
	<element name="Time Step" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_STEP">
		<supports>Bard,Cleric,Ranger,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You briefly step forward in time. You disappear from your location and reappear at the start of your next turn in a location of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of the space you disappeared from. You can’t be affected by anything that happens during the time you’re missing, and you aren’t aware of anything that happens during that time.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TIME VORTEX  -->
	<element name="Time Vortex" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIME_VORTEX">
		<supports>Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell destabilizes the flow of time, enabling you to create a vortex of temporal fluctuations that are visible as a spherical distortion with a 10-foot radius, centered on a point within range. Each creature in the area when you cast the spell must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be affected by the time vortex. While the spell lasts, a creature that enters the sphere or starts its turn inside the sphere must also succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be affected. On a succesful save, it becomes immune to this casting of the spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">An affected creature can’t take reactions and rolls a d10 at the start of its turn to determine its behavior for that turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can move the temporal vortex 10 feet each round as a bonus action. An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the radius of the sphere increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 4th.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1-2</td><td>The creature is affected as if by a slow spell until the start of its next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3-5</td><td>The creature is stunned until the start of its next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6-8</td><td>The creature’s current initiative result is reduced by 5. The creature begins using this new initiative result in the next round. Multiple occurrences of this effect for the same creature are cumulative.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9-10</td><td>The creature’s speed is halved (round up to the nearest 5-foot increment) until the start of its next turn.</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">temporal</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="temporal">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">90 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TIMELY DISTRACTION  -->
	<element name="Timely Distraction" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIMELY_DISTRACTION">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You call forth a swirling, crackling wave of constantly shifting pops, flashes, and swept-up debris. This chaos can confound one creature. If the target gets a failure on a Wisdom saving throw, roll a d4 and consult the following table to determine the result. An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Otherwise, the spell ends when its duration expires.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d4</td><td>Mutation</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Blinded</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Stunned</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Deafened</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Prone</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chaos</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="chaos">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">25 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">3 rounds</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a handful of sand or dirt thrown in the air</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 	

<!-- TIRELESS  -->
	<element name="Tireless" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TIRELESS">
		<supports>Bard,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You grant machinelike stamina to a creature you touch for the duration of the spell. The target requires no food or drink or rest. It can move at three times its normal speed overland and perform three times the usual amount of labor. The target is not protected from fatigue or exhaustion caused by a magical effect.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">clockwork</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school" addition="clockwork">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an ever-wound spring worth 50 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TOME CURSE  -->=
	<element name="Tome Curse" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TOME_CURSE">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You protect a book by writing a curse in it with ink made from the material components of this spell. The writing is typically a couplet or a quatrain that warns of the consequences of disturbing your property. The curse is triggered by an action or actions that you specify (which typically involves someone reading the book without permission, trying to damage the book, or trying to steal it). When the curse is triggered, the creature that did so must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or suffer its effect. You can choose one of the effects described in the bestow curse spell, or you can affect the target in one of the following ways:</p>
			<p class="indent"> •While the target is cursed, it is blinded.</p>
			<p class="indent"> •Beasts are unusually hostile to the target while it is cursed; they gain advantage on attack rolls against the target.</p>
			<p class="indent"> •While cursed, the target is an attractive mark to pickpockets and other thieves, and such individuals will try to steal the target’s valuables when the opportunity presents itself. (Even if in the target’s possession, the cursed book does not count as one of the target’s valuables.)</p>
			<p class="indent"> •A cursed target that either receives magical healing or rolls Hit Dice to recover hit points after a long rest must roll twice and use the lower result.</p>
			<p class="indent">A remove curse spell ends this effect. You can also stipulate other actions taken by the target that would nullify the curse (returning the book after it is stolen, for example).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fiendish</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="fiendish">Necromancy</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Until dispelled or triggered</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an ounce of blood, and powdered onyx worth at least 50 gp, both of which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>


<!-- TORRENT OF FIRE -->
	<element name="Torrent of Fire" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TORRENT_OF_FIRE">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You harness the power of fire contained in ley lines with this spell. You create a 60-foot cone of flame. Creatures in the cone take 6d6 fire damage, or half as much damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. You can then flow along the flames, reappearing anywhere inside the cone’s area. This repositioning doesn’t count as movement and doesn’t trigger opportunity attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 round</set>
			<set name="range">Self (60 ft. cone)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of obsidian</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TRACER  -->
	<element name="Tracer" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TRACER">
		<supports>Druid,Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you cast this spell and as a bonus action on each of your turns until the spell ends, you can imbue a piece of ammunition you fire from a ranged weapon with a tiny, invisible beacon. If a ranged attack roll with an imbued piece of ammunition hits a target, the beacon is transferred to the target. The weapon that fired the ammunition is attuned to the beacon and becomes warm to the touch when it points in the direction of the target as long as the target is on the same plane of existence as you. You can have only one tracer target at a time. If you put a tracer on a different target, the effect on the previous target ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature must succeed on an Intelligence (Arcana) check against your spell save DC to notice the magical beacon.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a drop of brigh paint</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TRACKING BEACON -->
	<element name="Tracking Beacon" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TRACKING_BEACON">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You choose a creature within range to mark with a glowing orb of light, which floats 120 feet above the creature’s head. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the spell ends. On a failed save, the light hovers above the target’s location, moving as the target moves, which enables you to track the creature’s direction and distance by staying within sight of the beacon. The beacon continues to function even when you cannot see it, as long as the target remains on the same plane as you. If either you or the target travels to another plane, the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use a bonus action on your turn to adjust the height of the beacon, ranging from its starting point of 120 feet to as low as 5 feet above the head of the target.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">illumination</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school" addition="illumination">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">120 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 8 hours</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">component</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 

<!-- TRANSMOGRIFICATION  -->
	<element name="Trangsmogrification" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TRANSMOGRIFICATION">
		<supports>Cleric,Druid,Sorcerer,Warlock,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>	You elevate your body to a higher form. When you cast the spell, choose three of the forms described below and indicate which one’s effects will occur first. While the spell lasts, you can use a bonus action to exchange one of your choices for an unused one, or to make a new choice when the current one ends. The spell ends when its duration expires or when you expend all the available uses of the third form you adopt.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Wings.</i></b> You sprout wings from your shoulders and gain a flying speed of 60 feet. The wings can be batlike or feathered.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Breath Weapon.</i></b> You gain a breath weapon of one of these types of your choice: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison. You can use an action to unleash your breath weapon in a 15-foot line that is 5 feet wide. Each creature in the line takes 8d6 damage of the chosen type, or half as much damage with a successful Dexterity saving throw. The breath weapon is considered a magical attack. You can use this ability up to three times, and it expires after the third use.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Limbs.</i></b> Appendages resembling tentacles, spider legs, pincers, or something else of your choosing sprout from your body. Choose slashing, bludgeoning, or piercing damage; you can use an action to make two melee weapon attacks with your new limbs, and each attack deals 2d12 damage of the chosen type. You are proficient with these weapons, and they have the reach and finesse properties.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Radiating Light.</i></b> You emit light in a 10-foot radius. The light can come from a halo, from ghostly flames, from your eyes, or any other source you choose. The light deals your choice of necrotic, fire, or radiant damage. A creature that passes through the light on its turn or that ends its turn in the light takes 2d10 damage of the chosen type, or half as much damage with a successful Constitution saving throw. A creature takes this damage only once per turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Regeneration.</i></b> You regain 10 hit points at the start of your turn. You can use this ability up to three times, and it expires after the third use.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Overwhelming Might.</i></b> When you hit a target with a weapon attack, the target takes an extra 2d8 force damage and must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Frightening Presence.</i></b> As an action, choose any number of creatures within 30 feet of you that can see you. Each of them must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for 1 minute. A creature frightened in this way can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature’s saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to your frightening presence for the next 24 hours. You can use this ability up to three times, and it expires after the third use.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">apocalypse</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="apocalypse">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a bit of flesh from a fiend, or a feather from a celestial, each item worth at least 50 gp</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TREASURE CHASM -->
	<element name="Treasure Chasm" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TREASURE_CHASM">
		<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cause the glint of a golden coin to haze over the vision of one creature in range. The target creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, it sees a gorge, trench, or other hole in the ground, at a spot within range chosen by you, which is filled with gold and treasure. On its next turn, the creature must move toward that spot. When it reaches the spot, it becomes incapacitated, as it devotes all its attention to scooping imaginary treasure into its pockets or a pouch.</p>
			<p class="indent">An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. The effect also ends if the creature takes damage from you or one of your allies.</p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures with the dragon type have disadvantage on the initial saving throw but have advantage on saving throws against this spell made after reaching the designated spot.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dragon</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school" addition="dragon">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gold coin</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<!-- TRIUMPH OF ICE --> 
	<element name="Triumph of Ice" type="Spell" source="Deep Magic" id="ID_KBP_DM5E_SPELL_TRIUMP_OF_ICE">
		<supports>Druid,Sorcerer,Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You transform one of the four elements—air, earth, fire, or water—into ice or snow. The affected area is a sphere with a radius of 100 feet, centered on you. The specific effect depends on the element you choose.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Air.</i></b> Vapor condenses into snowfall. If the effect of a fog cloud spell, a stinking cloud, or similar magic is in the area, this spell negates it. A creature of elemental air within range takes 8d6 cold damage—and, if airborne, it must make a successful Constitution saving throw at the start of its turn to avoid being knocked prone (no falling damage).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Earth.</i></b> Soil freezes into permafrost to a depth of 10 feet. A creature burrowing through the area has its speed halved until the area thaws, unless it can burrow through solid rock. A creature of elemental earth within range must make a successful Constitution saving throw or take 8d6 cold damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fire.</i></b> Flames or other sources of extreme heat (such as molten lava) on the ground within range transform into shards of ice, and the area they occupy becomes difficult terrain. Each creature in the previously burning area takes 2d6 slashing damage when the spell is cast and 1d6 slashing damage for every 5 feet it moves in the area (unless it is not hindered by icy terrain) until the spell ends; a successful Dexterity saving throw reduces the slashing damage by half. A creature of elemental fire within range must make a successful Constitution saving throw or take 8d6 cold damage and be stunned for 1d6 rounds.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Water.</i></b> Open water (a pond, lake, or river) freezes to a depth of 4 feet. A creature on the surface of the water when it freezes must make a successful Dexterity saving throw to avoid being trapped in the ice. A trapped creature can free itself by using an action to make a successful Strength (Athletics) check. A creature of elemental water within range takes no damage from the spell but is paralyzed for 1d6 rounds unless it makes a successful Constitution saving throw, and it treats the affected area as difficult terrain.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">winter</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school" addition="winter">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">100 ft.</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a stone extracted from glacial ice</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>