<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Barbarian: Path of the Juggernaut</name>
        <author url="https://darringtonpress.com/taldorei-campaign-setting-reborn/">Darrington Press, Critical Role</author>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="barbarian-juggernaut.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mamawerecat/AuroraCustomContent/test/critcal-role-taldorei-campaign-setting-reborn/archetypes/barbarian-juggernaut.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Path of the Juggernaut" type="Archetype" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT">
            <supports>Primal Path</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Barbarians who follow the Path of the Juggernaut stand so resolutely that none can deter them, and they swing their weapons with such force that all who stand against them are flung aside. In might and in spirit, juggernauts are immovable object and unstoppable force all at once.</p>
                <p class="indent">Juggernaut barbarians can be found all over Tal'Dorei, and are common among the goliath warriors of the Rivermaw herd that wanders the Dividing Plains. Some dwarves and humanoid survivalists of the Cliffkeep Mountains adopt this fighting style as an extension of their rugged determinism. And a number of stalwart juggernauts hail from the jungles of the Rifenmist Peninsula, having cast off the oppressive yoke of the Iron Authority.</p>
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_THUNDEROUS_BLOWS" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_SPIRIT_OF_THE_MOUNTAIN" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_DEMOLISHING_MIGHT" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_RESOLUTE_STANCE" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_HURRICANE_STRIKE" />
                <div element="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_UNSTOPPABLE" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_THUNDEROUS_BLOWS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_SPIRIT_OF_THE_MOUNTAIN" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_DEMOLISHING_MIGHT" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_RESOLUTE_STANCE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_HURRICANE_STRIKE" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_UNSTOPPABLE" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>

        <!-- PATH OF THE JUGGERNAUT ARCHETYPE FEATURE THUNDEROUS BLOWS -->
        
            <element name="Thunderous Blows" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_THUNDEROUS_BLOWS">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, your rage instills you with the strength to shove and smash your way through your foes, making any battlefield your domain. When you hit a creature with a melee attack while you’re raging, you can push that creature up to 5 feet away from you in a direction of your choice. A creature that is Huge or larger makes a Strength saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier. On a success, the creature is not pushed.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Starting at 10th level, you can push a creature up to 10 feet when you hit it with a melee attack while you’re raging.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description level="3">When you hit a creature with a melee attack while you’re raging, you can push that creature up to 5 feet away from you in a direction of your choice. A creature that is Huge or larger makes a Strength saving throw with a DC equal to {{barbarian thunderous blows:dc}}. On a success, the creature is not pushed.</description>
                    <description level="10">When you hit a creature with a melee attack while you’re raging, you can push that creature up to 10 feet away from you in a direction of your choice. A creature that is Huge or larger makes a Strength saving throw with a DC equal to {{barbarian thunderous blows:dc}}. On a success, the creature is not pushed.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
			        <stat name="barbarian thunderous blows:dc" value="8" />
			        <stat name="barbarian thunderous blows:dc" value="proficiency" />
			        <stat name="barbarian thunderous blows:dc" value="strength:modifier" />
		        </rules>
            </element>
        
        <!-- PATH OF THE JUGGERNAUT ARCHETYPE FEATURE SPIRIT OF THE MOUNTAIN -->
        
            <element name="Spirit of the Mountain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_SPIRIT_OF_THE_MOUNTAIN">
                <description>
                    <p>At 3rd level, you harness your fury to anchor your feet to the ground, becoming a bulwark of strength. While you are raging, you can’t be knocked prone or moved along the ground against your will.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>While you are raging, you can’t be knocked prone or moved along the ground against your will.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        
        <!-- PATH OF THE JUGGERNAUT ARCHETYPE FEATURE DEMOLISHING MIGHT -->
        
            <element name="Demolishing Might" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_DEMOLISHING_MIGHT">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 6th level, your melee weapon attacks deal an extra 1d8 damage to constructs, and deal double damage to objects and structures.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your melee weapon attacks deal an extra 1d8 damage to constructs, and deal double damage to objects and structures.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        
        <!-- PATH OF THE JUGGERNAUT ARCHETYPE FEATURE RESOLUTE STANCE -->
        
            <element name="Resolute Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_RESOLUTE_STANCE">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 6th level, you can temporarily refocus your combat ability to make yourself a bulwark of defense. At the start of your turn (no action required), you can assume a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in this stance, you can’t be grappled, attack rolls against you have disadvantage, and your weapon attacks are made with disadvantage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>At the start of your turn (no action required), you can assume a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in this stance, you can’t be grappled, attack rolls against you have disadvantage, and your weapon attacks are made with disadvantage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        
        <!-- PATH OF THE JUGGERNAUT ARCHETYPE FEATURE HURRICANE STRIKE -->
        
            <element name="Hurricane Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_HURRICANE_STRIKE">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 10th level, your blows can hurl foes through the air and into the attacks of your allies. As a reaction when you push a creature at least 5 feet, you can then leap into an unoccupied space next to the creature. If you do so, the creature must succeed on a Strength saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier or be knocked prone. This leap costs no movement and does not provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you push a creature into a space within 5 feet of one of your allies, the ally can use its reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Hurricane Strike" action="Reaction">
                    <description>As a reaction when you push a creature at least 5 feet, you can then leap into an unoccupied space next to the creature. If you do so, the creature must succeed on a Strength saving throw with a DC equal to {{barbarian hurricane strike:dc}} or be knocked prone. This leap costs no movement and does not provoke opportunity attacks. Additionally, whenever you push a creature into a space within 5 feet of one of your allies, the ally can use its reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
			        <stat name="barbarian hurricane strike:dc" value="8" />
			        <stat name="barbarian hurricane strike:dc" value="proficiency" />
			        <stat name="barbarian hurricane strike:dc" value="strength:modifier" />
		        </rules>
            </element>
        
        <!-- PATH OF THE JUGGERNAUT ARCHETYPE FEATURE UNSTOPPABLE -->

            <element name="Unstoppable" type="Archetype Feature" source="Tal'Dorei Campaign Setting Reborn" id="ID_TALDOREI_CR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_JUGGERNAUT_UNSTOPPABLE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, your fury in battle makes you unstoppable. While you’re raging, your speed cannot be reduced, and you are immune to the frightened, paralyzed, prone, and stunned conditions. If you are frightened, paralyzed, or stunned, you can still use a bonus action to enter a rage (even if you can’t otherwise take actions). You aren’t affected by any of these conditions while you’re raging.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>While you’re raging, your speed cannot be reduced, and you are immune to the frightened, paralyzed, prone, and stunned conditions. If you are frightened, paralyzed, or stunned, you can still use a bonus action to enter a rage (even if you can’t otherwise take actions). You aren’t affected by any of these conditions while you’re raging.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
       
</elements>
